This dam project will create many new jobs!
The Party will assist in your relocation!
Grandma, give me your hand.
- But where are they taking us?
- It'll be all right.
Brother!
Grandma! I will send you money!
Who can write?!
Who can read?!
Who can weld?!
I put a lot of faith into your organization.
It's a perfect replica, Roland.
There are too many fanatics out there
who could damage her.
Just think about the
beautiful Buddha statues
they blew up in Afghanistan.
Our Heritage Organization
has already made selections,
from the British Museum and L'hermitage.
I guess she'll be safe now tucked away,
hidden... in some bunker in Switzerland.
Perfectly safe, Roland.
Only infrared analysis would reveal the difference.
But it's still a fake.
Hello?
Laura!
Laura, can you hear me?!
Roland, is that you?
Laura, they lied to us.
I've arranged a press conference for tomorrow.
I will tell everyone the truth
about what's going on.
What are you talking about?
The art you collected?
It's not in the Alps.
Those tunnels are empty.
I have proof.
Laura!
Laura, can you hear me?!
I'm losing you.
Roland?!
Can you hear me?!
Laura!
I feared you would not come!
Zultan, listen to me.
We are fighters, we never go down,
no matter how hard they hit us!
Kill the bastard!
Yuri! Where are you going?!
Do not believe in something simply
because you have heard it, Nima.
But, Great Lama, Tenzin is my brother.
He works inside the big tunnel,
where the ships are built.
But what is there in your wisdom,
great Lama, if Tenzin is right?
What if our world is indeed coming to an end?
Great Rinpoche...
It is full.
It's full!
Like this cup,
you are full of opinions and speculations.
To see the light of wisdom,
you first must empty your cup.
Be careful with the clutch.
It tends to slip.
Grandma!
Grandpa! Nima is here!
Grandma, I got a message from Tenzin.
He wants us to meet him
in Cho Ming at the west gate.
He says he can get us
on the ships he's working on.
What are you talking about?
Tenzin works on the dam.
Grandma...
The dam is a ship!
The government lied to us!
There will be a big flood!
We must pack up right away!
Nima!
He gave you the truck?
We took a trip on the Laem Song ferry once.
Grandpa threw up...
the whole way.
Let's eat first.
Who are they?!
We found them along side of the road.
Send them back!
I am a follower,
of our great Lama Rinpoche.
You know I cannot do that!
We are all children of the earth.
Grandma, my plan will not work for so many!
We will take them all.
Tenzin wait!
Grandma! we're almost there!
Daddy look!
Tenzin, almost there!
Nima, what happened?
Grandma, Grandpa.
I'm sorry.
I could not save us.
He has gone back in. He will fix it.
There's no way.
Don't lose your faith, brother.