Translated By:
|| killer_sub ||
Imagine...
a soldier...
the size of an insect.
The ultimate secret weapon.
If you give God-like powers to everyone?
It's gonna be chaos.
So how do we stop him?
I know a guy...
Scott...
I've been watching you for awhile now.
You're different.
And I believe everyone deserves a shot at redemption.
Do you?
Absolutely. My days of breaking into places and stealing stuff...
are OVER.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to break into a place and steal some stuff.
Makes sense.
Are you ready...
to become the hero?
Now, this suit has power.
You have to learn how to control it.
And these are your greatest allies.
You're kinda cute...
Whoa...
When you're small, you have super-human strength.
You're like a bullet.
So you need to know how to punch.
You're gonna show me how to punch?
Show me how to pun -
That's how you punch.
You tried to hide your suit from me.
Now, it's gonna blow up in your face.
And destroy everyone you care about.
Scott get out of there!
Did you think you could stop the future?!
You're just a thief!
No...
I'm Ant-Man.
I know...
Wasn't my idea.