Once upon a time in the hidden heart
of France.
A handsome young prince
lived in a beautiful castle.
Puff! Puff!
Although he had everything
his heart desired,
the Prince was selfish and unkind.
Master, it's time.
He taxed the village
to fill his castle with the most
beautiful objects.
And his parties with the most
beautiful people.
Oh, how defined
Glamour music and magic combined
See the maidens for anxious to shine
Look for a sign that in the hands,
chances,
She'll be his special one
What a play
What a breathtaking, thrilling array
Every prince, every has a day
As I sing with passion, gusto...
***
Then one night,
an unexpected intruder arrived
at the castle,
seeking shelter from the
bestest storm.
As a gift, she offered
the Prince a single rose.
Repulsed by her haggard
appearance,
the Prince turned the woman away.
But she warned him not to be deceived
by appearances.
For beauty is found within.
When he dismissed her again,
the old woman's out with her appearance
melted away.
To reveal...
a beautiful enchantress.
The Prince begged for forgiveness,
but he was too late.
Cause she had seen that there was no love
in his heart.
Chip! Chip! Oh, Lord!
As punishment...
she transformed him into
a hideous beast.
And placed a powerfull spell
on the castle...
and all who lived there.
As days bleed into years...
The Prince and his servants
were forgotten by the world.
For the enchantress had erased
all memory of them,
from the minds of the people
they loved.
But the rose she had offered was truly
an enchanted rose.
If he could learn to love another...
and earned their love in return
by the time the last petal fell,
the spell would be broken.
If not, he would be doomed to remain
a beast for all time.
As the years passed,
he fell into despair and lost
all hope.
For who could ever learn to love
a beast?
BEAUTY AND THE BEAST
Transcripted by umbulbil
https://subscene.com/u/1030447
Little town, it's a quite
village
Everyday, like the one before
Little town, full of little people
Waking up to say..­
Bonjour.
- Bonjour.
Morning.
There goes the baker
with his tray, like always
The same all bread and rolls
to sell
Every morning just the same
Since the morning that we came
to this poor provincial town.
Good morning, Belle!
Good morning Monsieur Jean!
Have you lost something again?
Well, I believe I have.
The problem is, I can't remember what!
I'm sure it'll come through me.
Where are you off to?
To return this book to
Père Robert.
It's about two lovers in fair Verona.
Sounds boring.
Look there she goes that girl is strange,
no question
Dazed and distracted, can't you tell?
Never part of any crowd
'Cause her head's up on some cloud
No denying she's a funny girl that Belle
Bonjour, good day!
How is your family?
How is your wife?
I need six eggs,
that's too expensive.
There must be more than
this provincial life.
Ah! If it isn't the only bookworm
in town!
So, where did you run off to
this week?
Two cities in northern Italy.
I didn't want to come back.
Have you got any new places to go?
I'm afraid not.
But you may re-read any
of the old ones that you'd like.
Thank you.
Your library makes a small corner of the wall
seems big.
- Bon voyage.
- Bye.
Look there she goes that girl is so peculiar
I wonder if she's feeling well?
With a dreamy far-off look
and her nose stuck in a book.
What a puzzle to the rest of us
is Belle.
Ah~ isn't this amazing?
it's my favorite parts, because
you'll see..
Here's where she meets Prince Charming
But she won't discover that it's him,
'til chapter three
Now it's no wonder that her name
means "beauty"
Her looks have got no parallel
But behind that fair facade
I'm afraid she's rather odd
Very different from the rest of us
She's nothing like the rest of us
She's different from the rest of us
is Belle
Look at her, LeFou.
My future wife.
Belle is the most beautiful girl
in the village.
That makes her the best.
But she's so well-read.
And you so..
athletically inclined.
I know.
Belle can be as argumentative
as she's beautiful.
Exactly! Who needs her, when you've
got us?
Yes..
Ever since the war, I felt like,
I've been missing someting.
And she is the only girl
who gives me that sense of...
I don't know what that means.
Right from the moment when
I met her, saw her.
I said, "she's gorgeous"
and I fell
Here in town there's only she,
who is beautiful as me.
So I making plan to woo
and marry Belle.
Look there he goes.
Isn't he dreamy?
Monsieur Gaston, oh!
He's so cute!
Be still my heart
I'm hardly breathing
He's such a tall, dark, strong and
handsome brute
That's never gonna happen, ladies.
- Bonjour!
- Pardon!
- Good day!
- Mais oui!
- You call this bacon?
- What lovely grapes!
- Some cheese­
- Ten yards
- One pound
- Excuse me
- I'll get the knife
- Please, let me through!
- This bread
- Those fish
- It's stale!
- They smell
Madame's mistaken
There must be more than this provincial life!
Just watch, I'm going to make Belle my wife!
Look there she goes a girl who's strange
but special
A most peculiar mad'moiselle
It's a pity and a sin
She doesn't quite fit in
'Cause she really is a funny girl
A beauty but a funny girl
She really is a funny girl!
That Belle~
Good morrning, Belle!
Wonderful book you have there!
Have you read it?
Well, not that one. But, you know, books...
For your dinner table.
Shall I join you this evening?
Sorry, not this evening.
Busy?
No...
So, moving on?
No, LeFou.
It's the ones who play hard to get
that are always the sweetest prey.
That what makes Belle so appealing.
She hasn't made a fool of herself
just to gain my favour.
How would you call that?
Dignity?
It's outrageously attractive, isn't it?
Gaston!
How does a moment last forever?
How can a story never died?
It is love we must hold onto.
Never easy, but we try.
Sometimes our happiness is captured.
Somehow a time and place stand still.
Love leads on inside our hearts.
And always will.
Oh, Belle!
Could you..?
Hand me a...
Thank you.
And I also need..
No. No.
Actually...
Yes, that's exactly what I need.
Thank you.
Papa, do you think I'm odd?
Odd?
My daughter? Odd?
Where did you get an idea
like that?
I don't know. People talk.
This is a small village, you know.
Small minded, as well.
But, small also means safe.
Even back in Paris, I knew a girl like you,
who would be so...
ahead of a time.
Different.
People mocked her.
Until the day they all found themselves
imitating her.
Please, just tell me one more thing
about her.
Your mother was..
fearless.
Fearless.
So,
what can I bring you from the market?
A rose. Like the one
in the painting.
You ask of that every year!
And every year you bring it.
Then I should bring you another.
You have my word.
Bye, Papa.
Bye, Belle.
Come on, Philippe.
You know the way.
I'll see you tomorrow!
Right!
Tomorrow, with the rose!
Stay safe.
What are you doing?
The laundry.
Come! Come!
"The Blue Bird.."
The Blue Bird
"that flies over..."
"the dark..."
"wood".
That was amazing!
What on earth are you doing?
Teaching another girl to read?
Isn't one enough?
We have to do something.
You are the wildest,
most gorgeous thing
I've ever seen.
Nobody deserves you.
But at least I know our children
will be beautiful.
Am I catching you at a bad time?
- What is it, LeFou?
- A damsel is in distress.
It's hero time.
I'm not done with you, yet.
Me, neither.
Belle! I heard you had trouble
with the headmaster.
He never liked me either.
Can I give you a little advise
about the villagers, Belle?
They're never gonna trust the kind of change
you're trying to bring them.
All I wanted was to teach a child
to read.
The only children you should concern
yourself, will be..
your own.
I'm...
not ready to have children.
Maybe you haven't met the right man.
It's a small village, Gaston.
I've met them all.
Well, maybe you should take
another look.
Some of us have changed.
Gaston,
we could never make each other happy.
No one can changed that much.
Oh, Belle.
Do you know what happens to spinsters in this village
after their fathers died?
Coins? Could you spare me coins?
They beg for scraps,
like poor Agathe.
This is our world, Belle.
For simple folk like us,
it doesn't getting better.
I want to be a farm girl.
But I'm not simple.
And..
I'm never going to marry you, Gaston.
I'm sorry!
Can you imagine?
Me? The wife of that boorish,
brainless...
Madam Gaston, can't you just see it?
Madame Gaston, his little wife. Ugh!
No, Sir. Not me, I guarantee it
I want much more than this
provincial life
I want adventure in the great wide
somewhere
I want it more than I can tell
And for once it might be grand
To have someone understand
I want so much more than they've got planned
The woods are lovely.
I only wish I'd recognized them.
You know where we are, Philippe?
Cause I don't.
It's all right. It's all right. Philippe.
Yes, we can go this way.
Go on. To the right.
That's it!
Come on!
One door closes,
another one opens.
All right, boy.
Just a bit of snow.
In June.
Mind your step.
It's slippery.
Go, go Philippe! Come on!
Come on!
Go, Philippe! Go!
Philippe!
Good boy.
Go, boy! Go!
Philippe, you saved my life!
Well done. Ehh.
They'll have to get their dinner
somewhere else, won't they?
Look!
It's hay!
And water.
You are safe, my old friend.
I'll go pay my respects to our
unwitting host.
Whoever that may be.
Thank you.
Thank...
Hello?
Sorry to intrude.
I'm a.. just a traveler,
seeking shelter from the storm.
Sorry to disturb you.
Anyone home?
Anyone awake?
He must''ve lost his way
in the woods.
You have to keep quite!
Excuse me?
Beautiful.
Extraordinary.
A man of taste.
He was talking about me.
Well, wherever you are..
I'm just going to warm myself
by the fire.
That's better.
Oh, much better.
Thank you.
Mom said I wasn't supposed to move,
because it might be scary.
Sorry.
It's alright.
I cannot..
Thank you enough for your hospitality.
I'll..
leave you..
and good night.
Come on Philippe, go! Go!
No, wait, wait, wait!
Roses. I nearly forgot.
Stay here.
I promised Belle a rose.
There!
Philippe!
What happened?
Where is Papa?
Take me to him!
Look! Cogsworth!
A beautiful girl!
Yes! I can see it's a girl.
I lost my hands, but my eyes.
But, what if she's the one?
The one who'll break the spell?
Who said that?
Who's there?
Papa?
Papa, is that you?
Belle!
How did you find me?
Your hands are iced.
We need to get you home.
Belle, now you must leave!
This castle is alive!
Now, go before he finds you!
Who?
Who's there?
Who are you?
I've come to my father.
Your father is a thief!
Liar!
He stole a rose.
I asked the rose.
Punish me, not him!
No!
He means forever!
Apparently, that's what happens around here
when you pick a flower!
A life sentence for a rose?
I received eternal damnation for one.
I merely locking him away.
Do you choose to take you father's
place?
Come in to the light.
Choose.
Belle, I won't let you do this.
I lost your mother.
I won't lose you, too!
Now, go!
Go!
All right, Papa. I'll leave.
I need a minute alone with him.
You are so cruel,
did you won't allow a daughter
to say her father goodbye?
Forever can spare a minute.
When this door closes, it will
not open again.
I should've been with you.
No. Belle, listen to me.
It's all right.
Now, go.
Live your life.
And forget me.
Forget you?
Everything I aim is because of you.
I love you, Belle.
Don't be afraid.
I love you too, Papa.
I'm not afraid.
And I will escape, I promise.
Wh.. What?
You took his place.
He is my father.
He's a fool.
And so are you.
Belle..
Papa!
Don't hurt him!
- Papa!
- No!
I'll come back!
I promise!
Forgive my intrusion, mademoiselle.
But I have come to escort you
to your room.
My room?
- But I thought...
- Oh, what?
That "Once this door closes,
it will not open again"?
I know.
He gets all dramatic.
Hallo!
Oh, you are very strong.
This is a great quality.
What are you?
I am Lumière!
And.. You can talk?
Of course, he can talk.
It's all he ever does.
Now, Lumière, as the head of
the household,
I demand that you to put her
back in her cell at once.
What do you want to be
for the rest of your life, Cogsworth?
A man or a mental clock?
Ready, miss?
Trust me.
You must forgive first impressions.
I hope you are not too startled.
Why would I be startled?
I'm talking to a candle.
Candelabro, please.
You know there's a difference.
But consider me at your service.
The castle is your own now,
so feel free to go anywhere
you like.
Except the west wing.
Uh, which we do not have.
Why? What's in the west wing?
- Nothing.
- Storage space.
- That's it
- That's it.
Yes, that's it!
This way, please.
To the east wing.
As I like to call it,
it's the only wing.
Ha ha. Watch your step,
s'il vou plait!
Welcome to your new room!
It's modest, but comortable.
It's.. beautiful.
But of course,
The Master wanted you to have
the finest room in the castle.
Oh, dear. We were not expecting guest.
Enchanté, mademoiselle.
Don't worry.
I'll have this place spotless
in no time.
This plan of yours is
dangerous.
I would've risk anything to kiss you
again, Plumette.
No, my love. I've been burnt
by you before.
We must be strong.
How can I be strong when
you make me so..
Is everything here alive?
Hello. What's your name?
That is a hairbrush.
Do not be alarmed.
This is just your wardrobe.
Meet Madame De Garderobe.
A great singer.
Which you can stay awake.
Cogsworth! A diva needs
a beauty rest.
Stay with us, Madame.
We have someone for you
to dress!
Ah, finally!
A woman!
Pretty eyes.
Proud face.
A perfect canvas. Yes!
I will find you something worthy
of a princess.
I'm not a princess.
Non sense!
Let's see what I got
in my drawer.
Oh! How embarassing!
Froufrou, come and help mama.
Perfecto!
Subtle, understated. I love it!
Au revoir!
Froufrou, send my love to
the maestro.
Picture it, LeFou.
A rustic cabin,
My latest kill roasting on the fire.
Adorable children running around us,
while my love...
rubs my tired feet.
But what did Belle say?
"I will never marry you, Gaston!"
You know, there are other girls.
A great man doesn't waste
his time.
Gosh, it disturbs me to see you, Gaston
Looking so down in the dumps.
Every guy here'd love to be you, Gaston.
Even when taking your lumps.
There's no men in town as admired
as you.
You're everyone's favorite guy
Everyone's awed and inspired by you
And it's not very hard
to see why
No one's slick as Gaston
No one's quick as Gaston
No one's neck's as incredibly thick as Gaston's
For there's no man in town half as manly
Perfect, a pure paragon!
You can ask any Tom, Dick, or Stanley
And they'll tell you whose team they prefer to be on
Who plays...?
dart like Gaston!
- Who breaks hearts
- Like Gaston!
Who's much more than some of this...
like Gaston.
As a specimen, yes, I'm intimidating.
My, what a guy, that Gaston!
I needed encouragement.
Thank you, LeFou
Well, there's no one as easy to bolster
as you
Too much?
Yep.
No one fights like Gaston
Douses lights like Gaston
In a wrestling match nobody bites like Gaston
When I hunt, I sneak up with
my quiver
And beasts of the field say a prayer
Cause I'm carefully aimed for
the liver
Then I shoot from behind
Is that fair?
I don't care.
No one hits like Gaston
Matches wits like Gaston
In a spitting match nobody spits like Gaston
I'm especially good at expectorating!
Ten points for Gaston!
Thank you. Thank you.
When I was a lad I ate four dozen eggs
Every morning to help me get larger
And now that I'm grown I eat five dozen eggs
So I'm roughly the size of a barge!
Who has brains..
like Gaston?
- Entertains
- like Gaston?
Who can make up these endless
refrains like Gaston?
I use antlers in all of
my decorating
Say it again
Who's a man among men?
Who's the super success?
Don't you know?
Can't you guess?
Ask his fans and his five
hhangers-on
There's just one guy in town
Who's got all of it down
And his name's
G-A-S-T..
I believe there's another T..
It just occurred to me that
I'm illiterate
And I've never actually had to
spell it out loud before..
GASTON!
LeFou, you are the best.
How is it no girls snatch you up yet?
I've been told that I'm clingy.
But I don't really get it.
Please, please.
Someone, someone.
Help, help..
You must help me.
It's Belle! He's got Belle.
She's locked in a dungeon!
Who's got her?
A beast!
A huge, horrid, monstrous beast!
My daughter's life is in danger.
Why do you laugh? It's no joke!
His castle is hidden in the woods.
It's already winter there.
Winter in June?
Crazy old Maurice.
Listen to me!
The beast is real.
Do you understand?
Well, no one help me?
I'll help, Maurice.
What?
You will?
Everybody,
stop making fun at this man at once.
Captain, thank you.
Don't thank me, Maurice.
Lead us to the Beast.
Come.
Mama! There's a girl in the castle!
Yes, Chip! We know.
What kind of tea does she likes?
Herbal, oolong,
chamomille?
I'm too excited!
Slow down, before you break
your handle.
Hands up, Mrs. Potts.
Lumière!
I'll be come. Let me do the talking.
You're making her a dinner?
We thought you might appreciate
a company.
Master, I just want to assure you...
that I had no part in this
hopeless plan.
Preparing a dinner, designing a gown
for her, giving her a suite...
in the east wing.
You gave her a bedroom?
No, no, no. He gave her a bedroom.
This is true.
But, if this girl is the one
who can break the spell,
then maybe you could stop by using dinner
to charm her.
- Good thinking, Cogsworth!
- What?
That's the most ridiculous idea I've ever heard!
Charm the prisoner?
But you must try, Master.
With every passing day...
we become less human.
She's the daughter of a common thief.
What kind of person do you think
that makes her?
Ow, you can't judge people by who
their father is, now can you?
You'll join me for dinner.
That's not a request.
Gently, Master.
The girl lost her father
and her freedom in one day.
Yes, the poor thing is probably in there,
scare to death.
Exactly.
Just a minute.
You see? There she is.
Now remember, be gentle.
- Kind!
- Charming!
Sweet!
And when she opens the door,
give her a dashing smile.
Come, come, show me the smile.
- Oh, my God!
- Oh, no.
Will you join me for dinner?
You've taken me as your prisoner,
and now you want to have dinner with me?
Are you insane?
O, o, he's losing it.
Oh, dear.
I told you to join me
for dinner!
I told you, no!
What, what time is it?
What's happening?
I'd starved before I ever
ate with you.
Well, be my guest!
Go ahed and starve!
If she doesn't eat with me,
then she doesn't eat at all.
Idiot!
You can't talk to us like that.
I forbid it.
Am I too late?
Shame, I was ready enough
to tell him off this time.
Oh, Master! You've returned!
- Very funny.
- I got you there!
Show me the girl.
Another petal fell.
Lumière...
I grew three more feathers.
And I just plugged yesterday.
I know, darling.
I'm getting more metallic
everyday.
Oh, no. It's happening again.
Pardon me.
Oh, everyone, calm yourself.
We still have time.
Mama,
am I ever going to be a boy again?
Oh, es, Chip. You'll have your days
in the sun again.
You just leave it to me.
I told you to go away.
Don't worry, dear.
It's only Mrs. Potts.
Oh, I own you a vision!
How lovely...
to my *** to miss.
It's a very long journey.
Let me fix you up
before you go.
I have found..
that most of the troubles
seem less troubling,
after a bracing cup of tea.
Slowly now, Chip.
Pleased to meet you.
Wanna see me do a trick?
Chip!
That was a very brave thing
you did for your father, deary.
Yes.
We all think so.
I'm worried about him.
He's never been on his own.
Cheer up, my puppet.
Things will turn out in the end.
You'll feel a lot better
after dinner.
But he said, "if she doesn't eat with me,
she doesn't eat at all".
People say a lot of things
in anger.
It is our choice whether or not
to listen.
You coming, puppet?
Go.
They're coming! Final checks, everyone!
No, you don't!
If the Master finds that you buy and order
some **. He will blame me!
Yes, I will make sure of it.
But, did you see us stand up to win?
I am telling you, this girl is the one.
They must fall in love,
if we are to be human again.
And how can they fall in love if
she stays in her room?
Ay, Chapeau, you missed
this spot.
You know, she'll never love him.
A broken clock is right two times
a day, mon ami.
But this is not one of those times!
Stand up straight!
It's time to sparkle!
I have no taste buds,
but I can tell this is exquisite.
Get off me while I work!
Pepper, ***!
Salt, ***!
Not so loud. Keep it down.
Of course, of course. But what is dinner
without a little music?
Music?
Maestro Cadanza, are you ready?
It has been so long since
I've performed.
I can't barely even remember how.
Another cavity.
Maestro, your wife is upstairs.
Finding it harder and harder
to stay awake.
She's counting on you to help us
break this curse.
Then I shall play through
the dental pain.
Maestro, play quartet, please.
Oh, quartet. Sotto voce!
Of course!
Are there any other tasteless demands
you wished to make upon my artistry?
No, that's it.
There you are, dear.
Ma chère mademoiselle!
It is with the deepest pride
and greatest pleasure
that we welcome you tonight!
Mhm.. here.
And now,
we invite you to relax.
Let us pull up a chair
as the dining room proudly presents
Your dinner!
Be our.. Guest.
Be our guest
Put our service to the test
Tie your napkin around your neck,
cherie. And we'll
provide the rest.
Soup du jour! Hot hors d'oeuvres!
While we only live to serve.
Try the grey stuff, it's delicious.
Don't believe me? Ask the dishes.
They can sing, they can dance.
After all, Miss, this is France!
And a dinner here is never second best
Go on, unfold your menu
Take a glance and then you'll
be our guest. Oui, our guest.
Be our guest
Beef ragout
Cheese souffle
Pie and pudding "en flambe"
We'll prepare and serve with flair
a culinary cabaret
You're alone and you're scared
But the banquet's all prepared
No one's gloomy or complaining
while the flatware's entertaining
We tell jokes
I do tricks
With my fellow candlesticks
And it's all in perfect taste
that you can bet
Come on and lift your glass
You've won your own free pass
to be our guest
If you're stressed,
it's fine dining we suggest
Be our guest
Be our guest, be our guest
Life is so unnerving for a servant
who's not serving
He's not whole without a soul to wait upon
Ah, those good old days when we were useful
Hey, Cogsworth?
Suddenly those good old days are gone
Too long we've been rusting
Needing so much more than dusting
Needing exercise, a chance to use our skills
Most days we just lay around the castle
Flabby, fat and lazy!
You walked in and oops-a-daisy!
It's a guest! It's a guest!
Sakes alive, well I'll be blessed
Wine's been poured and thank the Lord
I've had the napkins freshly pressed
With dessert, she'll want tea
And my dear that's fine with me
While the cups do their soft shoeing
I'll be bubbling, I'll be brewing
I'll get warm, piping hot
Heaven's sakes! Is that a spot?
Clean it up! We want the company impressed
We've got a lot to do
Is it one lump or two
For you, our guest?
She's our guest
Be our guest, be our guest
Our command is your request
It's ten years since we had anybody here
And we're obsessed
With your meal
With your ease
Yes, indeed, we aim to please
While the candlelight's still glowing
Let us help you
We'll keep going
Course by course
One by one
'Til you shout, "Enough! I'm done!"
Then we'll sing you off to sleep
as you digest
Tonight you'll prop your feet up
But for now, let's eat up
And be our guest
Be our guest
Please, be our guest
Budin?
I don't understand why you'e all
being so kind to me.
Surely, you're as trapped here
as I am.
Don't you ever want to escape?
The Master is not as terrible
as he appears.
Somewhere, deep in his soul
there's a prince..
of a fellow just waiting
to be set free.
Lumière mentioned something
about the west wing.
Never you mind about that.
Off to bed with you, puppet.
- Good night.
- Nighty night.
Straight to bed.
What are you doing here?
What did you do to it?
Nothing.
Do you realize what you could've done?
You could've ruined us all!
Get out of here!
Go!
Check mate. Again.
Wait, No! You're cheating again!
Mademoiselle, what are you doing?
Getting out of here!
Stop!
Go! Go, Froufrou!
Yes­, Froufrou. Stop her!
Don't let her leave!
Stop her!
No, no, Froufrou!
No, no! Not time to play!
Not now, silly boy!
Bad dog! Bad dog!
No! No!
Please, don't go.
It's dangerous!
Oh, my!
You have to help me.
You have to stand.
No! I'm sure this is the way.
Do you hear those wolves?
That means we're getting very close
to the castle.
Look, enough is enough.
We have to turn back.
Stop!
That's it! There it is!
That's the tree!
I'm sure of it.
It.. It was down by lightning
at the time.
But now it's..
resume to an upright
position,
to some sort of..
Magic, or.. Or other.
You really want to marry
into this family?
So that means..
The castle is that..
No.
No, it's...
That way!
Definitely, that way!
I'm done playing this game, Maurice.
Where is Belle?
The Beast took her and she..
There are no such things
as beasts.
Or talking teacups.
Or magic!
But there are wolves, frosbite,
and starvation!
Deep breath, Gaston.
Deep breath.
So why don't we just turn around,
go back to Villeneuve?
I'm sure Belle is at home,
cooking up a lovely dinner.
If you think I've made all this up,
then why did you offer to help?
Because I want to marry your daughter!
Now, let's go home.
Belle is not at home!
She is with the..
You say "beast" one more time,
I will feed you to the wolves!
Gaston! Stop it!
Breath!
Think of happy thoughts.
Go back to the war.
Bloods.
Explosions. Countless widows.
- Widows.
- Yes, yes.
That's it.
Maurice!
Please, forgive me, old bean.
There's no way to talk to
my future father-in-law,
now, is it?
Future father-in-law?
Yes!
You will never marry my daughter.
I saw that, Captain.
If Maurice won't give me
his blessing,
then he's in my way.
Once the wolves have finished
with him
Belle will have no one to take of her,
but me.
Let's say we're adjusting
our all options...
Do we maybe wanna consider
a slightly less gruesome alternatives?
Are you coming?
Get!
That hurts!
If you held still, it wouldn't hurt
as much.
If hadn't runaway,
none of this would've happened.
If you hadn't frightened me,
I wouldn't've runaway!
Well, you shouldn't've been in
the west wing!
Well, you should learn to control
your temper!
Try to get some rest.
Thank you, miss.
We are eternally grateful.
Why do you care about him
so much?
We've looked after him
all his life.
But he's cursed you somehow.
Why?
You did nothing.
You're quite right there, dear.
You see, when the Master
lost his mother
and his cruel father took that
sweet innocent lad, and
twisted him up to be
just like him.
We did nothing.
Let him sleep.
Days in the sun
When my life has barely begun
Not until my whole life is done
Will I ever leave you?
Will I tremble again?
To my dear one's gorgeous refrain
Will you now forever remain
Out of reach of my arms
All those days in the sun
What I'd give to relive just one
Good night, Mama.
Undo what's done
And bring back the light
Oh, I could sing
of the pain these dark days bring
The spell we're under
Still it's the wonder of us
I sing of tonight
How in the midst of all this sorrow
Can so much hope and love endure
I was innocent and certain
Now I'm wiser but unsure
- Days in the back
- I can't go back into my childhood
- Oh, all those precious days
- That my father made secure
I can feel a change in me
I'm stronger now but still not free
Days in the sun
Will return, we must believe
As lovers do
That days in the sun
Will come shining through
What happens when the last petal
falls?
The Master remains a beast forever.
And we become..
- Antiques.
- Knick knacks.
Lightly used housewares.
Rubbish.
We become rubbish.
I want to help you.
There must be someway to break
the curse.
Well, there is one.
It's not for you to worry about,
lamb.
We've made our bad
and we must lie in it.
Drink.
Thank you, Agathe.
"Love can transpose to form
and dignity".
"Love looks not with the eyes,
but with the mind"
"And therefore is winged Cupid
painted blind".
You know Shakespeare?
I had an expensive education.
Actually, "Romeo and Juliet"
is my favorite play.
Ugh, why is that not a surprise?
I'm sorry?
Well, you know that heartache,
pining, and blublb.. ekh.
So many better things to read.
Like what?
Well, there are a couple things in here,
which you could start.
You all right?
It's wonderful!
Yes, I suppose it is.
Well, if you like it so much,
then it's yours.
Have you really read every one
of these books?
What?
Well, not all of them.
Some of them are in Greek.
Was that a joke?
Are you making jokes now?
Maybe.
The air is blue, keen and cold...
"and in a frozen sheath enrolled.
"Each branch, each twig...
"each blade of grass,
seems clad miraculously with...
"glass".
Why does it feel like if I'm seeing it
for the first time?
Is there anymore?
"But in that solemn silence
is heard the whisper...
"of every sleeping things.
"Look. Look at me.
"Come wake me up
"For still here I'll be".
There's something sweet and almost kind
But he was mean and he was coarse
and unrefined
And now he's dear and so unsure
I wonder why I didn't see it there
before
She glanced this way... I though
I saw
And when we touched, she didn't shudder
at my paw
No it can't be, I'll just ignore
But then she's never looked at me
that way before
New and a bit alarming
Who'd have ever thought that this could be?
True that he's no Prince Charming
But there's something in him that
I simply didn't see
- Well, who'd have thought?
- Well, bless my soul
- Well, who'd have known?
- Well, who indeed?
And who'd have guessed they'd come
together on their own?
It's so peculiar, wait and see
We'll wait and see
A few days more
There may be something there
that wasn't there before
Well, here's a thought..
Perhaps there's something there
that wasn't there before
What, Mama?
There may be something there
that wasn't there before
What is it? What's there?
I will tell you when you're older.
Okay, I'm older.
Oh, Chip.
You are ***
What are you reading?
Nothing.
Guinevere and Lancelot
Well, actually..
King Arthur and the Round Table,
Knights, men, swords, and
so on.
But still
it's a romance.
Alright.
I never thank you for saving
my life.
Well, I never thank you
for not leaving me to be eaten
by wolves.
They know how to have
a good time.
Yes, but when I enter the room,
the laughter dies.
Me, too.
The villagers say that I'm
a funny girl.
But I'm not sure they mean it
as a compliment.
I'm sorry.
Your village sounds terrible.
Not as lonely as your castle.
What dou you say
we'd runaway?
Another little gift from the enchantress.
A book that'll allow you to escape.
Amazing!
It was the cruelest trick of all.
It was just another curse.
The outside world has no place
for a creature like me.
But it can for you.
Think of the one place you've always
wanted to see.
Now, find it in your mind's eye.
And then feel it in your heart.
Where did you take us?
Paris.
I used to love Paris.
What would you like to see first?
Notre Dame?
Los Champs-Élysées?
No?
Too touristy?
It's so much more that I imagined.
This is the Paris of my childhood
This what the borders of my life
In this crumbling dusty attic
Where an artist loved his wife
Is it to remember?
Or it to move on?
Knowing the Paris of my childhood..
is gone
What happened to your mother?
It was the one story, Papa can never
bring himself to tell.
I think, better not to ask.
A doctor's mask.
Plague.
You must leave. Now.
Quickly...
before it takes her, too.
I'm sorry I ever called your father
a thief.
Let's go home.
It's just some storm, huh?
At least, we're not tied to a tree
in the middle of nowhere,
surrounded by bloodthirsts
and wolves.
You know, it's not too late.
We could always turn back..
It's just..
everytime I close my eyes,
I picture Maurice stranded alone.
And when I open them,
he is..
Maurice?
Gaston,
did you try to kill Maurice?
Maurice!
Thank heavens!
I've spent the last five days
trying to find you!
You tried to kill me.
You left me to the wolves.
Wolves?
It's one thing to rave about
your delusions
and another, to accuse me of
attempted murder.
Maurice,
do you have any proof of
what you're saying?
Ask Agathe. She rescued me.
Agathe!
You'd hang your accusations
on the testimony
of a filthy hag?
No offense, Agathe.
Monsieur LeFou.
He was there. He saw it all.
Me?
You're right!
Don't take my word for it.
LeFou!
My dearest companion.
Did I,
your loyal friend and most loyal
compatriot,
try to kill the father of the only woman
I've ever loved?
Well, it's a complicated question on a
number of accounts.
But, no.
No, he did not.
You!
Maurice,
it pains me to say this, but you've become
a danger to yourself and others.
No wonder, Belle runaway.
You need a help, Sir.
A place to heal your
troubled mind.
Everything is gonna be fine.
Just fine.
Well, I'd saw her in the ballroom,
and said, "You're making everything
looks so beautiful,
we should have a dance tonight".
I never imagined she'd actually say yes.
What was I thinking?
No, Master. It's perfect!
The rose has only four petals left,
which means tonight..
You can tell her how you feel.
I feel like a fool.
She will never love me.
Do not be discourage.
She is the one.
Please, stop saying that!
There is no "one".
You care for her, don't you?
Well then, woo her with beautiful music
and romantic candlelight.
Yes, and when the moments just right.
Hmhhm.
Well, how will I know?
You'll feel slightly nauseous.
Don't worry, Master. You'll do fine.
Just don't be so nervous and
tell Belle how you feel.
Because if you dont,
I promise, you'll be drinking cold tea
for the rest of your days!
- In the dark.
- Covered in dust.
Dark and very, very dirty.
Start with the hair.
Women love nice hair!
How tidy the fingers and toes?
Chapeau, brush those teeth.
They need it.
Deep, deep.
Snip, snip.
Polish the nails.
Shine the horn.
Eyes close. Puff, puff.
And to top final look.
Voilà!
Okay, I can fix this.
Oh, beautiful!
But something has missing.
Oh, yes!
The finishing touch!
Tale as old as time
True as it can be
Barely even friends
Then somebody bends
unexpectedly
Just a little change
Small, to say the least
Both a little scared
Neither one prepared
Beauty and the Beast
Ever just the same
Ever a surprise
Ever as before
Ever just as sure
As the sun will rise
Tale as old as time
Tune as old as song
Bittersweet and strange
Finding you can change
Learning you were wrong
Certain as the sun
Rising in the east
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the beast.
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the beast.
I hadn't dance in years.
I almost forgot how to feel it.
It's foolish, I suppose,
for a creature like me, to hope..
that one day he might earn
your affection.
I don't know.
Really?
You think you could be happy here?
Can anybody be happy
if they're free?
My father taught me to dance.
I used to step on his toes
a lot.
You must miss him.
Very much.
Would you like to see him?
I'd like to see my father.
Papa!
What are they doing to him?
He.. He's in trouble!
Then you must go to him.
What did you say?
You must go to him.
No time to waste.
No.
You keep it with you.
And you'll always have a way
to look back on me.
Thank you.
Well, Master, I have had my doubts,
but everything's moving like clockwork.
True love really does win the day!
I let her go.
What?
Master, how could you do that?
I had to.
But, why?
Because, he loves her.
Then, why are we not human?
Because, she doesn't love him.
And now, it's too late.
But she might still come back.
No.
I set her free.
I'm sorry I couldn't do the same
for all of you.
Now, go.
Our time has so much passed.
Go, my love.
I was the one who had it all
I was the master of my fate
I never needed anybody in my life
I learnt the truth too late
I'll never shake away the pain
I close my eyes but
she's still there
I let her steal into my melancholy heart
It's more than I can bear
Now I know she'll never leave me
Even as she runs away
She will still torment me
Calm me, hurt me
Move me, come what may
Wasting in my lonely tower
Waiting by an open door
I'll fool myself, she'll walk right in
And be with me forevermore
I rage against the trials of love
I curse the fading of the light
Though she's already flown so far
beyond my reach
She's never out of sight
Now I know she'll never leave me
Even as she fades from view
She will still inspire me
Be a part of everything I do
Wasting in my lonely tower
Waiting by an open door
I'll fool myself, she'll walk right in
And as the long, long nights begin
I'll think of all that might have been
Waiting here forevermore
This man is weak, please!
He needs a hospital.
Not an assylum!
Have you ever see the inside
of a mad house, Maurice?
You wouldn't last a week.
Just give me your daughter's hands,
and I'll set you free.
Never.
Take him away!
Stop!
Papa!
Ah, Belle. I thought I'd lost you.
Let him out! He's hurt!
We can't do that, Miss.
We will take good care of him.
My father's not crazy!
Gaston, tell him!
You know how loyal I am
to your family,
but your father's been making
some unbelievable claims.
It's true, Belle.
He's been raging about a beast
in a castle!
I've just come from the castle
and there is a beast!
You'd say anything to set him free.
Your word is hardly prove!
You want a proof?
Show me the Beast!
That's your proof!
This is sorcery!
Look at this beast!
Look at his face!
His claws!
No, no, don't be afraid!
He's gentle and kind.
The monster has her under a spell!
If I didn't know better, I'd say
she even cared for him!
He's not a monster, Gaston!
You are!
The Beast wouldn't hurt anyone.
I've heard the effect of
dark magic,
but I've never before see it with
my own eyes!
This is a threat
to our very existence!
We can't have her running out
to warn the Beast.
Lock her up, too.
- No!
- Lock her away!
- Shut up!
You won't get away with this, Gaston!
Oh, Belle.
Gaston, with all due respect..
Do you want to be next?
Fetch my horse.
Stand guard!
Don't let them escape!
This creature will curse us all
if we don't stop him!
What I say, we kill the beast!
Kill the beast!
We're not safe until he's dead
He'll come stalking us at night
Set to sacrifice our children to his
monstrous appetite
He'll wreak havoc on our village
if we let him wander free
So it's time to take some action, boys
It's time to follow me
Through the mist, through the woods
Through the darkness and the shadows
It's a nightmare but it's one exciting ride
Say a prayer, then we're there
At the drawbridge of a castle
And there's something truly terrible inside
It's a beast, he's got fangs
Razor sharp ones
Massive paws, killer claws for the feast
Hear him roar, see him roam
But we're not coming home
'Til he's dead
Good and dead!
Kill the beast!
Light your torch, mount your horse
Screw your courage to the sticking place
We're counting on Gaston to lead the way
Call it war, call it threat
You can bet they all will follow
For in times like this,
they'll do just as I say
There's a beast running wild,
there's no question
But I fear the wrong monster's
released
Sally forth! Tally ho!
Grab your sword! Grab your bow!
Praise the Lord and here we go!
Show me the castle!
At least, they've finally learnt to love.
It'd be better for us,
if she does love him in return.
No, this is the first time of
at any real hope, she would.
Did you hear that, Mama?
Is it her? Is she coming back?
Could it be?
I told you!
Sacré bleu!
Invaders!
Rufianes!
Well, where do you go?
So much for true love.
Frame the barricades!
And oppose!
Move aside!
Hearts ablaze, banners high
We go marching into battle
Unafraid although the danger's just
increased
Raise the flag, sing the song
Here we come, we're fifty strong
And fifty Frenchmen can't be wrong
Let's kill the Beast!
We need help.
I have to warn the Beast.
Warn him?
How did you get away from him?
He let me go, Papa.
He sent me back to you.
I don't understand.
Where did you..?
He took me there.
I know what happened to mama.
Then you know why I had to leave her there.
I had to protect you. I.. I've always
tried to protect my little girl.
Probably, too much.
I understand.
Will you help me now?
It's dangerous.
Yes!
Yes, it is.
I could try to pick the lock.
After all,
it's, it's only gears and springs.
But I would need
something long and sharp.
Like that.
Perfect.
Oh, excuse me, Master.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
She's not coming back.
No.
They're breaking down the doors.
Doesn't matter now.
Just let them come.
Kill the beast!
This isn't working.
I know what to do.
Kill the beast! Kill the beast!
Kill the beast!
Are you not at least be concerned
that this castle might be haunted?
Don't lose your nerve, LeFou.
Where are we?
This place seems familiar.
Like I've been here before.
Oh, hello there.
You must be
the talking teacup.
And you must be
his grandmother.
Grandmother?
Attack!
Oh, hallo!
Gaston!
Help me.
Sorry, old friend.
It's hero time.
Hello.
Oh, uh, I believe this is yours.
She is very headstrong.
Do you have children?
No one to protect you now, huh?
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Good shot, Chip, my boy!
Ha ha!
Excellent!
The infantery's arrived!
Now, go and teach some lessons.
Go!
Yes, those are called books,
you low-grade musketeers!
Oh! I'm off.
Just a clock.
Ha ha. Come here,
little boys.
***
Yes, pretty little boys. Yes!
Beautiful!
Go! Be free!
Be free! Be free!
How do you like your tea?
Hot enough?
Or boiling?
Mr. Potts!
Mama!
Thank you!
Take my guts!
Nicely handled!
Well, I used to be on Gaston's side,
but we are so in a bad place
right now.
You're too good for him,
anyway.
Yeah.
Should we get back to it then?
The sweet of music!
***
What?
Maestro!
Darling! I've lost!
I'm coming, my love!
This is it!
The fat lady is singing!
Watch your toes!
That's it! Go! Go!
Bon voyage!
***
Hands stay out!
Hello, Beast!
I'm Gaston.
Belle sent me.
Were you in love with her?
Did you honestly think she'd want you?
Belle!
Where is he?
When we return to the village,
you will marry me!
And that beast's head
- will hang on our wall.
- Never!
I'm telling you, Beast!
No!
Belle?
Belle!
You came back!
I tried to stop them!
Stay there!
I'm coming!
Gaston!
No!
Don't let me go.
Please.
I'll do anything.
Don't let me, Beast.
I am not
the beast.
Go!
Get out!
Don't!
It's too far!
Please!
Come on.
You came back.
Of course, I came back.
I'll never leave you again.
I'm afraid it's my turn to leave.
We're together now.
It's gonna be fine.
At least I could see you.
One last time.
No!
Please, no!
Come back!
We did it, Plumette!
Victory is ours!
Plumette?
Oh, my darling, Plumette.
Oh, no.
Maestro, you were so brave.
Goodbye, my love.
Amore!
No! Don't leave me!
Chip!
Have you seen Chip?
He ran off.
Where is my little boy?
- Mama!
- Oh, no!
Mam!
Lumière,
I, I can't
speak.
It's all right, Cogsworth.
I can't..
Lumière,
my friend.
It was an honor to serve
with you.
The honor was mine.
Come back!
Please, don't leave me!
I love you.
Maestro!
Madame!
Lumière!
Cogsworth, we beat the clock!
Plumette!
Oh, mon amor!
Chip! Look at you!
You're a little boy again!
What did I tell you, darling?
Ohh.. You smell so good.
Froufrou, lamer!
Darling?
Mr. Potts!
Beatrice!
I remember!
I do!
Henry?
Henry!
Oh, dear.
I've been so lonely.
Turn back into a clock.
Lumière, look!
My Prince!
Hello, old friend.
It's so good to see you.
You saved our lives, mademoiselle.
Belle! It's me!
It's Chip!
Tale as old as time
Tune as old as song
Bitterweet and strange
Finding you can change
Learning you were wrong
Winter turns to spring
Famine turns to feast
Nature points the way
Nothing left to say
Beauty and the Beast
What? What is it?
How would you feel about
growing a beard?
Certain as the sun
Rising in the east
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast