It's 12:00 noon in London.
7:00 a.m. in Philadelphia.
And around the world,
it's time for Live Aid.
Wembley welcomes
their Royal Highnesses...
the Prince
and Princess of Wales.
David, look at me.
Oi! You missed one, Pakkie!
I'm not from Pakistan.
Dinner is ready.
I'm not hungry, Mum.
Hmm, where are you going?
- Out with friends.
- A girl?
- Oh, Mum.
- Look at you.
Give your mother
a kiss.
I'm going to be late.
You're always late.
Hi, Papa.
How was work?
Out again, Farrokh?
It's Freddie now, Papa.
Freddie or Farrokh...
what difference does it make
when you're out every night...
no thought of the future
in your head?
Good thoughts,
good words, good deeds.
That's what
you should aspire to.
Yes.
And how's that
worked out for you?
Yeah, they're better
than last week.
- They're a cool band.
- Yeah, not bad.
Yeah.
What can I get for you?
Pint of lager.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
See you, mate.
Humpy Bong?
Humpy Bong.
They're going places.
They're gonna be big.
Humpy Bong?
Are you joking?
Don't do it, Tim.
No, I'm sorry, guys,
but...
we're not going anywhere
with this.
What? College gigs, pubs?
Gotta give it a go.
So I just said to him,
"No, you can't do that."
You literally
can't hear anything.
It's a bit silly.
But then everyone else was
in, like, long dresses?
How bizarre.
You all right?
Sorry. Oh, I was just
looking for the band.
They're usually out back.
I like your coat.
It's from Biba.
She works there.
Thank you.
I think he's right.
That show
was a load of bollocks.
Well, there was room
for improvement, yeah.
I've got better things to do
with my Saturday nights.
I could give you
their names.
I enjoyed the show.
- Thanks, man.
- Thank you.
I've been following you
for a while, actually.
Smile.
Makes sense
for a dental student.
And you're astrophysics,
aren't you?
- Yeah.
- Makes you the clever one.
Yeah, I suppose
it does, yeah.
I study design here.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Also, um, I write songs.
Might be
of interest to you.
It's just a bit of fun,
really.
Well, you're
5 minutes too late.
Our lead singer
just quit.
Well, then you'll need
someone new.
Any ideas?
What about me?
Uh, not with those teeth,
mate.
I know what I'm doin'
I got a feeling
I should be doin' all right
Doin' all right
I was born with
4 additional incisors.
More space in my mouth
means more range.
I'll consider your offer.
Uh, do you play bass?
Nope.
Excuse me. Thanks.
So, you found me, then.
- How can I help you?
- Oh.
Um, I rather liked these.
Do you think
you have them in my size?
This is the ladies' section,
so I'm not exactly sure.
There wasn't a sign
or anything.
I don't think it should
really matter, do you?
I thought
you might like this.
Are you even allowed
to be in here?
No, not really.
One more thing.
May I?
You have such
an exotic look.
I love your style.
I think we should all
take more risks.
What do you think?
Oh, cheers.
Thank you.
Hello, everybody.
We've got a few fresh faces.
This is John Deacon,
our bass player.
Yeah, and
our new lead singer...
Freddie Bul... Bulsara...
Freddie Bulsara.
That's right.
And Roger, of course. The
biggest member of them all.
Hey, Roger!
Hello,
all you beautiful people.
Where's Tim?
Who's the Pakkie?
Ready, Freddie?
Let's do it.
Keep yourself alive
I was told a million times
Of all the troubles in my way
Mind you grow a little wiser
Little better every day
But if I rode a million
rivers
-  And I crossed a million miles
- No, no.
-  Still be where I started
- Wrong lyric!
-  Bread and butter for a smile
- Wrong lyric.
Sold a million mirrors
In shopping alley ways
But I never saw my face
In any window any day
Now they say your folks
are telling you
Be a super star
Tell you,
just be satisfied
And stay right where you are
Keep yourself alive
All you people
Learn the song, Freddie.
You're late.
This is bollocks!
It's counterclockwise,
I think you'll find, John.
Oh, is it?
Thank you, Brian.
Would you like to do it?
Please, feel free.
No, no, no.
Doing a good job.
We sold out every pub and uni
south of Glasgow...
and I'm stuck
in the middle of nowhere,
eating a ham sandwich!
Trouble is, we're just not
thinking big enough.
What have you
got in mind, Fred?
An album.
We can't afford an album.
Oh, we'll find a way.
How much do you think
we can get for this van?
I hope you're joking.
That's 3 months' wages.
And a perfectly good van.
Don't be so dramatic,
darling.
You're recording
an album tonight. Let's go!
Don't you think
I sound like shit?
No, it's good.
- Can we try it again?
- Sure, yeah.
Sure, it's your money.
Literally.
Sounds a lot better.
We need to
get experimental.
Try bouncing us left and right
for the ah-ah-ahs.
Now dead center for the last.
And then blast it!
Yes!
That's good, right?
Do we have time
to stack a few more?
The studio opens at 8:00,
so we got 30 more minutes.
Hmm.
- That sounds good, right?
- Yeah.
Oi, RT, who are these kids
in the box?
A student band
doing some weird stuff.
How about demos?
You got some?
Been up all night,
mate.
So the new name is Queen?
As in "Her Royal Highness."
And because
it's outrageous...
and I can't think of anyone
more outrageous than me.
This is the most
impractical bed.
That's beautiful.
Think it has potential.
- I have to go to work.
- I simply won't allow it.
You're going to support me
if I get fired?
I'll always
look after you.
I'm going to...
I'm going to be late.
How beautiful you are.
When I was a little girl...
I used to run around the house
and hide and...
he couldn't find me.
Clever girl.
Please tell your father
it's nice to meet him.
I have.
Then thank him
for the lovely birthday cake.
I have.
Then tell him his daughter's
an epic shag.
Freddie,
he can read lips.
Mary...
I can't tell you how long
I have waited for Farrokh...
to bring home
a nice girl like you.
Farrokh?
Did Farrokh not tell you
he was born in Zanzibar?
- No, he did not.
- I used to know a girl
- who was Zanzibari.
- 1 minute.
I thought Freddie
was born in London.
- Oh, he was. At the age of 18.
- Shut up.
Our family is
Indian Parsee.
- Mum. Mum, Mum.
- Mary...
- Mum.
- Mum, please...
Here. Have a look at these.
- Yes. Yeah.
- Please! Please.
- No stopping.
- We need to see those.
A thousand years ago,
the Parsees fled to India
from Persia...
to escape Muslim persecution.
Really?
That's terrible.
So why did you
leave Zanzibar?
We didn't leave.
He's so small.
We were chased out with just
the clothes on our backs.
He was quite a good boxer,
actually.
He had to be.
His opponents
went for his teeth
always trying to
punch them in.
Certainly a target.
So how old is he
in this photo?
I think 3
or 4 years old.
Really?
Boxing already at that age?
So good.
Mercury?
No looking back.
Only forward.
So now the family name's
not good enough for you?
It's just a stage name.
No, it's not.
I changed it legally.
Got a new passport
and everything.
Kash, how old are you here?
I don't know.
It was before Freddie went off
to boarding school.
I sent Farrokh away to make
a good Parsee boy of him.
He was too wild and unruly.
But what good did it do?
Good thoughts,
good words, good deeds.
You can't get anywhere
pretending to be
someone you're not.
Who'd like some cake?
Cake is always good.
Hello?
Just a moment.
Freddie Mercury.
Phone call.
Quite like
the sound of that.
Freddie tells me that you're
some sort of a scientist.
- Astrophysics, actually.
- Oh.
Yeah, my father would've
preferred it if I continued.
- When?
- That's very clever.
- He's a dentist.
- I was never a dentist.
That's a picture
I want to see.
He's a dentist.
I see.
That's also quite clever,
actually.
Kash...
what are you doing later?
Homework.
Just making conversation.
What kind of music
was he listening to
back in those days?
Uh, he was listening to
Little Richard.
- Very good.
- Richard, yeah.
And his first band...
I have an announcement.
One of the A&R men...
from EMI saw us recording.
Gave our demo
to John Reid.
He looks after Elton John.
Oh, my God.
Mr. Reid wants to meet us...
and possibly, even manage us.
- Shut up.
- You're joking!
Oh, my God!
You're sure
he said 12 o'clock?
Yes. "Midday at
the pub, don't be drunk."
That's what he said.
You look
a bit nervous, Brian.
John, I'm fine.
You're usually
so particular.
You just gotta be cool.
- Wow!
- Wanker.
I didn't know
it was fancy dress, Fred.
I've gotta make
an impression, darling.
You look like
an angry lizard.
- It's your best work.
- Very subtle.
You gonna fly away?
Can I borrow it
for Sunday church?
So, this is Queen.
And you must be
Freddie Mercury.
You've got a gift.
You all have.
So tell me...
what makes Queen
any different
from all the other
wannabe rock stars I meet?
I'll tell you what it is.
We're 4 misfits
who don't belong together,
playing to the other misfits.
The outcasts right at the back
of the room...
who are pretty sure
they don't belong either.
We belong to them.
We're a family.
But no 2 of us
are the same.
Paul.
Paul Prenter...
meet Queen...
our new signing.
Paul will be looking after
your day-to-day.
Pleasure.
If I can get you
on the radio...
maybe I can get you
on television.
- Top of the Pops?
- Hopefully.
And then?
And then...
it's only the biggest
television program
in the country.
No one's ever even
heard of you.
Look, I admire
your enthusiasm.
If it goes well,
if it happens...
I've got a promotional tour
of Japan in mind.
We'll want more.
Every band wants more.
Every band's not Queen.
- Listen, I understand.
- Hurry up.
I understand that
it's the policy of the BBC.
- We have procedures.
- This is shit!
I need you to explain it
to the band, please.
- Okay, let's make it quick.
- Freddie, boys.
Look, chaps,
it is going to be playback.
Lip synch's
all that's required.
We do know how to
play our instruments.
You want me to lip synch?
I don't understand why
we can't simply perform live.
The audience will never know
the difference.
We'll know
the bloody difference.
This is the BBC.
That's how things are done
around here. All right?
Don't be a nuisance.
Freddie, it'll be great.
You'll just have to make sure
no one's looking at your lips.
Well,
the way things are done
are a load of bollocks,
old chap.
This is the BBC.
I'm relieved.
You would be.
Perfect performance.
She's a Killer Queen
Gunpowder, gelatine
Dynamite with a laser beam
Guaranteed to blow your mind
Anytime
Number 2,
only above the waist.
Camera up!
Camera 2!
No one wants to see this
while they're eating
their meal.
Drop of a hat
she's as willing as
Playful as a pussy cat
Momentarily out of action
Temporarily out of gas
To absolutely drive you
wild, wild
What was it like singing
for all those people?
When I know
they're listening...
when I know
I really have them...
I couldn't sing off-key
if I tried.
I'm exactly the person
I was always meant to be.
I'm not afraid of anything.
The only other time
I ever feel that way
is when I'm with you.
Don't move.
You're the love of my life.
Freddie.
Which finger
do I put this on?
Wedding finger.
Will you marry me?
Yes!
Are you gonna leave it
in the box?
Freddie, it's beautiful.
I love it.
Promise me
you'll never take it off.
Oh, I promise.
No matter what.
I love you, Freddie.
You're going to do
such great things.
We're going to do
great things.
Your phone's
off the hook.
This is Crystal.
Cheryl!
Oh, that's right.
My mistake.
Where's your loo?
Uh, just down the hall.
Oh, come on in.
Make yourselves at home.
Don't mind us.
Hello, Mary.
How's your dad?
Yeah, pretty well.
Thanks.
- Good.
- What's going on, Brian?
Well, if you'd answered your
phone, you'd know already.
This really isn't
a good time, guys.
John Reid called today.
He has a little tour
in mind for us.
It's not little,
Brian.
He's booked us a tour
of America.
The album's hit the charts
in the U.S.!
Oh, yes!
Yes!
It's happening!
Now, who wants to take a ride?
We love you, Cleveland!
We love you, Houston!
We love you, Denver!
Very happy to be here!
And are the crowds big?
Well, we're selling out
every night.
I just wish you were here
to see it.
They really love us.
We love you, Portland!
He's got a big ass, too!
We love you, New Orleans!
We love you, Atlanta!
Rog, come down here
and say hello.
We love you, Pittsburgh!
- Roger!
- Now, hit it!
I'm good.
I just miss you.
What are you doing?
You can't possibly be having
any fun without me.
Nothing as exciting
as America.
Say hi to the boys for me.
I will. Love you.
Bye, Freddie. I love you.
Hello.
- You're late.
- Am I?
We saved you a seat.
- Lovely.
- Okay.
So, now that
we're all here...
Jim, this is Ray Foster.
Ray, this is the
band's lawyer, Jim Beach.
Hello.
You must stop
calling him that.
That's his name.
No, we cannot keep
calling him "Jim Beach."
No, that's absurd, not to
mention, unspeakably boring.
Miami.
From now on,
I dub thee "Miami Beach."
The sun always sets
behind you, doesn't it?
On Miami Beach.
Hmm, right.
Now that everybody's
got an acceptable name...
let's get to it.
Look...
we just really need
something special.
More hits...
like Killer Queen...
only bigger.
It's not bloody widgets
we're making.
We can't just
reproduce Killer Queen.
No.
We can do better.
It's opera.
- Opera!
There seems to be
an echo in here.
See, we don't want to
repeat ourselves.
The same formula
over and over.
Formulas are a complete
and utter waste of time.
Formulas work.
Let's stick
with the formulas.
I like formulas.
We'll call the album...
A Night at the Opera.
Are you aware that no one
actually likes opera?
I like opera.
- Do you?
- I do.
No, don't
misunderstand, darling.
It's a rock and roll record...
with the scale of opera...
the pathos of Greek tragedy...
the wit of Shakespeare...
the unbridled joy
of musical theater.
- It's a musical experience.
- Yeah.
Rather than just
another record.
Something for everyone...
something...
Hmm.
Something that will make
people feel belongs to them.
We'll mix genres,
we'll cross boundaries...
we'll speak in bloody tongues
if we want to.
There's no musical ghetto
that can contain us.
- That's it.
- No one knows what Queen means
because it doesn't mean
one thing.
What do you think, John?
I...
agree with the band.
Of course you do.
How about you, uh...
- Miami.
- Hmm.
Fortune favors the bold.
Surely, a man of your...
unique taste...
isn't afraid
of a little risk?
Please don't make me
regret this.
You're fun.
Recording studio?
Well, the idea was to get away
from all distractions.
Right, I know it's not
the Ritz. Not even close.
- Roger, you're in here.
- Right.
Freddie, this is you.
Biggest room.
Brian, that's you.
John, you're downstairs.
And...
this is all yours, John.
Smaller rooms
don't get nearly as cold.
Okay.
Hmm.
Oh, that's really good.
Love of my
life, you've hurt me
You've broken my heart
And now you leave me
Love of my life,
can't you see?
Bring it back, bring it back
Bring it back,
bring it back
Don't take it away from me
Because you don't know
What it means to me
Hmm.
It's beautiful.
What's it called?
Love of My Life.
I wrote it for Mary.
If you say so.
Don't misunderstand, Paul.
Mary knows me in a way
that no one else ever will.
I know you, Freddie Mercury.
Is that what you think?
Oh, no, you don't know me.
You just see
what you want to see.
We work together.
That's all.
I put my heart and soul
into this song.
No one is disputing that.
And you don't like it
because you want
your songs on the album!
- It's not that, Roger.
- Then what is it?
I'm in Love with My Car.
Maybe it's not
strong enough?
What does that even
mean, "not strong enough"?
I know I'm late.
What did I miss?
Discussing Roger's
car song.
Is it strong enough?
That's all I'm asking.
If I'm on my own here,
then I apologize.
How does your new song go,
then, hmm?
"You call me sweet...
"like I'm some
kind of cheese."
- It's good.
- Wow.
"When my hand's
on your grease gun..."
That's very subtle,
isn't it?
It's a metaphor, Brian.
It's just a bit weird,
Roger.
What exactly are you doing
with that car?
Children, please.
We could all
murder each other...
but then who would be left
to record this album?
Statistically speaking,
most bands don't fail,
they break up.
Why the hell would
you say something like that?
Roger, there's only room
in this band
for one hysterical queen.
You know why
you're angry, Roger?
Why?
'Cause you know your song
isn't strong enough.
- Not...
- Is that strong enough?
What about that?
Not the coffee machine!
Goodbye, everybody
I've got to go
Gotta leave you all behind
and face the truth
Mama
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh
I don't wanna die
I sometimes wish
I'd never been born at all
What next?
That was pretty damn good.
Brilliant.
I love that.
Press the button, Freddie.
I know,
I know where it is.
I know where...
Knock, knock.
Good.
It's good. Um...
You know,
play it like you wrote it.
Well, I did.
I wrote that part.
Taking the piss.
Okay. Are you happy?
I think it's beautiful.
It's almost perfect.
Almost?
Yes, give it
more rock and roll.
I'm always up for that, Fred.
Put your body into it.
Right. Okay.
Put my body into it.
I got it.
Not like that.
No, I got it. I got it.
Bit more soul, yeah?
All right.
Give it more heart.
I'll do that. We good to go?
Roy, you good?
Oh, and then there's
the operatic section.
You're gonna love it.
The operatic section?
- I know, it sounds crazy.
- I love it, Fred. I love it.
I don't know.
It could be a flop.
- It could work.
- I love it!
What have we got to lose?
Nothing.
If you say so.
Okay, let's go.
Deacy.
How was that?
- Freddie?
- Higher.
Can you go a bit higher?
If I go any higher,
only dogs will hear me.
Try.
Freddie's note. Sorry.
Go on, roll the tape.
Overdub 24 of "Fred's Thing."
How was that?
- Better?
- Higher.
Jesus! How many more
"Galileos" do you want?
Freddie wants to do
a few more overdubs.
Do we even have
any tape left?
I do have to say
the tape is wearing out.
It can't take much more.
Yeah, we can't afford
much more.
We're already
3 weeks over schedule.
Dub 26 of "Fred's Thing."
One more, one more.
One more.
Again.
Go on, roll the track.
Who even is Galileo?
My nuts feel like
they're in my chest right now.
- Are we done?
- That's it.
He loves you.
That's it.
It's beautiful! Love it!
Christ.
Well...
I'm not entirely sure...
that's the album
you promised us.
No, it's better than the album
we promised you.
It's better than any album
anyone's ever promised you,
darling.
It's a bloody masterpiece.
- Christ.
- It is a good album, Ray.
We prefer "masterpiece."
It's expensive,
and as for...
"Bohemian..."
Rhapsody.
What is that?
- It's an epic poem.
- It goes on forever.
6 bloody minutes.
I pity your wife if you think
6 minutes is forever.
And do you know what?
We're going to release it
as our single.
Not possible.
Anything over 3 minutes...
and the radio stations
won't program it, period.
And what on earth
is it about, anyway?
Scaramouche?
Galileo?
And all that
"Ismillah" business!
"Ishmillah"?
Bismillah.
Oh, aye.
What's it about, anyway?
Bloody Bismillah?
True poetry
is for the listener.
It ruins the mystery
if everything's explained.
Seldom ruins sales.
3 minutes
is the standard.
John.
Yeah, we need radio.
Format is 3 minutes,
I have to agree with Ray.
I actually think
the single's Love of My Life.
No.
Okay, how about John's song...
You're My Best Friend?
You know?
"Ooh, you make me live."
Catchy, stronger.
What about
I'm in Love with My Car?
You're joking!
Oh, Jesus.
I love it.
Well,
that's the kind of song...
teenagers can crank up
the volume in their car...
and bang their heads to.
Bohemian Rhapsody
will never be that song.
It's a band decision,
Bohemian Rhapsody.
- That's it.
- You're My Best Friend...
and it's my money.
Bo-Rap, period.
Or we walk.
MacArthur Park
was seven minutes long.
It was a hit.
Look, I'm not arguing
Bohemian whatever's...
- musicianship.
- ...Rhapsody.
But there's no way in hell
the station will play...
a 6-minute
quasi-operatic dirge...
comprised of nonsense words!
Bismillah? Bullshit!
I paid for this record,
so I say what goes!
Have we no legal
recourse on this?
Ray...
you did Dark Side of the Moon,
didn't you?
I did.
Yeah, I absolutely
love that record.
Legally, no.
No, he's got all your balls
in a vice.
It's a different matter
in the court
of public opinion,
of course.
Ray Foster's a giant name
in the music industry, but...
to the average person...
Say the name Queen,
on the other hand...
ears prick up.
We're going with
You're My Best Friend.
- Done.
- No.
We know what we have,
even if you don't.
It's called Bohemian Rhapsody.
You will forever be known
as the man who lost Queen.
Temperamental artists, eh?
They're well aware
they're tied to a contract...
but who knows
what goes on...
inside the inscrutable mind
of the recording artist?
Mark these words.
If they're not careful...
by the end of the year...
no one will know
the name Queen.
Christ!
You can take that
out of our royalties!
- Twat!
- Wanker!
You can shove
your gold disks!
You made a mistake, Foster!
Arsehole!
You'll never have
a gold disk...
you medium talent!
And to think
I worked with Hendrix.
In the studio today...
...singer Frederick Mercury!
So what have you
got today for us?
Have you got a little taste
of the new record?
I'm really not supposed to.
Oh, forbidden fruit?
Don't tempt me!
- "I'm in Love with My Car!"
- Other side.
"Bohemian Rhapsody."
I didn't know Freddie
knew Kenny so well.
The BBC won't play it.
Nor did I.
In fact, no one will play it
on the radio...
so EMI won't release it.
What's wrong
with this song?
Nothing's wrong
with it at all.
Except that
it's 6 minutes long.
6 minutes?
You'd have to be mad
to play it.
Oh, you'd have to be bonkers.
- I positively forbid it.
- Let's hear it.
Ladies and ladies...
a Capital Radio exclusive...
for the first time ever...
Bohemian Rhapsody!
Is this the real life?
Is this just fantasy?
So you think you can
stone me and spit in my eye?
So you think you can love me
and leave me to die?
Oh, baby
Can't do this to me, baby
Just gotta get out
Just gotta get
right outta here
Yeah
How much do they love him?
Can't get enough.
Nothing really matters
Anyone can see
Nothing really matters to me
Any way the wind blows
Tom, Jerry, can you hear me?
Freddie,
when do I get to see you?
I'll be home soon, darling.
Will you put Romeo
on the phone
so I can tell him I miss him?
Do you miss me?
What a stupid question.
Of course I do.
I love you.
Good night.
Morning, boss.
Clean this mess up
and get rid of your friend.
Get dressed.
According to Brian...
it was the largest paying
audience in history.
The whole night...
I didn't know
if they understood a thing
I was saying.
And then...
Love of my
life, you've hurt me
You've broken my heart
And now you leave me
Love of my life,
can't you see?
Bring it back, bring it back
Don't take it away from me
They're all singing.
Thousands of them.
All singing to you.
Because it's true.
Freddie, what's wrong?
Love of my life,
don't leave me
You've stolen my love
And now desert me
Something's been wrong
for a while now.
Say it.
I've been thinking
about it a lot.
I think I'm bisexual.
Freddie, you're gay.
I've known for a while now.
I just didn't want to
admit it.
It's funny, really. This is
what I always settle for.
"I love you, but..."
"I love you, Mary,
but I need space."
but I've met someone else."
And now,
"I love you, but I'm..."
And this is the hardest,
because it's not
even your fault.
No, don't take it off.
Don't take it off.
You promised me
you'd never take it off.
What do you want from me?
Almost everything.
I want you in my life.
Why?
We believe in each other.
And that's everything.
For us.
Your life is going to be
very difficult.
What do you think?
Gay-er?
Not this, darling, the house.
Isn't it amazing?
Mary's already
moved in next door,
so she can visit
the cats and me.
Uh-huh.
Each cat will have
his own room.
Delilah's by the kitchen...
Miko's next door.
Tiffany, Oscar, Romeo,
all upstairs.
Lilly's room is even larger
than this one! Spoilt thing.
Well, I'm not sure
the echo is quite
pronounced enough.
Eh-oh!
Oh, I knew
you'd appreciate it.
Stay for dinner.
Anything you fancy.
I can't.
Wife, kids, you know.
Of course.
Well, come on.
We'll eat off the floor.
It's clean enough.
Another time, Fred.
- Hello?
- Mary.
- Hi.
- Hello, my love.
Hi.
I need you to do
something for me.
But you can't
ask any questions.
Freddie, what are you
doing this time?
No, I just told you...
you can't ask any questions.
Right.
I want you to go
to your bedroom window.
Look out of it.
- Do you see me?
- Yes, I do see you.
Now, you do the same.
Oh...
Keep yours on.
Come have a drink.
- Now?
- Right now.
It's late, Freddie.
Come on.
Please.
Do you have something
to drink?
I suppose.
Go get it.
Pour yourself something.
Pour yourself a drink,
darling.
Do you have it?
Yes.
Cheers.
To you, my love.
To you, Freddie.
Good night.
- Hello?
- Paul.
Freddie?
Sweetheart,
I want to throw a party.
Okay.
Who do you want to invite?
People.
I want you to shake
the freak tree
and invite anyone
who plops to the ground.
Dwarfs and giants...
magicians, Zulu tribesmen,
contortionists...
fire eaters...
and priests.
We're going to
need to confess.
Fill me up, will you, Trixie?
Marvelous, Fred!
You've outdone yourself!
Thank you, John.
I'm so glad you love it!
Mmm. They say money can't
buy happiness, darlings!
But it does allow you
to give it away!
I see you and Paul
are getting along quite well.
He's Trixie now...
'cause he's always
up to something.
So, tell me, Rog...
what's the sexiest part
of a car?
Ah!
Well, well, well!
Ah, your majesty!
No, I'm not her majesty!
We're her majesty, darlings!
- Cheers!
- Thank you, my loves!
- Rog.
Where's Mary?
It's not exactly
her scene, is it, Freddie?
Hmm.
Fabulous, isn't it?
If you say so.
Hmm.
You're starting to look
like each other.
What's wrong with that,
Brian?
You're supposed to be
in a rock band, Freddie.
Not the Village People.
You might want to think about
cutting your hair one day.
Never.
I was born like this.
Come on!
- Let's dance!
- Yes!
I don't dance, Freddie.
I need a few more
of these for that.
It's my party,
and I demand you dance!
We should go.
By royal decree!
We're gonna go, actually.
Oh, God! You're dull.
If you were any more dull,
you'd be Deacy.
What are you
complaining about?
You've got your little pet.
I have...
and he's loyal.
Loyalty's so important.
Don't you think, Dominique?
Careful, Fred.
- Let's go.
- Where you going?
Home.
Just a joke.
Freddie, sometimes
you're a total prick.
- Good night.
- Brian.
Forget them.
Come on!
Your guests are waiting.
They all want a little
Mercury in their cup.
Come on.
All right!
My darlings...
the time has finally come...
to get absolutely...
shit-faced!
Whoo!
Senor, where's
my marching powder?
You've got a set of balls.
Go fetch me
a drink and find out.
I may work
for you tonight...
but put your hands on me
again, and I'll thump you.
Got it?
I'm terribly sorry.
I didn't mean to offend you.
I'm sorry.
I won't do that again,
all right?
Let me get you a beer.
I wouldn't mind a beer.
Can you just tell me where
we keep them?
You're very handsome.
I love a man in uniform.
So do I.
So, all your friends
have left you alone.
They're not my friends.
Not really.
Just distraction.
From what?
The in-between moments,
I suppose.
I find them intolerable.
All of the...
darkness you thought you left
behind comes creeping back in.
I know what you mean.
Really?
What is it that
you do with them?
Spend them
with real friends.
You look like
you could use a friend.
I like you.
I like you, too, Freddie.
Come and find me when
you decide you like yourself.
Can I have
your name at least?
It's Jim Hutton.
- Good night, Jim.
- Good night, Freddie.
Or should I say good morning?
I want a new boat.
This one is for me.
This one.
Didn't you say
we were going to see him?
- I've got an hour left.
- Wait. What about this one?
No, I think
we'll still make that.
It's a good size.
Screw him.
Everyone up
on the drum risers!
- Up on the drum risers.
- Come on!
Thank you, Chrissie.
Showing some enthusiasm.
- Wives and everyone, Brian?
- Me?
Yes! Come on, John. Everyone.
- I'm not waiting any longer.
- Let's go.
Get up.
- Bass?
- No, you don't need it.
Get up.
- Come on, Rog, take your time.
- All right.
What's this about?
You remember our last concert?
The crowd were singing
our songs back to us.
I mean, it was deafening,
but it was wonderful.
They're becoming
a part of our show.
I want to encourage that,
so...
I've got an idea to involve
them a little bit more.
Let's start with this.
Stamp to this beat.
Genius.
Thank you, John.
Come on.
Good.
Now, I want you to clap
on the third beat.
Don't speed up.
Rog, keep that time.
No Prenter?
It's unusual to see you
without your clone.
It's unusual seeing you
be so bitchy.
It's usually me.
Ah, you kept time, Rog.
Good.
What's going on?
You'd know
if you were on time.
I'm a performer, darling,
not a Swiss train conductor.
Sorry I'm late.
Again.
All right.
Now, will you
please tell me
why you're not playing
any instruments?
I wanna give the audience
a song that they can perform.
All right?
Let them be part of the band.
So, what can they do?
Imagine...
thousands of people...
doing this in unison.
Huh?
Well?
What's the lyric?
Buddy, you're a boy
Make a big noise
Playing in the street
Gonna be a big man some day
You got mud on your face
You big disgrace
Kickin' your can
all over the place
Singin'
-  We will, we will rock you
Buddy, you're a young man,
hard man
Shouting in the street
Gonna take on
the world some day
You got blood on your face
You big disgrace
Wavin' your banner
all over the place
-  We will, we will rock you
Singin'
Yeah!
Buddy, you're an old man,
poor man
Pleading with your eyes
Gonna get you
some peace someday
You got mud on your face
Big disgrace
Somebody better put you
Back into your place
Do it!
-  We will, we will rock you
-  Rock you
Yeah!
All right! I feel like taking
a bite out of the Big Apple!
Who wants to take a bite
out of me?
All right, play with me now.
Eh-oh!
- Eh-oh!
Never seen anyone interact
with a crowd like that.
Bigger than any band,
don't you think?
I mean, Queen...
how long can that last?
Did he say
something to you?
Not explicitly.
But we've had some interest
from CBS Records...
about a solo deal.
Well, that's a big number.
That's a Freddie-size number.
You should be the one
to propose it.
Hi, guys. How's it going?
- Good.
- Everything's great.
John, another drink?
Er, no, I'm fine.
Here's the Coke.
Coming right up.
- Freddie.
- Oh, there you are.
Oh, God! Freddie!
Put me down!
You were brilliant.
Ah, that's only because
I knew you were watching.
I've missed you.
We have
so much to catch up on.
Oh, thank you.
This is my boyfriend, David.
David, this is Freddie.
Magnificent show.
Thank you.
It's so kind of you,
I appreciate it.
Thank you so much.
Where's your ring?
I just didn't want to travel
with something so valuable.
Freddie, there are some people
here for you to see.
You promised you'd say hello.
- Oh, did I?
- Mmm-hmm.
We should go.
Will I see you soon?
Yes, of course.
Of course.
Mwah!
It's a pleasure to meet you,
David.
And you.
And well done again.
Bye.
Thank you for coming
such a long way.
Bye.
Then you've got
the MTV interview...
and the plane to Houston
for the special.
Back here on Friday.
Listen to me now.
Do you know who sold
4% of all the records
purchased last year?
Worldwide?
Michael Jackson.
Not the Jackson 5.
And I think
you could do even better.
In fact, I've had an offer
from CBS Records.
It's a lot of money
for you, Fred,
and I think
you should consider it.
Are you asking me
to break up the band?
I'm just pointing out what
awaits you if you go solo.
An end to your
frustrations.
My frustrations?
Paul?
I don't know what
you're talking about, John.
Perhaps I misunderstood.
Yes, sir.
Pull over.
Stop the car, pull over.
- Get out. Out now!
- What the hell?
Get out of this car.
You're fired.
What're you talking about,
fired?
I said get out.
- Freddie, you are high!
- I said get out!
What are you
talking about?
Out! Out or I'll kill you!
Get out,
you treacherous piss flap.
You're not
thinking clearly.
Get your ass
out of my car now.
Get out!
Out!
Get your ass out of my car!
Get out!
You're firing the
wrong snake, Freddie.
You'll regret it.
Get your ass out of here!
Drive!
Hey! What the hell? Move!
Hey, watch it!
I'll run your ass over!
Move!
Did you know
anything about this?
I warned him against it.
Pure greed.
Tried to break up
my family.
We can manage the band.
We don't need him.
What do you know
about what I need?
I know what it's like...
not to belong.
A queer Catholic boy
from Belfast.
You know...
I think my father
would rather see me dead...
than let me be who I am.
I'm gonna take care
of you now, Freddie.
If you'll let me.
What are you reading?
Just the cricket.
We're a rock and roll band.
We don't do disco.
- It's not disco.
- Then what is it?
It's Queen.
So sorry, my darlings!
Lost all track!
You fired Reid
without consulting us!
You don't make decisions
for the band.
Hey.
Well, I'm terribly sorry,
dear.
It's done.
Besides...
Miami will manage us.
Won't you, darling?
Erm... I'll think about it.
- No.
- Are you high again?
Well done, Columbo.
You need to slow down, Fred.
Oh, don't be such a bore.
I'm here, aren't I?
Are you?
I don't care
if you're shit-faced.
As long as you can sing.
No, John,
I don't wanna play it.
Then I'm all for it.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm tired of
the bloody anthems.
I want the energy
in the clubs.
The bodies,
- I want to make people move.
- You mean disco?
Why not?
Do you mind pissing off?
This is a band discussion.
Drum loops?
Synthesizers?
- If you say so.
- It's not us!
- Us?
- It's not Queen!
Queen is whatever
I say it is!
Well, you can play
your own bloody drums, then.
Fred.
Okay, let's see how good
a boxer you really are!
Roger, take it easy!
Take it easy!
Take it easy.
All right, Muhammad Ali.
That's...
That's quite a cool riff,
actually.
Hmm. You wrote that?
That's really good.
Yes, it will be...
if you all can
just shut up and play.
- He started it.
- Oh, shut up!
Steve walks warily
down the street
With the brim pulled
way down low
Ain't no sound
But the sound of his feet
Machine guns ready to go
Are you ready
Are you ready for this?
Are you hanging
on the edge of your seat?
Out of the doorway
the bullets rip
Okay, I'll do it.
To the sound of the beat
I'll do it.
Oh, just improvise. Just
give it whatever you want.
I can do that.
Let's go!
Steve walks warily
down the street
With the brim pulled
way down low
Ain't no sound
but the sound of his feet
Machine guns ready to go
Are you ready, hey
Are you ready for this?
Are you hanging
on the edge of your seat?
Out of the doorway
the bullets rip
Rip
To the sound of the beat,
yeah
Another one bites the dust
And another one gone
Another one bites the dust,
yeah
- That's a good idea.
-  Hey
I'm gonna get you, too
And then you double it,
on top.
How do you think
I'm gonna get along
Without you
when you're gone?
You took me for everything
that I had
And kicked me
out on my own
Are you happy,
are you satisfied?
How long can you
stand the heat?
Out of the doorway
the bullets rip
To the sound of the beat
Look out!
Freddie!
Freddie! Freddie,
as the leader of Queen...
do you feel responsible
for the success of the band?
I'm not the leader of Queen,
I'm only the lead singer.
Freddie!
A question for Freddie.
Do you ever
doubt your talent?
No, that's a stupid question.
- Take it easy, Fred.
- What's next?
Freddie, uh, your teeth!
Why don't you
get your teeth fixed?
I live in Britain.
I don't want to stand out.
Next...
Why don't you have
your manners fixed?
That's an asshole question
to ask anybody.
That's an asshole question.
In your song Life Is Real,
what do you mean
by the line...
"Love is a roulette wheel"?
Are you implying that
the more partners you have...
the more chances
you have of...
contracting something?
What?
I don't know, I haven't
figured out love yet.
But it implies something else,
Freddie.
That might be
a better question for Rog.
Watch it.
Freddie, concerning
your private life...
there's lots of pictures
of you in the tabloids...
looking drunk or ill.
Which one is it, ill or drunk?
I had a cold last week,
if anyone cares.
As much as we'd love to answer
questions about colds...
I'd like to speak
about the album.
If anyone's got any questions
about the music?
Freddie! Freddie!
Freddie!
Freddie! Freddie,
your parents...
they're conservative
Zoroastrians.
I wonder, what do they make
of your public persona?
Is that music...
My parents died
in a fiery wreck.
I happen to know
that's not true, is it?
I just wanted to know whether
they were proud of you.
Are your parents
proud of you?
Is this what they hoped for?
I hope that they are.
I surely don't think so.
Anyone wanna talk
about the album?
Freddie! Freddie!
Freddie!
Could you answer
my questions please?
This better be good.
Shut up!
Freddie, could you
tell us about the rumors
concerning your sexuality?
What about the rumors
concerning your lack
of sexuality?
I'm just a musical prostitute,
my dear.
Can you answer
the question?
What's your name, dear?
Shelley Stern.
- Shelley.
- Yes.
That thing between your legs,
does it bite?
Hah!
Could you answer the question,
please?
We're here as a courtesy.
You know, there's
four of us up here.
What are you afraid of,
Freddie?
What do you want?
What is the truth?
Can you be honest for once?
Why are you lying
about your parents, Freddie?
I'm not lying about anything.
I just, I'm...
Your fans deserve
to know the truth, Freddie.
Can you answer the question,
please?
This is my business.
No, you're a public figure.
What are you afraid of,
Freddie?
- Your parents?
- Can you tell us
- about...
- Your sexuality?
What? Why, why...
Can you just be honest?
Contracting something.
Your fans deserve
to know the truth.
Our readers want to know.
What do your readers want to
know? They want to know what?
But life still goes on
I can't get used to
living without
Living without
Living without you
by my side
I don't want to live alone
Hey
God knows
Got to make it on my own
So, baby, can't you see?
I've got to break free
Brilliant!
Can I get up now?
What is happening?
No, you can't.
- I wanna be in it.
- Get off me!
Freddie, you in there?
Freddie?
They're here.
We can't put this off
any longer.
Freddie?
MTV banned our video.
The youth of America.
We helped give birth to MTV.
It's America.
They're Puritans in public,
perverts in private.
I'm never touring
in the U.S. again.
And I'm
the one being blamed for it.
Not you, dear...
whose idea, I believe, it was
to dress up in drag.
And not you.
Not even you,
who wrote the bloody thing.
No.
Crazy, cross-dressing Freddie.
Freddie the freak.
Freddie the fag.
I'm tired of touring.
Aren't you?
Album, tour, album, tour.
I want to do
something different.
We're a band.
That's what bands do.
Album, tour, album, tour.
Well, I need a break.
I'm sick of it.
What are you saying,
Freddie?
I've signed a deal
with CBS Records.
- You've done what?
- Without telling us?
What kind of deal?
Look, I'm not saying we won't
record or ever tour again.
Queen will go on.
But I need to do
something different.
Do you know what I mean?
I need to grow.
What's the song?
"Fly away"?
"Spread my wings
and fly away."
A solo album?
Two, actually.
- Back to back.
- Another word out of you...
and I'll throw you out
the bloody window.
But that's years, Freddie.
I mean...
- that'll take years.
- Ye of little faith.
I don't believe this.
How much?
What did they pay you?
I wanna know how much
they paid you...
$4 million!
That's more than
any Queen deal.
Look, the routine
is killing us.
I mean, you must all want a
break from all the arguments.
I mean, whose song
gets on the album...
whose song's the single...
who wrote what...
who gets a bigger slice
of the royalties...
what's on the B-side,
all of it.
You must need a break.
Freddie, we're a family.
No, we're not!
We're not a family!
You've got families,
children, wives.
What have I got?
You've got $4 million. Perhaps
you can buy yourself a family.
I won't compromise
my vision any longer.
Compromise?
Are you joking?
You were working at Heathrow
before we gave you a chance.
And without me...
you'd be a dentist...
drumming 12/8-time blues
at the weekend
at the Crown and Anchor.
And you.
Well, you would be
Dr. Brian May...
author of a fascinating
dissertation on the cosmos...
that no one ever reads.
And Deacy...
for the life of me...
nothing comes to mind.
I studied
electrical engineering.
Does that meet
your standard?
Perfect.
You just killed Queen.
Oh, give it a kiss one day.
She might wake up.
You need us, Freddie.
More than you know.
I don't need anyone.
Hello?
Paul.
Can I speak to Freddie?
Oh, Mary.
No, he can't talk right now.
He's working day and night,
constantly.
Will you make sure
to tell him that I called?
Don't worry,
he's in safe hands.
I will certainly
tell him you called.
Cheers.
Freddie, it's really great.
It's shit!
Just leave it.
Yeah,
hang on one second.
Give it more treble.
Where is he? Is he
there? I wanna speak to him.
He is working himself
to the bone.
I'm blue in the face trying
to get him to take a break.
Paul, listen to me.
It's one performance
for a good cause.
It's a televised concert
for the famine in Ethiopia.
They're gonna have
simultaneous performances
in Philadelphia and London.
There's gonna be
a billion people watching.
Queen should be part of it.
He's just been
really focused.
But I'll be sure
to pass it on.
Sure you will.
Hi.
Come in, come in.
Why did you
come all this way?
I just haven't heard
from you in so long,
and I phoned and phoned,
and then...
last night I just had
this terrible dream
that something bad
had happened.
No, no.
I've been working, that's all.
Freddie, you're burning
the candle at both ends.
Yes, but the glow
is so divine.
Being human
is a condition
that requires
a little anesthesia.
- I miss you.
I miss you so much.
Listen, but I have to finish
the second album.
I need you.
Stay. Stay here with me.
Just you and me.
I need the love of my life.
Freddie...
What about Queen?
Jim told me he's been trying
to contact you
about Live Aid...
and you won't
take his calls.
What is Live Aid?
You haven't heard?
Freddie,
it's the biggest concert
there's ever been
or ever will be.
It's for the famine
in Africa.
Well, perhaps Paul thought
it wasn't a good idea.
A distraction from my work.
That's what's important,
that I finish this album.
Stay with me, darling,
and I'll be all right.
Freddie,
I can't stay with you.
Of course you can.
I need you, Mary.
Freddie, I'm pregnant.
How could you?
How could I?
Freddie, this has nothing
to do with you.
Come on. Let's get in.
I bought some nibbles.
Freddie.
Sorry we're late.
Mary.
What a pleasant surprise.
Hans. Everyone, come in.
Milan,
make our guests comfortable.
I wish I knew
you were coming to stay.
I'd have scrubbed the place.
Actually, I'm not staying.
Wait. Mary, wait. Don't go.
You told me
you had a dream.
What was it?
I was trying
to talk to you, but...
it was like
talking to my father.
You needed
to tell me something...
but you couldn't say it.
Because you had no voice.
Freddie, come and
say hello to our new guests.
They're dying to meet you.
He'll be one second.
Mary!
I'm happy for you, Mary.
Truly, I am.
It's just...
I'm frightened.
Freddie,
you don't need to be.
Because no matter what,
you are loved.
By me, by Brian,
Deacy, Roger...
your family.
It's enough.
And these people...
they don't care about you.
Paul doesn't care about you.
You don't belong here,
Freddie.
Come home.
Home.
Freddie!
What are you doing?
You'll catch your death.
Why didn't you tell me
about Live Aid?
The Africa charity gig?
It'll be an embarrassment.
I didn't wanna
waste your time.
You should have told me.
Of course I did.
You forgot.
You're always
forgetting things.
Come in now
and have a drink.
You're out.
What do you mean?
I want you out of my life.
'Cause I'm the only one left,
you're blaming me
for everything?
I blame myself.
So I'm out?
Just like that?
After everything
we've been through?
Just think of
the photos I have.
I know who you are,
Freddie Mercury.
You know when
you know you've gone rotten?
Really rotten?
Fruit flies.
Dirty little fruit flies.
Coming to feast
on what's left.
Well, there isn't much left
for you to feast on anymore.
So, fly off.
Do what you like with your
photographs and your stories.
But promise me one thing.
That I never see
your face again.
Ever.
I didn't mean it.
I'm sorry!
Freddie, come back!
I'll make it better.
But, Peter,
you might be right.
I'm not even hurt
by the fact that
he's let me go as a friend.
But you can only be there
so much for a person.
And so, Mr. Prenter...
all these stories
about Freddie Mercury
and his lovers...
that there were so many.
Yeah?
- Is it really true?
- Yes, it is.
His lovers were countless.
Genuinely countless. Uh...
All these wild,
drug-fueled parties...
where he'd find
another lover every night...
and a routine
he couldn't get out of.
So, you really
did see behind the mask?
I knew Freddie when
he did Bohemian Rhapsody.
And the Freddie we have now...
he doesn't have
the same passion about music.
Hello?
Miami?
Freddie?
How are you?
There was
this Africa concert...
that wants Queen to play.
Is that still...
You mean Live Aid?
They've announced
all the bands, Freddie.
It's too late.
I need...
I need to reconnect
with the mothership.
Freddie, they don't want
anything to do with you.
They're still very upset.
Maybe if you ask them...
they would meet me.
Tell them I want to talk.
Just talk.
We're family.
You know, family...
have fights...
all the time.
I can call.
Thank you...
Jim.
As this friend,
somebody who...
probably knows Freddie Mercury
better than anybody else...
how would you describe him
inside as a person?
For me,
Freddie will always be...
this frightened
little Pakkie boy...
who's afraid to be alone.
I hope he sees this
and realizes
what he has lost in you.
I hope he does, too.
A close and important friend.
Where are they?
They're late.
Hi, guys.
Jim.
If anybody wants
any tea, coffee...
bladed weapons...
just ask.
So...
who wants to go first?
I'll start.
I've been hideous.
I know that, and...
I deserve your fury.
I've been conceited...
selfish.
Well, an asshole, basically.
Strong beginning.
Look, I'm happy to
strip off my shirt...
and flagellate myself
before you.
Or rather, I could ask you
a simple question.
I'm good
with the flagellation.
What's it gonna take
for you all to forgive me?
Is that what you want,
Freddie?
I forgive you.
- Is that it? Can we go now?
- No.
I went to Munich.
I hired a bunch of guys.
I told them exactly
what I wanted them to do...
and the problem was...
they did it.
No pushback from Roger.
None of your rewrites.
None of his funny looks.
I need you.
And you need me.
Let's face it.
We're not bad
for four aging queens.
So, um, go ahead.
Name your terms.
Could you give us a moment,
please, Fred?
Why'd you do that?
I just felt like it.
They'll be all right.
They just need a bit of time.
What if I don't have time?
What do you mean, Fred?
You can come back in now,
if you'd like.
We decided...
What did we decide?
From now on...
every song, no matter
who wrote it, music, lyrics...
it's by Queen.
Not one of us, just Queen.
All the money,
all the credits,
split four ways evenly.
Done.
We have a problem
with the people around you.
Paul is out.
I fired him.
- On what pretext?
- Villainy.
What else?
Bob Geldof.
I called to convince him
to squeeze you guys
into the lineup
for the Live Aid concert...
but he wants an answer now.
You have to make a decision.
Every ticket's already sold.
100,000 people at Wembley...
100,000 people at
JFK Stadium in Philadelphia...
a global TV audience around
the world of 150 countries...
13 satellites.
The Olympics only had three.
We haven't
played together in years.
It's kinda suicide
to play again...
for the first time
in front of millions.
Try over 1.5 billion.
"Who are
these 4 dinosaurs?"
"Where's Madonna?"
It's a 20-minute set.
Everyone gets the same.
Jagger, Bowie...
Elton...
McCartney, The Who...
Led Zeppelin...
Phil Collins,
REO Speedwagon...
Bob Dylan.
Certainly good company.
Anybody who is anybody
is doing this concert.
Look.
All I know...
is that if we wake up
the day after this concert...
and we didn't do our part...
we're going to regret it
till the day we die.
Please.
Every day, in San Francisco,
two more men
hear the grim news...
"You have AIDS,
there's no cure."
Since doctors
in France and America
isolated the virus in 1983...
research has proceeded
at a frantic pace.
The method used by the virus
to destroy
the body's immune system...
has been discovered...
but a cure still seems
many years away.
A major breakthrough
has been a new blood test...
that should ensure
that in future...
nobody contracts AIDS
from a blood transfusion.
But it's only just
been approved for use.
What is this thing
that builds our dreams
Yet slips away from us?
Who wants to live forever?
There's no chance for us
It's all decided for us
This world has only one
Sweet moment
set aside for us
Do you understand?
The way we go from here is
that treatments are available.
They're not particularly
effective, Freddie.
Eh-oh!
Eh-oh.
Yep.
Mmm-hmm.
- Let's call it. Yeah?
- Yeah, yeah.
Sorry.
I sound like shit.
You all are lovely,
you sound good.
Been a while.
My throat feels like
a vulture's crotch.
We still got a week.
We'll get there.
Yeah, we're in
a good place, Fred.
You just need a bit of rest,
that's all.
Yeah.
Get a drink, Rog?
Yeah,
there's a nice little pub
- down the road, actually.
- Can I come?
We're just an exclusive...
No, of course not.
Invite-only.
Yeah,
that's kind of you.
Before you leave...
Could I have a second?
Yeah. What's up?
I've got it.
Got what?
AIDS.
I wanted you to
hear it from me.
Fred, I'm so sorry.
Brian, stop.
Don't.
For right now...
it's between us.
All right? Just us.
So, please...
if any of you...
fuss about it or frown
about it, or, worst of all...
if you bore me
with your sympathy...
that's just seconds wasted.
Seconds that could be used
making music...
which is all I want to do
with the time I have left.
I don't have time
to be their victim...
their AIDS poster boy,
their cautionary tale.
No, I decide who I am.
I'm going to be
what I was born to be.
A performer...
who gives the people
what they want.
Touch of the heavens.
Freddie fucking Mercury.
You're a legend, Fred.
You're bloody right I am.
We're all legends.
But you're right,
I am a legend.
Now, you give me a chance
to get my bitchy little
vocal cords in order...
and we'll go and punch a hole
through the roof
of that stadium.
Actually,
Wembley doesn't have a roof.
- All right.
- No, he's right. It doesn't.
Then we'll punch a hole
in the sky.
Now, even though you're crying
like 3 little girls...
I still love you.
- All right, enough of this.
- All right.
- Drink?
- Yes!
Or 10?
What are you looking at?
You think
you could do better?
Everyone's a critic.
It's 12:00 noon in London.
7:00 a.m. in Philadelphia.
And around the world,
it's time for Live Aid.
If you have
credit cards...
you can phone up with
the number you want to give.
But you can also pledge cash,
and it's very important.
There is not enough money
coming in...
and all these people
are not playing
for the good of their health.
They're playing for the good
of other people's health.
So get your money out now!
And phone up
and give us the money.
You've got plenty of it,
or if you got none of it...
get it to people
who are dying of starvation.
We want to get a million
pounds out of this country.
On the telephone,
before 10:00 tonight.
Do you have any idea...
how many Jim Huttons
there are in London?
Well, I didn't want to make it
too easy for you.
How have you been, Freddie?
I've been a bit lost,
to be honest.
You were right.
I could do with a friend.
Would you like
to have tea with me?
Tea?
So, Jim,
how do you know Freddie?
Do you work together?
Jim's my friend.
Wonderful to have friends.
Mithai. Jer made it herself.
Thank you.
- Freddie?
- Your favorite, Freddie.
We have to go, Mum.
But you just got here, beta.
What do you mean, "go"?
We've gotta get to Wembley.
Would you believe it?
Jim's never been
to a rock concert.
That's true.
Queen are
playing at Live Aid.
We're all doing our bit
for the starving children
in Africa...
and nobody's
taking any money.
Good thoughts, good words,
good deeds.
Just like you taught me, Papa.
Love you, beta.
Bye, Kash.
Love you, too, Mama.
In fact...
I'll blow you a kiss
when I'm on stage.
Kashi...
put on the telly.
- Hello, Mary!
- Hi, Brian!
We just came
to wish you good luck.
Hello, my love.
Hi.
Mary, David...
this is Jim.
Jim...
Mary and David.
It's nice to meet you.
- Hi.
I'll see you after.
I don't think
you're gonna be able to see
anything from here.
Join them.
What do we think of David?
Nice chap.
I think he's gay.
We'll be on
in about one minute.
1, 2. 1, 2.
That's almost us.
We ready?
Feel good?
So we have had
a bit of a complaint
about the noise.
From a woman in Belgium.
Anyway...
it gives us enormous pleasure
to introduce the next combo...
who are...
Queen!
Her Majesty...
- Queen!
- Check, two, check.
Nothing.
Mama
Just killed a man
Put a gun against his head
Pulled my trigger,
now he's dead
Mama
Life had just begun
But now I've gone
and thrown it all away
Mama
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh
Didn't mean to make you cry
If I'm not back again
this time tomorrow
Carry on, carry on
As if nothing really matters
Too late
My time has come
Sends shivers down my spine
Body's aching all the time
Goodbye, everybody
I've got to go
Gotta leave you all behind
and face the truth
Mama
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh
I don't want to die
I sometimes wish
I'd never been born at all
I'd sit alone
and watch your light
My only friend
through teenage nights
And everything
I had to know
I heard it on my radio
You gave them all
those old-time stars
Through wars of worlds
invaded by Mars
You made 'em laugh,
you made 'em cry
You made us feel
like we could fly
So don't become
some background noise
A backdrop
for the girls and boys
Who just don't know
or just don't care
And just complain
when you're not there
You had your time,
you had the power
You've yet to have
your finest hour
Radio
Everybody!
All we hear is
Radio ga ga
Radio goo goo
All we hear is
Radio ga ga
Radio goo goo
All we hear is
Radio ga ga
Radio blah blah
Radio, what's new?
Radio
Someone still loves you
Loves
You
Eh-oh!
- All right!
Hey! Hammer to Fall!
Here we
stand or here we fall
History don't care at all
Make the bed,
light the light
Lady Mercy
won't be home tonight
You don't waste
no time at all
Don't hear the bell
but you answer the call
It comes to you as to us all
Yeah! And it's time
for the hammer to fall
Every night, every day
A little piece of you
is falling away
But lift your face
the Western way
Toe your line
and play their game
Then it's time
for the hammer to fall
Rich or poor or famous
Hello? Live Aid.
- Hello? Live Aid.
- Hello? This is Live Aid.
Oh, no
Lock your door
Hello, Live Aid.
- We just hit a million!
- 1 million pounds!
1 million pounds!
Thanks. Great.
For you who grew up
tall and proud
In the shadow
of the mushroom cloud
Convinced our voices
can't be heard
Just wanna scream it louder
And louder and louder
What the hell
we fighting for?
And it's time
for the hammer to
Hammer to fall
Yeah
Yeah, yeah
One more time!
Waiting for
the hammer to fall
Give it to me one more time!
I've paid my dues
Time after time
I've done my sentence
But committed no crime
And bad mistakes
I've made a few
I've had my share of sand
kicked in my face
But I've come through
We are the champions,
my friends
And we'll keep on fighting
till the end
We are the champions
No time for losers
'Cause we are the champions
Of the world
I've taken my bows
And my curtain calls
You brought me
fame and fortune
And everything
that goes with it
I thank you all
But it's been
no bed of roses
No pleasure cruise
I consider it a challenge
Before the whole human race
And I ain't gonna lose
We are the champions,
my friends
And we'll keep on fighting
till the end
We are the champions
No time for losers
'Cause we are the champions
We are the champions,
my friends
And we'll keep on fighting
till the end
We are the champions
No time for losers
'Cause we are the champions
Of the world
So long and goodbye!
We love you!