Subtitle By: Ivandrofly
& Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: July 17, 2018
(CELTIC FLUTE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRDSONG)
Where are you?
Come out!
(LAUGHS)
Come on out.
(GIGGLES)
- I'm coming to get you.
- (GIGGLES)
Where are you, you little
rascal? I'm coming to get you.
Hm.
(CHUCKLES)
Where is my little
birthday girl, hm?
I'm going to gobble her
up when I find her.
- Oh! (LAUGHS)
(SQUEALS)
I'm going to eat you.
I am.
(MAKES MUNCHING NOISES)
Och, Fergus, no
weapons on the table.
Can I shoot an arrow? Can I?
Can I? Can I? Can I?
Please? Can I?
(LAUGHS)
- Not with that. Why not...
- (GIGGLES)
use your very own?
(GASPS)
- Happy Birthday, my wee darling!
(BOW BEING PLUCKED)
- Now, there's a good girl.
- (STRAINS)
Draw all the way back now to
your cheek. That's right.
Keep both eyes open.
And, loose!
- I missed.
- Go and fetch it, then.
A bow, Fergus?
She's a lady.
- Ooh! You!
- (LAUGHS)
(BIRDS CALLING)
(CREAKING)
(LONE BIRD CALLS)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(HIGH-PITCHED CALL)
A will-o-the-wisp.
(GROWLING)
They are real.
ELINOR: Merida, come
along, sweetheart.
- We're leaving now.
- MERIDA: I saw a wisp.
- I saw a wisp.
- A wisp?
You know, some say that
will-o-the-wisps lead you to your fate.
- Oh, aye. Or an arrow.
- Och!
Come on, let's be off before
we see a dancing Tatty Bogle.
Or a giant having a
jigger in the bluebells.
Your father doesn't
believe in magic.
Well, he should.
Because it's true.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(GROWLS)
Mor'du! Elinor, run!
(ROARS)
- Sire!
(YELLS)
(SNARLS)
Come on, you!
(ROARS)
MERIDA: Some say our destiny
is tied to the land...
as much a pan' of
us as we are of it.
Others say fate is woven
together like a cloth.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
So that one's destiny
intertwines with many others.
It's the one thing we search
for or fight to change.
Some never find it.
But there are
some who are led.
(YELLS)
The story of how my
father lost his leg
to the demon bear
Mor'du became legend.
(GROANING)
I became a sister to
three new brothers.
The princes. Hamish,
Hubert and Harris.
Wee devils, more like.
They get away with murder.
I can never get
away with anything.
I'm the Princess.
- Oh!
- (BAGPIPES PLAYING)
MERIDA: I'm the example.
(SLURPS)
I've got duties,
responsibilities, expectations.
My whole life is planned out,
preparing for the
day I become...
Well, my mother.
She's in charge of every
single day of my life.
(BAGPIPES CEASE)
(SIGHS)
"Aye, Robin, Jolly Robin, and
thou shalt know of mine."
Project!
"And thou shalt know of mine!"
Enunciate. You must be understood
from anywhere in the room,
or it's all for naught.
- This is all for naught.
- I heard that!
(SIGHS)
- From the top.
A Princess must be knowledgeable
about her kingdom.
She does not doodle.
(PLAYS NOTES)
That's a C, dear.
(SCREECHES)
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHS AND SNORTS)
A Princess does not chortle.
- Mm!
- Does not stuff her gob!
Rises early.
- Is compassionate...
- (CHICKEN SQUAWKS)
patient, cautious,
clean.
And above all, a Princess strives
for... Well, perfection.
MERIDA: But every
once in a while,
there's a day when I don't
have to be a Princess.
No lessons, no expectations.
A day where anything
can happen.
A day I can change my fate.
Yeah!
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
When cold wind is a' calling, and
the sky is clear and bright.
Misty mountains sing and beckon,
lead me out into the light.
I will ride, I will fly.
Chase the wind and
touch the sky.
I will fly Chase the
wind and touch the sky.
Wooh-hoo!
(EAGLE CALLS)
Where dark woods hide secrets and
mountains are fierce and bold.
Deep waters hold reflections
of times lost long ago.
I will read every story,
take hold of my own dream.
- Oh!
- (HORSE WHINNIES)
Be as strong as the
seas are Stormy.
And proud as an
eagle's scream.
I will ride, I will fly.
Chase the wind and
touch the sky.
I will fly Chase the
wind and touch the sky
(SCREAMS EXCITEDLY)
And touch the sky.
Wooh!
Chase the wind.
Touch the sky
(WHINNIES)
I'm starving. You
hungry too, Angus?
Pfft!
- Oats it is, then.
- (SNORTS)
Good day, Princess.
I cannot find the salt.
Where did you put it?
It was over there a minute ago,
the last time I looked at it.
And then, out of nowhere, the
biggest bear you've ever seen!
His hide littered with the
weapons of fallen warriors.
His face scarred
with one dead eye.
I drew my sword and...
Whoosh!
One swipe, his sword shattered.
Then "chomp"!
Dad's leg was clean off.
Down the monster's
throat it went.
Oh, that's my favorite part.
Mor'du has never
been seen since,
and is roaming the wilds
waiting his chance of revenge.
(ROARING)
- Let him return.
I'll finish what I guddled
in the first place.
Merida, a Princess does not
place her weapons on the table.
Mum!
It's just my bow.
A Princess should not have
weapons in my opinion.
FERGUS: Leave her be.
Princess or not, learning
to fight is essential.
Mum? You'll never guess
what I did today.
- Hm?
- I climbed the Crone's Tooth,
and drank from the Fire Falls.
Fire Falls?
They say only the ancient kings were
brave enough to drink the fire.
(LAUGHS)
- What did you do, dear?
- Nothing, Mum.
Hungry, aren't we?
- Mum!
- You'll get dreadful collywobbles.
Oh, Fergus, will you look
at your daughter's plate?
(DOGS BARKING)
- So what?
- Oh, you great...
- Don't let them lick... (SIGHS)
Boys, you're naughty.
Don't just play
with your haggis.
- Urgh! (GAGGING)
- Och, how do you know you don't like it,
if you won't try it?
That's just a wee
sheep's stomach.
It's delicious. Mm!
(SMACKS LIPS)
- My lady.
- Thank you, Maudie.
FERGUS: You're getting
too big, the two of you.
ELINOR: Aha.
From the Lords Macintosh,
MacGuffin and Dingwall.
Their responses, no doubt.
Aye, aye!
FERGUS: Hey, hey!
(LAUGHS) (MUNCHING LOUDLY)
Stay out of my food,
you greedy mongrels.
Chew on that, you manky dogs!
(FERGUS LAUGHS)
- Fergus?
They've all accepted.
(DOGS SLOBBERING)
Who's accepted what, Mother?
Boys, you are excused.
(GIGGLING)
- Oof!
- (DOGS BARKING)
Hey!
(LAUGHS)
What did I do now?
Your father has something
to discuss with you.
Fergus?
Oh.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(COUGHS)
Er... Merida.
(SIGHS) The lords are presenting their
sons as suitors for your betrothal.
- What?
- The clans have accepted.
- Dad!
- What? (STAMMERS) I...
You... She... Elinor?
Honestly, Merida, I don't know
why you're reacting this way.
(SIGHS IN FRUSTRATION)
This year, each clan will present a suitor
to compete in the games for your hand.
I suppose a Princess just
does what she's told?
A Princess does not
raise her voice.
Merida, this is what you've been
preparing for your whole life.
No, it's what you've been
preparing me for my whole life.
I won't go through with it.
You can't make me.
Merida!
Huh? Merida!
- Urgh!
- (DOGS BARKING)
Boys!
(GRUNTING)
Mother. Suitors? Marriage?
Once there was an
ancient kingdom...
Oh, Mum!
Ancient kingdom.
It's name long forgotten,
ruled by a wise and fair
King who was much beloved.
And when he grew old he divided
the kingdom among his four sons,
that they should be the pillars on
which the peace of the land rested.
But the oldest Prince wanted
to rule the land for himself.
He followed his own path
and the kingdom fell
to war, and chaos and ruin.
That's a nice story.
It's not just a story, Merida.
Legends are lessons.
They ring with truths.
Och, Mum.
I would advise you to make
your peace with this.
The clans are coming to
present their suitors.
- It's not fair.
- Och, Merida.
It's marriage. It's not
the end of the world.
(SIGHS IN DISBELIEF)
(ELINOR MUTTERING)
FERGUS: - You're muttering.
- I don't mutter.
Aye, you do. You mutter, lass,
when something's troubling you.
I blame you. Stubbornness.
It's entirely from your
side of the family.
(LAUGHS) I take it the talk
didn't go too well, then?
Ooh, I don't know what to do.
- Speak to her, dear.
- I do speak to her.
- She just doesn't listen.
- Come on, now.
Pretend I'm Merida.
Speak to me.
What would you say?
Ooh... I can't do this.
Sure you can.
There, there.
That's my Queen.
Right, here we go.
"I don't want to get married."
"I want to stay single and let
my hair flow in the wind"
"as I ride through the Glen
firing arrows into the sunset."
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Merida, all this work, all the
time spent preparing you,
schooling you, giving you
everything we never had.
I ask you, what do
you expect us to do?
Call off the gathering.
Would that kill them?
You're the Queen.
You can just tell the lords the
Princess is not ready for this.
In fact, she might not ever be
ready for this, so that's that.
Good day to you. We'll expect your
declarations of war in the morning.
I understand this
must all seem unfair.
Even I had reservations
when I faced betrothal.
But we can't just run
away from who we are.
I don't want my life to be over.
I want my freedom!
But are you willing to pay the
price your freedom will cost?
I'm not doing any of
this to hurt you.
If you could just try to see
what I do, I do out of love.
But it's my life, it's...
(SIGHS)
I'm just not ready.
I think you'd see,
if you could just...
I think I could make you
understand if you would just...
- listen.
- Listen.
(WHINNIES)
I swear, Angus, this
isn't going to happen.
Not if I have any say in it.
(EXERTIVE GRUNTING)
(DRUMS POUNDING)
(MEN STRAINING)
(DRUMS BEATING RHYTHMICALLY)
MacGuffin!
MEN: MacGuffin!
- Dingwall!
MEN: - Dingwall!
- Macintosh!
MEN: - Macintosh!
Ooh! Aah!
Oh.
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTS)
You look absolutely beautiful.
I can't breathe.
Och, shush!
Give us a turn.
(GROANS)
I can't move.
It's too tight.
(STRAINS)
- It's perfect.
(GROANS)
(STRAINS)
- Merida?
- Mum?
Just...
Remember to smile.
(SNORING)
(PRINCES LAUGHING)
(CONTINUES SNORING)
- Aye, they're coming.
Places, everyone. Places.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(DOGS BARKING)
Oh!
(PRINCES GRUNTING)
(FERGUS CHUCKLES)
I look fine, woman! Leave me be!
GUARD: My Lord!
I want to announce the
arrival of the lords...
- Ow!
- Who goes there? Who goes there?
(BAGPIPES PLAYING)
Boy!
(ALL CRY OUT)
(SHOUTING)
(SILENCE)
So, here we are... Er...
the four clans.
MAN: - Aye.
- Er... Gathering...
- Oh.
- For...
- (DISCONTENTED MURMURS)
- the presentation of the suitors.
- The presentation of the suitors.
(ALL CHEERING)
FERGUS: - Clan Macintosh.
MEN: Macintosh!
Your Majesty, I present
my heir and scion,
who defended our land from
the northern invaders,
and with his own
sword, Stab Blooder,
vanquished 1,000 foes.
MEN: Macintosh!
(SCOFFS)
FERGUS: - Clan MacGuffin!
MEN: MacGuffin!
Good Majesty, I present
my eldest son,
who scuttled the
Viking longships
and with his bare hands
vanquished 2,000 foes.
MEN: MacGuffin!
Clan Dingwall.
MEN: Dingwall!
I present my only son
who was besieged
by 10,000 Romans
and he took out a whole
armada singlehandedly.
With one arm, he was...
With one arm he was
steering the ship
and with the other he
held his mighty sword
and struck down a whole
attacking fleet.
MAN: - Lies!
- What? I heard that.
(MEN SNICKERING)
- Go on. Say it to my face.
Or are ye scared,
simpering jackanapes,
afraid to muss your pretty hair?
- At least we have hair.
- And all our teeth.
(SPEAKS IN THICK ACCENT)
MAN: - Huh?
(SHEEP BLEATS)
And we don't hide under
Bridges, you grumpy old troll.
(ALL LAUGHING)
You want to laugh, huh?
Wee Dingwall!
(SCREAMS)
Get off me!
(LAUGHING)
(PLAYING LIVELY TUNE)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
(YELPS)
Nut them! Nut them!
That's the way to...
Alright.
Shut it!
(MUSIC WINDS DOWN)
Now, that's all done. You've
had your go at each other.
Show a little decorum.
And no more fighting.
(MACE CLANGING)
(SCREAMS)
(LIVELY TUNE CONTINUES)
(YELLING)
(BATTLE CRY)
Ow!
(GROANS)
(SHEEP BLEATS)
(YELLS)
FERGUS: You want a fresh one?
(MUSIC STOPS)
(CLAN CHIEFS WHINING IN PAIN)
FERGUS: Crivens,
you're fierce.
I didn't start it. It was...
My lady Queen, I feel terrible.
My humblest apologies.
- We mean no disrespect.
- I'm sorry, love, I didn't... But...
- Yes, dear.
- (CLEARS THROAT)
Now, where were we?
Ah, yes.
In accordance with our laws,
by the rights of our heritage,
only the firstborn of
each of the great leaders
- may be presented as champion.
- Firstborn?
And thus compete for the hand
of the Princess of Dun Broch.
To win the fair maiden they
must prove their worth
by feats of strength
or arms in the games.
It is customary that the challenge be
determined by the Princess herself.
Archery!
Archery.
(ALL MURMURING)
I choose archery.
- Let the games begin!
- (ALL CHEERING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
Pull!
- Pull!
- (MEN CRYING OUT IN SURPRISE)
(LIVELY BAGPIPES PLAYING)
(MAN ROARING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(MOOING AND BARKING)
- I'll just take one.
- Ooh!
PRINCE: Ooh!
Oh!
Now, I have told you,
you're not allowed... Oh!
- Oh!
- Argh!
(PRINCES GIGGLING)
- Oh!
(SHEEP BLEATING)
(HORN SOUNDING)
(DOGS HOWL)
(CROWD CHEERING)
It's time!
- Archers, to your marks!
- Aye, archers, to your marks.
And may the lucky arrow
find it's target.
(FERGUS CHUCKLES)
(EXCITED SQUEALING)
Oi! Get on with it.
CROWD: Ooh. (LAUGHS)
(GROANS)
- Och!
- I bet he wishes he was tossing cabers.
- Or holding up Bridges. (LAUGHS)
- Shh!
(GIRLS SQUEAL)
CROWD: Aw...
(YELLS ANGRILY)
At least you hit
the target, son.
(CONTINUES YELLING)
Oh, that's attractive.
(CONTINUES WAILING)
MAN: - I got it!
- Good arm.
And such lovely flowing locks.
- Fergus.
- What?
(LAUGHTER)
(GASPS)
Oh, wee lamb.
Oh, come on!
Shoot, boy!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(LAUGHS IN TRIUMPH)
Well done, lad! Well done.
(STARTS SINGING)
- Feast your eyes!
- (CHIEFS SCREAM)
- That's my boy.
- (LAUGHS) (GAGGING)
Well, that's just
grand now, isn't it?
- Guess who's coming to dinner?
- Fergus.
By the way, hope you don't
mind being called Lady Ding...
(WHINES)
(CROWD GASPS)
- I am Merida.
Firstborn descendant
of Clan Dun Broch.
And I'll be shooting
for my own hand.
- Oh!
- (CROWD MURMURING)
What are you doing?
Merida!
Curse this dress!
(SHOCKED GASPS)
(CROWD GASPS IN AWE)
Merida, stop this!
Don't you dare loose
another arrow.
(EXHALES)
Merida, I forbid it.
Michty me! I've just about
had enough of you, lass!
- You're the one that wants me to...
- You embarrassed them.
- You embarrassed me.
- I followed the rules.
You don't know what you've done!
- Just don't care how I...
- It'll be fire and sword if it's not set right.
- Just listen!
- I am the Queen!
You listen to me!
Ugh!
This is so unfair!
Ha! Unfair?
You're never there for me.
This whole marriage
is what you want.
Do you ever bother to
ask what I want? No.
You walk around telling me
what to do, what not to do,
trying to make me be like you.
Well, I'm not going
to be like you.
Oh, you're acting like a child.
And you're a beast.
- That's what you are!
- Oh, Merida.
- I'll never be like you.
- No, stop that!
- I'd rather die than be like you!
- (GASPS)
Merida, you are a Princess,
- and I expect you to act like one.
- Mum!
Oh!
(WEEPS)
ELINOR: Merida!
Merida!
Oh, dear.
Ah!
Oh, no.
What have I done?
Oh.
(SOBBING)
Oh! Oh! Oh!
(WHINNIES)
Whoa!
(SOBS)
Angus!
(WHINNIES AND SNORTS)
(ANGUS WHINNIES)
(WISP CALLS)
(WHISPERS) Come on, Angus.
(ANGUS NICKERS)
Angus!
(NICKERS)
(SIGHS)
(WISPS CALL)
(ANGUS NEIGHS)
(WISP CALLS)
(WHINNYING)
Why would the wisps
lead me here?
(BELL TINKLES)
Uh...
(WOOD GENTLY TAPPING)
Oh, look around.
You holler if you see
anything you like.
Everything is half off.
Uh...
- Who are you?
- Just a humble woodcarver.
Um...
I don't understand...
(GASPS)
- See anything you like?
- Uh...
Perhaps a touch of whimsy to
brighten any dank chamber?
But the will-o-the-wisps,
they...
Oh!
This is one of a kind!
I'll make you a deal
for this rare prize.
- Your broom!
- Oh! (SNAPS)
- It was sweeping by itself.
- That's ridiculous.
Wood cannot be imbued
with magical properties.
I should know. I'm a wit...
Whittler.
Of wood.
Oh, how about this conversation
starter? It's made of yew wood.
(GENTLE CLATTERING)
- Tough as Stone.
Oh, ah, ah, ah, ah!
That's stuffed.
(LAUGHS)
- Staring is rude.
- (GASPS) Ooh! The crow's talking!
That's not all I can do.
LA-IA LA-LA LA-LA
(SINGS HIGH NOTES)
(SNAPS)
(SQUAWKS)
- You're a witch!
- Woodcarver.
That's why the
wisps led me here.
- Woodcarver!
- You'll change my fate!
- You see, it's my mother.
I'm not a witch! Too many
unsatisfied customers.
If you're not going to buy
anything, get out. (SNAPS)
- No! The wisps led me here!
- I don't care!
- Get out! Shoo! Get! Be gone with you!
- I'll buy it all.
- What? What was that?
- Every carving.
Well...
(STAMMERING)
(LAUGHS) And how are you going
to pay for that, sweetie?
- With this.
- W...
Oh, my, that's lovely, that is.
That would set us up for months.
(CLATTERING)
MERIDA: - Ah, ah, ah.
(GASPS)
- Every carving and one spell.
- (SQUAWKS)
Are you sure you know
what you're doing?
I want a spell to change my mum.
That'll change my fate.
Hmm... Done!
(CHUCKLES)
- Where are you going?
(SNAPS)
(SQUAWKING)
- There.
What are you doing?
You never conjure
where you carve.
Very important.
WITCH: The last time I did
this was for a Prince.
(CLAPS)
(CAULDRON IGNITES)
Easy on the eyes.
Tight pants.
He demanded I give him
the strength of ten men.
And he gave me this for a spell.
A spell that would
change his fate.
And did he get
what he was after?
(LAUGHS)
Yes.
And made off with an especially
attractive mahogany cheese board.
Now, what do I need? Oh!
- Just a little bit of this.
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
Ah.
(CHUCKLES)
Hoo!
(SQUAWKING)
Tee-tee-tee-tee.
Whoosh.
That'll do.
(HUMS HAPPILY)
(SQUAWKS)
- Mi-Mi-Mi-Mi-Mi-Mi-Mi.
(BANG)
(PANICKED WHINNYING)
And now let's see.
What have we here?
(GASPS)
oh!
- Hey!
- (SQUAWKS)
Uh, a cake?
- You don't want it?
- Yes! I want it.
You're sure if I
give this to my mum,
it will change my fate?
Oh.
(CHUCKLES)
Trust me. It'll do
the trick, dearie.
Expect delivery of your
purchase within a fortnight.
Ooh! Ooh...
What was that thing
about the spell?
Did you say something about
the spell?
Mor'du, Mor'du, now the time has
come for all of us to slaughter you.
ALL: Hooray!
Mor'du, Mor'du...
(DISTANT SINGING)
ELINOR: - Merida.
- Mum!
Ooh, uh... I, uh...
- Oh, I've been worried sick.
- You... You were?
I didn't know where you'd
gone or when you'd come back.
I didn't know what to think.
Oh, look at your dress.
Oh. Angus threw me.
But I'm not hurt.
Well, you're home now,
so that's the end of it.
- Honestly?
- I've pacified the lords for now.
Your father's out there
"entertaining" them.
Come taste my blade,
you manky bear.
For gobbling up my leg.
I'll hunt you, then I'll skin
you, hang your noggin on a Peg...
(CHEERING)
Of course, we both know a
decision still has to be made.
- What's this?
- It's a peace offering.
I made it.
For you. Special.
You made this for me?
Mm.
Oh.
Interesting flavor.
- How do you feel?
- What... What is that?
- Different?
- Mm...
Tart and, um, (GULPS)
gamy.
Have you changed your mind at all
about the marriage and all that?
Oh, that's better.
Now, why don't we go
upstairs to the lords
and put this whole
kerfuffle to rest?
Hm?
(CELTIC FLUTE MUSIC PLAYING)
Ooh.
- Mother?
- I'm woozy suddenly.
My head's spinning like a top.
Ooh!
- Mum!
- Oh, suddenly I'm not so well.
Er... How... How do you feel
about the marriage now?
Merida! Oh, just
take me to my room.
FERGUS: Alright, that's fine.
That's just fine.
A little to the left. That's good. A
wee bit to the left. That's good.
It's good enough.
Now, clear out of there, boys. I
don't want you to spoil my shot.
- What? (CLEARS THROAT)
- My lady Queen.
We've been waiting patiently.
Milords, I am out of
sorts at the moment.
But you shall have your answer.
(BURPS)
- Oh!
- Eh?
Presently.
Now, if you'll...
(GROANS) excuse us.
(ALL CHEERING)
FERGUS: - Elinor, look!
It's Mor'du!
(LAUGHS)
Elinor?
Are you alright, dear?
Fine.
I'm fine.
Go about avenging your leg.
Oh...
Aye.
You heard her, lads.
I dream about the perfect
way to make this devil die.
(ALL CHEERING)
Just take all the time you need
to getting yourself right, Mum.
Then maybe in a bit you might have
something new to say on the marriage.
What was in that cake?
(SCOFFS)
Cake.
(COUGHS)
(GROANS)
Mum?
So I'll just tell them
the wedding's off, then?
(ELINOR GROANING)
Mum?
(DEEP GROANING)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(LOW GROWLING)
Bear!
(WHINES)
(FRIGHTENED GROWL)
(PANTING)
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMS)
(SURPRISED ROARING)
(GROANS)
- Oh!
Mum?
You're... You're a bear!
(GROANS)
Why a bear?
Oh, that scaffy witch
gave me a gammy spell.
It's not my fault.
I didn't ask her to
change you into a bear.
I just wanted her to change you.
(ROARS)
(ALL CHEERING)
- Shh. Did you hear that?
- (SNIFFS) (MUSIC STOPS)
Something's not right.
(ANXIOUS WHINING)
There's no point in having a go
at me. The witch is to blame.
Goggly old hag.
Eyes all over the place.
- Unbelievable.
- (GROANING)
- I'll get her to fix this.
- (SIGHS)
MERIDA: Why do I always get blamed
for everything? It's just not fair.
(SNIFFING)
Everybody, follow me.
And keep a sharp eye.
Here we go. Another hunt
through the castle.
But we haven't had dessert yet.
(SPEAKS IN THICK ACCENT)
(LAUGHS)
I have no idea.
MERIDA: Mum, you
can't go out there.
Mum! Wait!
What are you doing? Dad.
The Bear King?
If he so much as sees
you, you're dead.
LORD DINGWALL: Another one of your
entertainments to bore us to death!
LORD MACINTOSH: Oh, and what
exactly are we after...
Mum!
LORD MACINTOSH: My liege?
LORD MACGUFFIN: Best to humor
him. He is, after all, the King.
(SNIFFING)
He's like a hound with
that nose of his.
(LICKS AND SPITS)
Mum, wait.
- We have to...
- (GROANS)
(CLATTERING)
- Follow me.
Stop.
Stop!
(GASPS)
You're covered with fur.
You're not naked.
It's not like anyone's
gonna see you.
(SCREAMS)
Now you've done it.
Maudie!
(STUTTERING)
- Just calm down, lass. What is it?
- Spit it out, Maudie!
(SHOUTING)
A bear!
I knew it! (YELLS)
(ALL SHOUTING)
Would you just listen to me?
- We can't go this way. You'll be seen.
- (MEN YELLING)
Quick! This way!
Mum?
(WHIMPERS)
(ALL GASP)
(SOFTLY)
Mum? Oh!
(MEN SHOUTING)
- Oh!
- (ELINOR WHINING)
Hm?
A witch turned Mum into a bear.
It's not my fault.
We've got to get out of the
castle. I need your help.
Oh, alright.
You can have my desserts
for two... Three weeks.
Okay. Fine. A year.
- Did you hear that?
- Shh.
(ECHOING ROAR)
- There it goes!
- (MEN SHOUTING)
(MOCK ROARING CONTINUES) FERGUS:
- Come on, lads!
(YELLS)
(MOCK GROWLING)
There it goes!
(ALL YELLING)
(BIRD CALL)
- Come on, Mum.
- (WHINES)
(CLATTERING)
LORD MACGUFFIN: Think
we should lay a trap?
FERGUS: Try shutting yours!
(ALL ARGUING)
(MOCK GROWLING)
- There he is!
- (MEN SHOUTING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
FERGUS: I'm sure
it went this way.
LORD MACGUFFIN: You can
see my house from here.
It must have sprouted wings.
Was carried away
by a giant birdy.
- A dragon, perhaps.
- Bear in the castle!
Doesn't make sense.
It cannot open doors.
He's got big giant paws!
Let's just get inside.
(GRUNTING)
- It's locked.
- Dingwall was the last up.
LORD DINGWALL: I propped
it open with a stick.
(MEN GRUMBLING)
HANDMAID: What did you see,
Maudie? Just spit it out, Maudie.
Oh, for goodness' sakes,
Maudie, would you get a grip?
(CLATTERING)
(SCREAMS)
HANDMAID: Maudie, honey,
come here! It's alright!
Come on, Mum.
Quick.
(GROANS)
Shh.
(CRASHING AND CLATTERING)
(CLATTERING)
(GIGGLING)
(SNEEZES)
(WHINES)
They'll be fine.
Won't you, boys?
(SNIFFS)
Mum, we've got to hurry.
Now, I'll be back soon.
Go on and help yourself to
anything you want, as a reward.
(ALL GASP)
(STRAINING)
Oh!
(LORD DINGWALL SIGHS)
Right!
MERIDA: Where are these wisps?
Come out, wisps. Come on out.
Lead me to the witch's cottage.
I'm here!
Fine. Don't come out now
that my mum's watching.
(WHINES)
I was standing right here and
the wisp appeared right there.
Then a whole trail of them
led me off into the Forest.
Oh, does she think we're just going
to happen upon the witch's cottage?
(OWLS HOOTING)
(DISTANT HOWLING)
Oh, Mum, I know this place.
The witch's cottage...
It's this way!
Come on! Hurry!
I can't believe it.
I found it.
(WHINES)
No. She was here.
No, really, she was just here.
(WHINES)
Oh, wait.
- No.
- (BANGS DOOR SHUT)
No, no. No! No!
(METAL RATTLES)
- Oh.
(RUMBLING)
(DINGING)
(SHRIEKS)
(BUBBLING)
Welcome to the Crafty Carver,
home of bear-themed
carvings and novelties.
I am completely out of
stock at this time.
But if you'd like to enquire about
portraits or wedding cake toppers,
pour vial one into
the cauldron.
If you'd like the menu
in Gaelic, vial two.
If you're that red-haired
lass, vial three.
To speak with a
live homunculus...
Princess, I'm off to the
Wickerman Festival in Stornoway
and won't be back till spring.
There's one bit I forgot to
tell you about the spell.
By the second sunrise, your
spell will be permanent,
(GASPS) unless you
remember these words.
Fate be changed,
look inside,
mend the bond
torn by pride.
"Fate be changed... Mend the
bond." What does that mean?
One more time.
Fate be changed,
look inside,
mend the bond
torn by pride.
That's it. Ta-Ta.
Oh, and thank you for shopping
at the Crafty Carver.
No. No!
Where'd you go?
- Welcome to the Crafty Carver...
- What?
For all your...
(SPEECH OVERLAPPING)
Maybe there's a book of spells.
Look around. We'll need more vials.
I'm off to the Wickerman
Festival in Stornoway...
(SCRAMBLED MESSAGES)
Thank you for visiting.
Have a lovely day.
(BANG)
(WHINES SOFTLY)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(MERIDA STRAINING)
(ELINOR SIGHS)
We'll sort it out tomorrow.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(FAINT SINGING)
(ELINOR SINGING IN GAELIC)
(CRACK OF THUNDER)
(SCREAMS)
Oh.
(SPEAKS GAELIC)
My brave wee Lassie, I'm here.
I'll always be right here.
(CONTINUES SINGING IN GAELIC)
(BOTH SINGING)
(BIRDSONG)
Uh... Good morning.
(MOANS)
So...
(CHUCKLES)
- What's all this supposed to be?
- (SIGHS)
Oh.
(MOANS AND GRUNTS)
What?
(HUFFS AND SNORTS)
Sorry.
I don't speak bear.
(HUFFS)
Oh.
(MOANS)
Ah!
(GRUNTS IN SURPRISE)
(SLURPS)
- Find those by the creek, did you?
- Mm-hm.
They're nightshade berries.
Mmm.
They're poisonous.
(SPUTTERING)
Where did you get this water?
It has worms.
(GULPS)
(THUDDING)
(BIRDS SQUAWK)
(GIGGLES) Come on.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
Breakfast.
(GRUNTS APPROVINGLY)
Oh, wait. A Princess should not
have weapons, in your opinion.
Uh-huh... (GROANS)
There you go.
Go on.
(GROANS)
How do you know you don't
like it if you won't try it?
(WHINES)
(GROANS APPROVINGLY)
Mm.
(MUNCHING LOUDLY)
(GRUNTS)
(BURPS)
(GROANS)
(SLOW SONG PLAYING)
This love it is
a distant star.
Guiding us home
wherever we are.
This love it is a burning sun.
Shining light on the
things that we've done.
I tried to speak
to you every day.
But each word we spoke
the wind blew away.
How did we let
it come to this?
What we just tasted...
(MERIDA LAUGHS)
How will it feel when
this day is done?
And can we keep what
we've only begun?
(CRIES OUT)
Could these walls
come crumbling down?
I want to feel my
feet on the ground.
Can we carry this
love that we share.
Into the open air.
Hey!
Where are you going?
This love it is a burning sun.
Mum, come back.
(GROWLS)
- Uh...
- (SNARLS)
- Oh...
- (GROWLING)
Mum, is that you?
(ROARS)
Uh... Mum?
(WHINES)
You changed.
Like you were a...
I mean, like you were
a bear on the inside.
(WHINES AND SNORTS)
(WISP CALLS)
A wisp.
- Mum!
- (WISP SQUEAKS)
Stop it!
Mum, no!
(WISP CALLING)
Mum...
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
- Jings, crivens, help ma boab.
Mum, I know you're scared,
you're tired, you
don't understand,
but we've got to keep our heads.
Just calm down.
Listen.
(FAINT WHISPERING)
(FAINT WHISPERING CONTINUES)
(WISP CALLS)
They'll show us the way.
(WISPS CALLING)
(WISP CALLING)
MERIDA: Mum, look.
(WIND WHISTLES)
(ELINOR BEAR GROANS)
MERIDA: Why did the
wisps bring us here?
(ELINOR BEAR MOANS)
(ELINOR BEAR HUFFS AND SNORTS)
Whoever they were, they've been
gone for a long, long time.
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(WHINES)
- I'm fine, Mum.
Just fine.
It's, uh,
a throne room.
You suppose this could've
been the kingdom
in that story you
were telling me?
(MOANS)
- The one with the princes.
(GROANS)
One,
two,
three,
four.
The oldest.
(GROANS)
Split, like the tapestry.
(GROWLING)
(GASPS)
The spell.
It's happened before.
"Strength of ten men."
"Fate be changed."
"Changed his fate."
Oh, no.
The Prince became...
(GROWLING)
- Mor'du.
- (ROARS)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(ROARS)
(FABRIC TEARING)
(WHIMPERING)
(ROARS)
(SNARLS)
(MOANS)
(HUFFING AND PANTING)
(SCREAMS)
(CREAKING)
(MERIDA GROANS)
Mum, we need to get
back to the castle.
If we don't hurry, you'll
become like Mor'du.
A bear!
A real bear.
Forever!
(WHINES)
- "Mend the bond torn by pride."
The witch gave us the answer.
The tapestry.
(ELINOR GRUMBLES)
- Mum, do you have a better idea?
(GRUNTS)
(STRAINING)
That'll do.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(MEN SHOUTING)
No more talk. No
more traditions.
We settle this now!
You're the King.
You decide which one of our
sons your daughter will marry.
None of your sons are fit
to marry my daughter.
Then our alliance is over!
This means war!
(SHOUTING)
They're gonna murder each other.
You've got to stop them
before it's too late.
(WHINES)
I know, I know!
But how do we get you through
there and up to the tapestry
with the lot of them
boiling over like that?
(GRUNTS)
- Oh!
(SHOUTING)
(SHOUTING STOPS)
- What are you doing, lass?
- It's alright, Dad.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I, um...
I have...
Well, you see, I...
I have been in conference
with the Queen.
- Is that so?
- Aye, it is.
- Well, where is she, then?
- She, uh...
How do we know that
this isn't some trick?
- I'd never...
- This is highly irregular.
- What are you playing at?
- Where is the Queen?
LORD MACINTOSH: We will not stand for
any more of this jiggery-pokery.
- That's right. Let's see her.
- Shut it!
(SILENCE)
(LAUGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Well, I, uh...
Uh...
Once there was an
ancient kingdom.
What is this?
That kingdom fell into war
and chaos and ruin...
Och, we've all heard that tale.
Lost kingdom.
Aye, but it's true.
I know now how one selfish act
can turn the fate of a kingdom.
LORD MACGUFFIN: Bah,
it's just a legend.
Legends are lessons.
They ring with truths.
Our kingdom is young.
Our stories are not yet legend.
But in them, our
bond was struck.
Our clans were once enemies.
But when invaders
threatened us from the sea,
you joined together
to defend our lands.
You fought for each other.
You risked everything
for each other.
Lord MacGuffin, my
Dad saved your life,
stopping an arrow as you
ran to Dingwall's aid.
Aye, and I'll never forget it.
MERIDA: And, Lord Macintosh,
you saved my Dad when you
charged in on heavy horse
and held off the advance.
And we all know how Lord
Dingwall broke the enemy line.
With a mighty throw
of his spear!
I was aiming at you,
you big tumshie.
(ALL LAUGH)
The story of this kingdom
is a powerful one.
My Dad rallied your forces
and you made him your King.
It was an alliance forged
in bravery and friendship
and it lives to this day.
(ALL CHEERING)
But I've been selfish.
I tore a great rift
in our kingdom.
There's no one to blame but me.
And I know now that I
need to amend my mistake
and mend our bond.
And so, there is the
matter of my betrothal.
I've decided to do what's right
and...
break tradition.
(GASPING AND MUTTERING)
My mother...
the Queen, feels...
uh, in her heart
that I...
that we be free to...
write our own story...
follow our hearts
and find love in our own time.
- That's (SNIFFS) beautiful.
- (ALL SNIFFLING)
The Queen and I put the
decision to you, my lords.
Might our young people decide for
themselves who they will love?
Huh?
Well, since you've obviously
made up your minds about this,
I have one thing to say.
- This is...
- A grand idea!
Give us our own say
in choosing our fate.
- What?!
- Aye. Why shouldn't we choose?
But she's the Princess.
I did not pick her out.
It was your idea.
And you...
You feel the same way?
(SPEAKS UNINTELLIGIBLY)
- Good?
- (GRUNTS)
(GIGGLES)
Well, that settles it.
Let these lads try and win her
heart before they win her hand.
If they can.
I say, the wee Dingwall
has a fighting chance.
Fine, then. Seems
for once we agree.
- It was my idea in the first place.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
(SIGHS)
(ALL MUTTERING CONTENTEDLY)
Just like your mum.
You devil.
(GASPS)
Uh... Everyone to the cellar!
Let's crack open the King's
private reserve to celebrate!
(ALL CHEERING)
Oh.
(LAUGHS)
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Psst.
Bring the tiny glasses.
(TALKING AND LAUGHING)
(SIGHS)
(MERIDA GIGGLES)
(SINGS HAPPILY)
Oh, the tapestry!
Mend the bond...
Mend the bond.
Stitch it up.
This'll change you back.
We just need needle and thread.
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLS)
- Mum?
- (SNARLS)
Mum?
Not now.
No.
Please, not now.
(SNIFFING)
- Mum...
- (MEN LAUGHING)
(GROWLS)
- Shh.
(SINGING JOVIALLY)
Elinor, clear, you'll never guess who
just solved our little suitor problem.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(FERGUS BREATHING HEAVILY)
Elinor!
It can't be true! Elinor,
answer me, lass!
Elinor!
- Merida.
- (SNARLING)
- What?
- Dad, no! It's not what you think.
- Merida, get back!
- No!
(GROWLING)
(YELLING)
No, Dad! Don't hurt her!
- Get out of here!
- (SCREAMS)
Merida!
No!
(ROARS)
(YELLS)
- No!
(MOANS)
(GROANING)
- Mum.
- (WHINES)
(WHIMPERS)
It's alright. I'm alright. It's nothing.
It's just a little scratch. Mum!
- My liege!
- (ALL LAUGHING)
Fergus.
- Bear!
- (MOANING)
Dad!
Count your stars, lass. It
almost had you. Are you hurt?
It's your wife, Elinor.
(ELINOR WHINING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
Close the gate!
- You're talking nonsense!
- It's the truth!
There was a witch and she gave
me a spell. It's not Mor'du.
Mor'du or not, I'll
avenge your mother!
- I'll not risk losing you, too.
MERIDA: - No, Dad! Just listen to me.
Listen!
You can't!
- It's your wife Elinor!
- Maudie, keep this and don't let her out.
- What about the bear?
- Just stay put.
(BARKING)
Oh...
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
(FRUSTRATED GRUNT)
Come on, you sorry bunch
of galoots! Yeah!
Mum!
No.
No. Mum.
(WEEPING)
(GROANING)
Maudie. Maudie!
I need you!
Now!
(MERIDA GASPS)
Oh, no.
Maudie.
(GASPS)
Get the key.
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
Yeah!
Oh, Maudie!
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Needle and thread. Needle and
thread. Needle and thread.
(BARKING)
(HUFFING AND GASPING)
(GRUNTS AND MOANS)
There he goes!
Needle and thread. Needle and
thread. Needle and thread.
Ah, you beauty!
(GASPS)
(STRAINING)
(SHRIEKS)
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERING)
One, two... Huh?
(GASPS)
(THUD)
MAUDE: - Oh!
(CUB GROWLING)
(GASPS)
(WHINING)
(CRIES OUT)
Steady, Hamish.
FERGUS: There he goes.
(GRUNTS)
(DOGS BARKING)
(GROANS)
(MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
FERGUS: We've got his track!
(BARKING)
(MOANS)
- Back, back, back!
- Get him!
(GROANS)
Angus!
Easy, laddie.
(CRIES OUT)
Hubert, Harris, help Hamish.
(SHOUTING)
FERGUS: Watch your blade! You're
going to take somebody's arm off!
Aye, we've got you now!
FERGUS: - Give me a hand over here!
- Put your back into it, Dingwall!
LORD DINGWALL: I'm doing
all the pulling here.
LORD MACGUFFIN: Down
you go, you scoundrel.
(SQUEALS)
Done!
(WISP CALLS)
(HIGH-PITCHED CALLS)
Yeah!
(GROWLS)
(ELINOR BEAR GROANS)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(DOGS BARKING)
- Hah!
- (WHIMPERS)
(GROWLS)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
(MEN GASP IN SHOCK)
- Get back. That's my mother.
- Are you out of your mind, lass?
- Mum, are you hurt?
- (MOANS)
(GRUNTS)
(CRIES OUT)
(YELLS)
Merida!
(FERGUS GROANS)
- I'll not let you kill my mother.
(FERGUS SCREAMS)
- Boys!
(SCREAMING)
Boys?
(HEAVY THUD)
(GROWLS)
- Mor'du!
- Kill it!
(ALL YELLING)
(ROARS)
(MEN SCREAMING)
You Scoundrel!
(MEN GROANING)
(ROARS)
Come on! I'll take you
with my bare hands!
(FERGUS GROANS)
(FERGUS CRIES OUT)
(ROARS)
(WHIMPERING)
(SNARLS)
(SCREAMS)
(ROARS)
(ELINOR BEAR MOANS)
(BOTH ROARING)
Mum!
(GROANS)
(BOTH SNARLING)
(ELINOR CRIES OUT IN PAIN)
(STONE CRACKING)
(MERIDA SCREAMS)
(ROARING)
(CRACKING AND CRUMBLING)
(ROARS FEROCIOUSLY)
(SHRIEKS)
(GASPS)
The second sunrise.
(STRAINING)
(GRUNTS)
(WHIMPERS)
(WHINES)
No...
I don't understand.
I...
(SNIFFLING)
(WEEPING)
Oh, Mum, I'm sorry.
This is all my fault.
I did this to you.
To us.
(SNIFFING)
You've always been there for me.
You've never given up on me.
I just want you back.
(MERIDA SOBS)
I want you back, Mummy.
I love you.
(GASPS)
(LAUGHS)
Mum!
You're back!
(LAUGHING TEARFULLY)
You changed!
Oh, darling,
we both have.
Elinor!
Oh, oh, oh!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Elinor! Oh!
Ah!
Er... Urgh!
Oh, dear.
You're back.
She came back to us.
It's a great day for this
kingdom. The curse is broke.
Oh! Mum.
Ooh.
Erm... Dear?
- Eh?
- I'm naked.
Naked as a wee babby.
Don't just stare at me.
Do something!
What the... Avert
your eyes, lads!
Show some respect!
(ALL MUTTERING AWKWARDLY)
(PRINCES LAUGH)
Now that's what I call
a wee naked babby!
(LAUGHING)
Merida, Elinor, hurry up.
They're leaving.
- Mum!
- They're off! Come on!
We've got to wave them off!
Come along!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Though I may speak
some tongue of old.
Or even spit out
some holy word
(PRINCES SQUEALING)
I have no strength
with which to speak.
Oof!
(SCREAMS)
When you sit me down
and see I'm weak
(TALKING AND LAUGHING)
Goodbye! All the best!
Fair wind to your sails!
We will run and scream.
You will dance with me.
But how did this...
(GROANS)
(BARKING)
MERIDA: There are those who say fate
is something beyond our command,
that destiny is not our own.
But I know better.
Our fate lives within us.
You only have to be
brave enough to see it.
(WISP LAUGHS)
We will run and scream.
You will dance with me.
We'll fulfill our dreams
and we'll be free.
We will be who we are.
And then heal our scars.
Sadness will be far away.
So I had done wrong.
But you put me right.
My judgment burned in
the black of night.
When I give less than I take.
It is my fault,
my own mistake.
We will run and scream.
You will dance with me.
We'll fulfill our dreams
and we'll be free.
We will be who we are.
And then heal our scars.
Sadness will be far away
(SNORING)
(BIRD CAWS)
(SHEEP BLEATING)
Delivery.
Sign here, sign here.
(CAWS)
Come on, birdbrain.
I haven't got all day.
Subtitle By: Ivandrofly
& Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: July 17, 2018