Subtitle Created By : MUBDEE AL SADIK
(EXCLAIMING)
(ORCHESTRA MUSIC BLARING)
(GROANS)
(WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTING)
(MYSTICAL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(GROANS)
(COUNTRY ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN : Excuse me, sir,
is there a commode?
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS) Justin!
Quick, honey, take my picture.
I got the pyramid in my hand.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
Justin, you get
back here right now!
No, stop!
No, no! Stop him!
Go back! Don't climb!
(IMITATING
AIRPLANE WHOOSHING)
Wait, wait.
Hold on.
Easy, little boy.
Okay, stop, child!
Stop right there. No!
(GASPS)
No, no, no! Oh!
There he goes.
(GASPS)
Justin!
I've got him!
(GRUNTS)
(AIR ESCAPING)
Outrage in Egypt tonight
as it was discovered
that the Great
Pyramid of Giza
had been stolen
and replaced by
a giant inflatable replica.
There is panic
throughout the globe
as countries and citizens
try to protect
their beloved landmarks.
Law enforcement
still has no leads,
leaving everyone to wonder,
which of the world's villains
is responsible
for this heinous crime?
And where will
he strike next?
(CRYING)
I'm having a bad, bad day
It's about time
that I get my way
Steamrolling whatever I see
Freeze ray! Freeze ray!
Freeze ray! (LAUGHING)
I'm having a bad, bad day
If you take it personal,
that's okay
Watch, this is so fun to see
Despicable me
FRED : Morning, Gru!
(CHUCKLING)
How you doing?
Hello, Fred.
FYI, your dog
has been leaving
little bombs
all over my yard,
and I don't
appreciate it.
(LAUGHING) Sorry.
You know dogs.
They go wherever
they want to go.
Unless they're dead.
(LAUGHING)
I'm joking!
Although, it is true.
Anyway, have a good one.
Oh, okay.
Uh... Yeah.
Steamrolling whatever I see
Despicable me
(LOUD SNORING)
I'm having a bad, bad day
If you take it personal,
that's okay
Despicable me
(CONTINUES SNORING)
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
(GROANS)
You've got to be
pulling on my leg!
MARGO : Hello!
Cookies for sale.
Go away.
I'm not home.
Yes, you are.
I heard you.
(GASPS) No, you didn't. This
is a recording.
MARGO : No, it isn't.
Yes, it is.
Watch this.
Leave a message, beep.
(GRU SHOUTS IN PAIN)
Goodbye,
recorded message.
MARGO : Agnes,
come on.
Huh?
(SNAPS)
(SCREAMS) Kyle!
Bad dog! No!
No, no. Sit. My muffin.
Gru!
Ah, Dr. Nefario.
I know how you
must be feeling.
I, too, have encountered
great disappointment,
but in my eyes,
you will always be
one of the greats.
What? What happened?
It's all over the news!
Some fella just
stole a pyramid.
They're saying he makes
all other villains look
lame.
Assemble the minions!
(YELPS)
(COUNTING)
Minions, assemble!
Okay. Okay.
Throo...
(SCREAMS IN PAIN)
Hey!
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(ALL MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(ALL CHEERING)
Looking good, Kevin!
How is the family? Good?
All right.
That's my Billy boy!
What up, Larry?
Hello, everybody!
Yeah, all right!
Simmer down.
Simmer down!
Thank you, okay.
Now, I realize that
you guys probably heard
about this other villain
who stole the pyramids.
Apparently,
it's a big deal.
People are calling it
the crime of the century
and stuff like that.
But am I upset?
No, I am not!
A little,
but we have had
a pretty good year
ourselves,
and you guys are
all right in my book.
(EXCLAIMING)
No, no raises!
You're not going
to get any raises.
What did we do?
Well, we stole
the Times Square JumboTron!
Nice!
(ALL CHEERING)
Huh?
That's how I roll.
Yeah, you all like
watching football
on that, huh?
But that's not all.
We stole
the Statue of Liberty,
(ALL CHEERING)
The small one
from Las Vegas.
(EXCLAIMING DISAPPOINTEDLY)
And I won't even mention
the Eiffel Tower! Also Vegas.
Okay, I wasn't going to
tell you about this yet,
but I have been working
on something very big!
Something that will
blow this pyramid thing
out of the water!
And thanks to the efforts
of my good friend
Dr. Nefario...
Thank you!
GRU : Oh, there he is.
He's styling.
Now, we have located
a shrink ray
in a secret lab,
and once we take
this shrink ray,
we will have the capability
to pull off the true
crime of the century.
We are going to steal...
Wait, wait! I haven't
told you what it is yet.
(MINIONS EXCLAIMING)
Hey.
Dave, listen up, please.
Next, we are going to steal,
(SOFTLY) pause for effect,
the moon!
(MINIONS CHEERING)
And once the moon is mine,
the world will give me
whatever I want
to get it back!
And I will be
the greatest villain
of all time!
That's what
I'm talking about.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yes?
Hello, Gru? I've been
crunching some numbers,
and I really don't see
how we can afford this.
It can't be done.
I'm not a miracle worker.
Hey, chillax.
I'll just get another loan
from the bank. They love me!
(EXCLAIMS)
Edith, stop it!
What? I'm just walking.
(KEYS CLACKING)
ALL : Hi, Miss Hattie.
We're back.
Hello, girls!
Anybody come to adopt us
while we were out?
Mmm. Let me think.
No!
Edith! What did you
put on my desk?
A mud pie.
(SIGHS) You're never
gonna get adopted, Edith.
You know that, don't you?
Yeah, I know.
Good.
So, how did it go, girls?
Did we meet our quotas?
Sort of.
We sold 43 mini-mints,
30 choco-swirlies,
and 18 coco-nutties.
(SIGHS) Okay.
Well, you say that like
it's a great sale day.
Look at my face!
Do you still think
it's a great sale day?
Eighteen coco-nutties.
I think we can do a little
better than that, don't you?
Yeah.
We wouldn't want to spend
the weekend in the
Box of Shame, would we? No.
ALL : No, Miss Hattie.
Okay, good. Off you go.
Go clean something of mine.
Hi, Penny.
Hi, guys.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello, Mom. Sorry,
I meant to call, but...
I just wanted to
congratulate you
on stealing the pyramid.
(SIGHING)
That was you,
wasn't it?
Or was it a villain
who's actually successful?
(LAUGHING)
Just so you know, Mom,
I am about to do something
that's very, very big,
very important.
When you hear about it,
you're going to be
very proud.
(SCOFFS)
Good luck with that.
Okay, I'm out of here.
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Gru to see Mr. Perkins.
Yes, please have a seat.
NEIL ARMSTRONG : That's one
small step for man,
one giant leap for mankind.
Ma, someday I'm going
to go to the moon.
(SCOFFS) I'm afraid
you're too late, Son.
NASA isn't sending
the monkeys anymore.
Hey.
VECTOR :I'm applying
for a new villain loan.
Go by the name of Vector.
It's a mathematical term,
a quantity represented
by an arrow, with both
direction and magnitude.
Vector! That's me,
'cause I'm committing
crimes with both
direction and magnitude.
Oh, yeah!
Check out
my new weapon.
Piranha gun! Oh, yes!
Fires live piranhas.
Ever seen one before?
No, you haven't.
I invented it.
Do you want
a demonstration?
Oh! Shoot!
So difficult,
sometimes,
to get the piranha
back inside of my...
(EXCLAIMS)
RECEPTIONIST : Mr. Gru,
Mr. Perkins will see you now.
GRU : So, all I need
is money from the bank
to build a rocket.
And then,
the moon is ours.
Wow!
Well, very nice
presentation.
I'd like to see
this shrink ray.
Absolutely! Will do.
(SOFTLY)
Soon as I have it.
PERKINS :You don't have it?
And yet you have
the audacity to ask
the bank for money?
Apparently.
Do you have any idea
of the capital that this bank
has invested in you, Gru?
With far too few
of your sinister plots
actually turning a profit.
How can I put it?
Let's say this apple is you.
If we don't start
getting our money back...
Get the picture?
Look, Gru, the point is,
there are a lot of
new villains out there,
younger than you,
hungrier than you,
younger than you.
Like that young fellow
out there named Vector.
He just stole a pyramid!
GRU :I've got it.
I've got it.
Um... So, as far as getting
money for the rocket...
PERKINS :Get the shrink ray,
then we'll talk.
(YELPING)
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
(HIGH-PITCHED
TRUMPETING)
(RUMBLING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(SHOUTING DESPERATELY)
(LAUGHS) Suckers!
(GRUNTING)
Suckers!
(GROANS)
Ah-ha! We got it!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(METAL SIZZLING)
What?
Hey! Hey! What! Hey!
No, no, no!
You!
(LAUGHING)
Now, maybe you'll
think twice before you
freeze someone's head!
So long, Gru!
(LAUGHING)
Quick!
We can't let him get away!
(WHOOPING)
GRU : Up ahead!
Up ahead!
Fire! Fire, now!
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
(LAUGHING EXCITEDLY)
Oops, you missed me!
GRU : Come to papa!
Take that.
How adorable.
(CHUCKLES)
GRU : Got you
in our sights!
Like taking candy
from a...
What?
Ha! Hey, Gru!
VECTOR :Try this on for size!
That's weird.
What is going...
(SCREECHES)
This is claustrophobic!
No, no, no!
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
Too small!
This is too small for me!
(ALL SCREAM)
(GROANS)
I hate that guy!
...and please
watch over us,
and bless that we'll have
a good night's sleep.
And bless that
while we're sleeping,
no bugs will
crawl into our ears
and lay eggs
in our brains.
Great. Thanks for
that image, Edith.
And please bless
that someone will
adopt us soon,
and that the mommy
and daddy will be nice
and have a pet unicorn.
Amen.
AGNES : (SINGING)
Unicorns, I love them
Uni, uni, unicorns
I love them
Uni, unicorns,
I could pet one
If they were really real
(SIGHS)
And they are
So, I bought one
so I could pet it
Now it loves me
Now I love it
La, la, la, la, la
(ALARM BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(VIDEO GAME SOUNDS)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
Don't you...
(EXCLAIMS) What the...
(MOANING)
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, good luck,
little girls!
Whoa! Cool.
Hi! We're orphans
from Miss Hattie's
Home for Girls.
VECTOR : I don't care.
Beat it!
Come on!
We're selling cookies
so, you know, we can
have a better future.
VECTOR : Ooh! Wait, wait!
Do you have coco-nutties?
Yeah.
Light bulb.
Dr. Nefario!
Huh?
I'm going to need
a dozen tiny robots
disguised as cookies!
What?
Cookie robots!
Who is this?
Oh, forget it.
(CHUCKLING)
Well, it appears you have
cleared our background check,
Dr. Gru.
Oh! And I see you
have made a list
of some of your
personal achievements.
Thank you for that.
I love reading.
(MUMBLING GIBBERISH)
And I see
you have been given
the Medal of Honor
and a knighthood.
Me, me, me.
Kevin?
(BOTH SPEAK GIBBERISH)
You had your own
cooking show
and you can hold
your breath
for 30 seconds?
It's not that
impressive.
Uh... (BLOWS RASPBERRY)
(GROANS)
Idiot! (CHUCKLES)
ALL : Fight! Fight!
Fight! Fight!
What in the name of...
What?
(GRU CLEARS THROAT)
Well, here's the dealio.
Things have been
so lonely since my wife,
Debbie, passed on.
It's like
my heart is a tooth,
and it's got a cavity
that can only be filled
with children.
I'm sorry.
You are a beautiful woman.
Do you speak Spanish?
Do I look like
I speak Spanish?
You have a face
como un burro.
Oh!
Well, thank you!
(GIGGLES)
Anyway, can we proceed
with this adoption?
So, so excited!
Please tell Margo,
Edith and Agnes
to come to the lobby.
(ALL SCREAMING)
I bet the mom
is beautiful!
I bet the daddy's
eyes sparkle.
I bet their house is
made of Gummi Bears.
I'm just saying
it'd be nice.
Aw! My caterpillar never
turned into a butterfly.
That's a Cheeto.
Oh!
Well, Debbie was
a very lucky woman.
Who's Debbie?
Your wife.
(DOOR OPENS)
Oh! Hi, girls!
Girls, I want you
to meet Mr. Gru.
He's going to adopt you.
And he's a dentist!
Yeah! (CHUCKLING)
Um...
Hi. I'm Margo.
This is Edith.
And that's Agnes.
(SING-SONG)
I got your leg,
I got your leg!
GRU : Okay, that is enough,
little girl.
Let go of my leg.
Come on. You can do it.
Higher!
Higher! (LAUGHS)
Just release
your grip. Wow!
How do you remove them?
Is there a command?
Some nonstick spray?
Crowbar? (SIGHS)
Okay, girls, let's go.
(CRYING)
(CAR ALARMS SOUNDING)
VECTOR : (GRUNTS) Ah-ha!
Oh, yeah!
Pretty impressive!
What are you looking at?
Boo-ya!
You got shrunk,
tiny mouthwash!
Take that!
You done been shrunk!
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yello?
I got the shrink ray,
all right.
No, I'm not
playing with it.
Gru? (LAUGHING)
Don't make me laugh! No.
P.S., he is not
getting the moon,
and P. P.S., by the time
I'm done with him,
he's gonna be
begging for mercy.
Okay, bye.
Aw! Look at you,
a little tiny toilet
for a little tiny baby...
(SCREAMS)
Curse you, tiny toilet!
Okay, here we are.
Home sweet home.
So, this is, like,
your house?
Wait a sec...
You're the guy
who pretended he was
a recorded message!
No, that was
someone else.
Can I hold your hand?
Uh, no.
When we got adopted
by a bald guy,
I thought this'd be
more like Annie.
(GROWLING)
No, hey!
Kyle, these are not treats.
These are guests.
Girls,
this is Kyle, my
dog.
(SNARLS)
Ooh! Fluffy doggy!
(YELPING)
What kind of dog
is that?
He is a...
I don't know.
MARGO : Do you really think
that this is an appropriate
place for little kids?
'Cause it's not.
No! No!
Stay away from there!
It's fragile.
(GASPS)
Well, I suppose
the plan will
work with two.
EDITH : Hey!
It's dark in here.
It poked a hole
in my juice box.
As you can see,
I have provided everything
a child might need.
All right.
Uh... Okay.
As I was saying... Hey!
(CRASHING)
Somebody broke that.
GRU : Okay, okay.
Clearly, we need
to set some rules.
Rule number one.
You will not
touch anything.
Uh-huh.
What about the floor?
Yes, you may
touch the floor.
What about the air?
Yes, you may
touch the air!
What about this?
(EXCLAIMS)
Where did you get that?
Found it.
Okay. Rule number two.
You will not bother me
while I'm working.
Rule number three.
You will not cry or whine
or laugh or giggle
or sneeze
or burp or fart!
So, no, no, no
annoying sounds.
All right?
AGNES : Does this count
as annoying?
(POPPING)
Very!
(SIGHS)
I will see you
in six hours.
Okay, don't worry.
Everything's going
to be fine.
We're gonna be
really happy here.
Right? Agnes?
Mmm?
(EXCLAIMS)
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(CLICKING)
(UPBEAT POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Uh, question.
What are these?
A dozen boogie robots!
Boogie! (LAUGHING)
Look at this. Watch me!
(MUSIC STOPS)
GRU : Cookie robots.
I said cookie robots.
Why are you so old?
Okay. I'm on it.
Hello?
TV!
(KYLE GROWLING)
(WHIMPERS)
MARGO : What is that?
Wow!
Look at that!
That is cool!
Come on!
AGNES :I don't think
he's a dentist.
(WHIMPERS)
We've been working
on this for a while.
It's a anti-gravity serum.
(EXCLAIMING)
(SCREAMING)
I meant to close that.
He'll be all right,
I'm sure.
Do the effects wear off?
Uh, so far,
no. No, they don't.
And here, of course,
is the new weapon
you ordered.
(FARTING)
No, no.
I said "dart gun,"
not... Okay.
Oh, yes.
'Cause I was wondering
under what circumstances
would we use this?
But, anyway.
What I really wanted
to show you was this.
Now those are
cookie robots!
AGNES : (SINGING)
La, la, la, la
I love unicorns
What are you doing here?
I told you to stay
in the kitchen!
We got bored.
What is this place?
Can I drink this?
Do you want to explode?
(EXCLAIMS)
Gru!
Get back
in the kitchen!
Will you play with us?
No.
Why?
Because I'm busy.
(SCOFFS)
Doing what?
Um...
Okay, okay,
you got me.
The dentist thing
is more of a hobby.
In real life,
I am a spy.
And it is top secret,
and you may not tell anybody,
because if you do...
What does this do?
(GASPS)
Hey!
Oops.
My unicorn!
You have to fix it.
GRU : Fix it?
Look, it has been
disintegrated.
By definition,
it cannot be fixed.
(GASPS)
(INHALES)
That's freaking me out.
What is she doing?
MARGO : She's gonna hold her breath
until she gets a new one.
It is just a toy.
Now stop it!
(GRUNTING)
Okay, okay!
I'll fix it!
Tim! Mark! Phil!
This is very important.
You have to get
the little girl
a new unicorn toy.
Eh?
(BOTH SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, hey, hey! A toy!
Go, and hurry!
What are those?
They are my cousins.
Jerry! Stuart!
Watch them, and keep them
away from me, please.
ALL : Wow!
(ALL EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY)
(STUTTERING)
(GROANS)
Ooh!
(SCREAMING)
Oh!
Hmm...
(FEEDBACK)
(SHUDDERING)
(SINGING GIBBERISH)
(ALL SINGING)
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
(CRASHING)
It was your cousin's idea.
What?
Okay, bedtime.
GIRLS : Aw!
Aw!
Not you two!
(CHEERING)
Okey-dokey. Beddie-bye.
All tucked in. Sweet dreams.
Just so you know,
you're never
gonna be my dad.
Hmm. I think
I can live with that.
Are these beds
made out of bombs?
Yes, but they are
very old and highly
unlikely to blow up.
But try not to
toss and turn.
Cool.
AGNES : Will you read us
a bedtime story?
No.
But we can't go to sleep
without a bedtime story.
Well, then it's going
to be a long night
for you, isn't it?
So, good night,
sleep tight, and don't
let the bed bugs bite.
Because there are literally
thousands of them.
(WHISPERING SCARILY)
And there's probably
something in your closet.
He's just kidding, Agnes.
(DOOR OPENS)
(GASPS)
(SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
Para tu...Papoy
It's beautiful.
(HUMMING)
(SIGHS)
GRU : Girls, let's go.
Time to deliver the cookies!
Mmm. Okay. But first,
we're going to dance class.
Actually,
we're going to have to skip
the dance class today.
Actually, we can't
(IMITATING GRU)
Skip the dance
class today.
We have a big recital
coming up.
We're doing an excerpt
from Swan Lake.
Yeah, Swan Lake!
That's fantastic.
Wonderful.
But we're going to
deliver cookies!
Come on!
No.
No?
We're not going
to deliver cookies
until we do dance class.
GRU : Really?
Well, I am not driving you
to dance class.
So if you want to go,
you are going to have
to walk yourselves.
What are you doing?
Walking to dance class.
Ya? Okay, fine.
You just keep walking,
because I'm really not
driving you!
MARGO : Okay.
(SIGHS IN FRUSTRATION)
You're going to suffer
the wrath of Gru!
Seriously,
I'm going to
count to three!
And you had better
be in this car!
Here we go! One! Two!
INSTRUCTOR : Three,
four and five.
And lift, and stretch.
And one, and two...
Here you go.
What is it?
Your ticket
to the dance recital.
You are coming, right?
Of course,
of course.
I have pins and needles
that I'm sitting on.
Pinky promise?
(SIGHS)
Oh, yes.
My pinky promises.
All right.
Our first customer
is a man named Vector.
But he's a V.
You know, we're supposed
to start with the A's.
Then we go to the B's.
Then we...
Yes, yes!
I went to kindergarten.
I know how
the alphabet works!
(SIGHS)
I was just thinking
that it might be nice to
deliver Mr. Vector's first.
That is all.
Almost over.
It's almost over.
Girls,
welcome back to the fortress
of Vector-tude! (CHUCKLING)
Do you have
my cookies for me?
Four boxes of mini-mints,
two toffee totes,
two caramel clumpies
and fifteen boxes
of coco-nutties.
Exactly.
I'd like to see somebody else
order that many cookies.
Not likely.
Name one person
who ordered more
cookies than me.
That'll be $52.
Right.
Seven, eight, nine...
Tic Tacs! Where was I?
AGNES : Why are you
wearing pajamas?
(SCOFFING)
These aren't pajamas!
This is a warm-up suit.
(BLEEPING)
What are you
warming up for?
Stuff.
What sort of stuff?
VECTOR : Super-cool stuff
you wouldn't understand.
Like sleeping?
They are not pajamas!
(ALL GRUNTING)
Here you go, 52 big ones.
(GASPS)
(EXCLAIMS IN FRUSTRATION)
(SCREAMING)
Bye!
(DEVICE POWERING DOWN)
(GASPS)
(EXHALES)
(CRACKING)
(SHUDDERING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING ON TV)
(MAN CHATTERING ON TV)
(SOFTLY)
Come on!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS) What the...
Quiet down, fish!
Down, boy!
Ah-ha! (LAUGHING)
We did it!
Come on, girls, let's go!
But what about
the other people
who ordered cookies?
Life is full of
disappointments
for some people.
(CHUCKLING)
(SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMS)
Don't do that!
Super Silly Fun Land!
Can we go? Please?
No.
But we've never been.
And it's the funnest
place on earth!
Don't care.
Please?
We'll never ask
for anything else,
ever again!
Pretty please?
Please?
Come on!
Light bulb.
Goodbye, have fun.
Sorry, dude.
They can't ride
without an adult.
What?
(SIGHS IN FRUSTRATION)
(GIRLS WHOOPING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(RETCHING)
AGNES : (SQUEALS)
Oh, my gosh!
Look at that
fluffy unicorn!
He's so fluffy,
I'm gonna die!
You've gotta let
us play for it!
No, no, no.
Come on!
GRU : How much for
the fluffy unicorn?
(LAUGHING)
Well, it is not
for sale.
But all you gotta do
to win it
is knock down that
little spaceship there.
It's easy!
Yay!
Again!
Wait!
Come on.
One more time!
Just one more.
I accidentally
closed my eyes.
I hit it!
That was cool.
Aw!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What was that?
She hit that.
I saw that with
my own eyes.
Hey, buddy,
let me explain
something to you.
You see that
little tin spaceship?
You see how
it's not knocked over?
Do you know what
that means, professor?
It means you don't
get the unicorn!
Oh! Uh-oh!
Somebody's got
a frowny face.
Boo! Better luck
next time!
Okay, my turn.
GRU : Knocked over!
AGNES : It's so fluffy!
Yeah!
That was awesome!
EDITH : You blew up
the whole thing!
Let's go.
Let's try
another game!
(ALL LAUGHING)
NEFARIO : Gru, do you mind
if I have a quick word?
GRU : Okay, girls, go play.
I got the shrink ray!
Cotton candy!
We have 12 days
until the moon is
in optimum position.
We can't afford
any distractions!
Get me Perkins.
Ah-ha!
Sorry to bother you,
Mr. Perkins,
but I figured that you
would want to see this!
What?
Well done, Gru.
(SQUEAKING)
Rather impressive.
GRU : Now, the rest
of the plan is simple.
I fly to the moon.
I shrink the moon.
I grab the moon.
I sit on the toilet.
What?
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
Sorry. Sorry!
Could you excuse me
for just one second?
I told you not
to touch my things.
I told you, I told you.
I've told you
a thousand times.
MARGO : Hey, can we
order pizza?
Pizza?
You just had lunch.
Not now, for dinner.
Dinner?
Just...
Fine, fine, fine, whatever.
Just get back in there!
Oh! Can we get
stuffed crust?
(EXCLAIMING)
Stuffed crust!
I'll stuff you
all in the crust!
(GIGGLING)
AGNES : You're funny!
Just don't come out
of that room again!
All right.
Sorry about that.
Where were we?
PERKINS : You were sitting
on the toilet.
No, no, no!
No, I'm sorry. It was
a little attempt at humor.
I know how much
you like to laugh
inside.
Now, I was saying...
(DOOR CREAKING OPEN)
You don't seem
terribly focused, Gru.
Believe me,
I am completely focused.
Hello! Whoa!
What?
That guy is huge!
Are we on TV?
What are those? Children?
What are you doing?
I told you to stay
out of here!
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
No, no, no!
Freeze ray!
Mr. Gru?
(GRU EXCLAIMING)
Okay.
As I was saying...
No need to continue.
I've seen quite enough.
But my plan...
Is a great plan.
I love everything
about your plan,
except for one thing.
You.
Look, Mom,
I drew a picture of me
landing on the moon!
(EXCLAIMS INDIFFERENTLY)
Look, Mom, I made
a prototype of the rocket
out of macaroni!
(EXCLAIMS INDIFFERENTLY)
Look, Mom,
I made a real rocket
based on the
macaroni prototype!
(GASPS)
(EXCLAIMS INDIFFERENTLY)
I don't understand.
Let's face reality, Gru.
You've been at this
for far too long with
far too little success.
We're gonna put our faith,
our money, into a...
Well, a younger villain.
But I...
It's over. Goodbye, Gru.
(INDISTINCT MUTTERING)
(SIGHS)
Now, I know there have been
some rumors going around
that the bank is
no longer funding us.
Well, I am here to put
those rumors to rest.
They are true.
(ALL GASP)
Uh-oh!
In terms of money,
we have no money.
So how will we
get to the moon?
The answer is clear.
We won't.
(SOBBING)
We are doomed.
Now would probably
be a good time
to look for other
employment options.
(ALL GASP)
I know.
I have fired up my resume
as I suggest that
all of you do, as well.
What is it?
Can't you see that
I am in the middle
of a pep talk?
(MINION EXCLAIMING)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Yes!
Yes, we will build
our own rocket
using this and whatever
else we can find!
Grab everything!
Hit the junkyards!
Take apart the cars!
Who needs the bank?
Let's go. Let's go!
(UPBEAT POP SONG PLAYING)
(SCREAMING)
(BLEEPING)
(GASPS) Mom!
What are you doing here?
And here he is
in the bathtub.
Oh! Look at his
little buns.
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
Mom.
Not cool.
And here,
he's all dressed up
in his Sunday best.
He looks like a girl!
(CHUCKLES)
Yes, he does.
An ugly girl!
(WHOOPING)
(SNARLING)
You're funny!
Yes! Mine's shaped
like a dead guy!
(BLEEPING)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
RECEPTIONIST :
Mr. Perkins,
your son is here.
Send him in.
Hey, Dad.
You wanted to see me?
Yes, I did, Victor.
VECTOR : I am not Victor anymore.
Victor was my nerd name.
Now I am Vector!
Sit down!
PERKINS : Do you know where
the shrink ray is?
Duh! Back at my place.
Oh, is that right?
Back at your place?
Oh, that's cool.
I guess Gru
must just have one
that looks exactly like it!
VECTOR : Oh! What the...
Those girls sold me cookies!
Do you have any idea
how lucrative this
moon heist could be?
I give you
the opportunity
of a lifetime,
and you just blow it!
No, I didn't.
Oh, really?
You just wait
until Gru sees
my latest weapon.
Squid-launcher! Oh, yeah!
MAN : (SCREAMS)
There's a squid on my face!
(CHUCKLES)
Don't worry.
The moon is as good as ours.
(CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
Come on now,
it's bedtime.
Did you brush your teeth?
Let me smell. Let me smell.
(EXHALES)
You did not!
Put on your PJs.
Hold still. Okay,
seriously! Seriously!
This is beddie-bye time,
right now.
I'm not kidding around.
I mean it!
But we're not tired!
Well, I am tired.
Will you read us
a bedtime story?
No.
Pretty please!
The physical appearance
of the "please"
makes no difference.
It is still no,
so go to sleep.
But we can't.
We're all hyper!
And without a bedtime story,
we'll just keep getting up
and bugging you.
All night long.
(SIGHS) Fine.
All right, all right.
Sleepy Kittens.
Sleepy Kittens?
What are these?
AGNES : Puppets.
You use them when
you tell the story.
Okay, let's get
this over with.
"Three little kittens
loved to play,
"they had fun
in the sun all day.
"Then their mother
came out and said,
"'Time for kittens
to go to bed."'
Wow! This is garbage.
You actually like this?
Keep reading!
(GROANS)
Come on!
All right,
all right, all right.
"Three little kittens
started to bawl,
"'Mommy, we're not
tired at all.'
"Their mother smiled
and said with a purr,
"'Fine, but at least
you should brush your fur."'
Now you brush the fur.
This is literature?
A 2-year-old could
have written this.
All right.
"Three little kittens
with fur all brushed
"said, 'We can't sleep,
we feel too rushed! '
"Their mother replied,
with a voice like silk,
"'Fine, but at least
you should drink your milk."'
Now make them
drink the milk.
I don't like this book.
This is going on forever.
"Three little kittens,
with milk all gone,
"rubbed their eyes
and started to yawn.
(GIRLS YAWNING)
(YAWNS)
"'We can't sleep,
we can't even try.'
"Then their mother
sang a lullaby.
"'Good night kittens,
close your eyes.
"Sleep in peace
until you rise.
"'Though while you sleep,
we are apart,
"'your mommy loves you
with all her heart."'
The end.
Okay, good night.
Wait!
What?
What about
good night kisses?
No, no. There will be
no kissing or hugging
or kissing.
He is not gonna
kiss us good night, Agnes.
I like him. He's nice.
But scary.
Like Santa!
Only 48 hours
till the launch,
and all systems are go.
Uh... About that,
I was thinking that
maybe we could move
the date of the heist.
Please tell me this
is not as a result
of the girls'
dance recital, is it?
No, no, no!
The recital?
Don't...
That's stupid!
I just think
it's kind of weird
to do it on a Saturday.
I was thinking,
maybe a heist is
a Tuesday thing, right?
Gru, you and I have been
working on this for years.
It's everything
we've dreamed of.
Your chance to make history,
become the man
who stole the moon!
But these girls are becoming
a major distraction!
They need to go.
If you don't do
something about it,
then I will.
I understand.
Good.
(CHUCKLING)
Butt.
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Butt.
GRU : All right.
Now, when we put
our cups together,
we will make
the "clink" sound
with our mouths.
Ready? Edith?
Clink.
There we go.
And now we drink.
And Agnes?
Clink.
Very good!
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
Excuse me, girls.
(ALL GROAN)
Come on!
Don't worry, I'll be back.
Keep clinking.
AGNES : Clink, clink.
JERRY : Clink, clink.
Oh!
Miss Hattie,
what are you doing here?
I'm here for the girls.
I received a call
that you wanted
to return them.
And also, I did purchase
a Spanish dictionary.
I didn't like
what you said.
But...
(CLEARING THROAT)
Oh!
I will get the girls ready.
Don't let her
take us, Mr. Gru!
Tell her you wanna keep us.
All right, girls.
Come on, let's go.
Goodbye, Mr. Gru.
Thanks for everything.
I did it
for your own good.
Come on,
let's go get that moon.
Right.
(MINIONS CRYING)
(SCREAMING)
(ALL MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(HUMMING)
(SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
What is this for?
The recital?
I am the greatest
criminal mind
of the century.
I don't go
to little girls'
dance recitals!
Opening launch bay doors.
Commencing launch sequence.
And we are good to go
in T minus 10 seconds.
Ten, nine, eight, seven,
six...
(RUMBLING)
Oh, yeah!
Nice work, Doctor.
All systems go.
Boo-ya!
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
My flight suit.
Oh, yeah!
Once again, the mighty...
(SCREAMING)
(ALL CHEERING)
ALL : Whoa!
(HOWLING)
Ah-ha!
I've got it!
I've got the moon!
I can make it!
Wait a minute!
Kevin!
Come on, come on!
He's still not here.
Why would he come?
He gave us up.
But he pinky promised!
Girls, girls, places!
No, we can't start yet!
We're still expecting
someone.
Can we just wait
a few more minutes?
All right. But just
a few more minutes.
He's not coming, guys.
Gru! Gru, can you hear me?
Quick, we have to
warn him, and fast!
(ENGINE REVVING)
(SCREAMING)
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay, okay.
There's the library.
That's Third Street.
The dance studio...
There! There!
There it is!
(CHILDREN CHEERING)
(GASPS)
Sorry, buddy.
Show's over.
Over?
Vector, open up!
First give me the moon.
Then we'll talk.
(CHUCKLES)
AGNES : Mr. Gru!
Zip it, Happy Meal.
Now, the girls.
Actually,
I think I'll hold on to them
a little while longer.
No!
Oh, yeah! Unpredictable!
Listen close,
you little punk.
When I get in there,
you are in for
a world of pain!
(EXCLAIMING SARCASTICALLY)
I'm really scared!
He is gonna
kick your butt.
(SCOFFS)
What?
He punched my shark!
Ha! There he is!
Hang on, Gru.
Oh, no!
(SCREAMS)
Ow?
Vector has the girls. Go!
What happened to the ship?
It's big again!
Not as big as the moon
is going to be!
What?
The larger the mass
of an object,
the quicker the effects
of the shrink ray wear off!
I call it
the Nefario Principle.
I just came up
with it now, actually.
Oh, no!
(GASPS)
Did you see that?
Vector! Help!
Vector!
Over here!
Hey!
What are you girls
doing back there?
The moon!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
Ouch!
Watch out!
(SCREAMING)
GRU : Get as close in
as you can.
You got it.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Mr. Gru, up here!
Mr. Gru!
Okay, girls! Girls!
You're going to
have to jump.
EDITH : Jump?
Are you insane?
Don't worry,
I will catch you.
You gave us back!
I know, I know.
And it is the worst
mistake I ever made.
But you have to
jump now.
It'll be okay.
Okay, girls.
Jump now!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Margo,
I will catch you.
And I will never
let you go again.
Not so fast!
No!
Let me go!
(LAUGHING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Margo!
Whoa!
I'm coming, Margo.
Hang on!
(LAUGHING)
(GROANS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
I got you.
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
No!
(EXPLOSION)
Oh, poop.
This time, good triumphs,
and the moon
has been returned
to its rightful
place in the sky.
But once again,
law enforcement is baffled,
leaving everyone to wonder,
who is this mysterious hero?
And what will he do next?
Okay, girls.
Time for bed.
Come on!
We want a story.
Three sleepy kittens!
Oh, no! Sorry.
That book was accidentally
destroyed maliciously.
(SCOFFS)
Tonight we are going
to read a new book.
This one is called
One Big Unicorn by...
Who wrote this?
Oh! Me! I wrote it.
Look, it's a puppet book!
Here, watch this.
That's the horn!
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
This is gonna be
the best book ever!
Not to pat myself
on the back,
but, yes,
it probably will be.
Here we go.
"One big unicorn,
strong and free
"thought he was happy
as he could be.
"Then three little
kittens came around
"and turned his
whole life upside down."
Hey, that one
looks like me!
No, what are you
talking about?
These are kittens!
Any relation
to persons living or dead
is completely coincidental.
"They made him laugh. (LAUGHS)
"They made him cry. (MOANS)
"He never should
have said goodbye.
"And now he knows
he could never part
"from those
three little kittens
"that changed his heart.
"The end."
Okay, all right.
Good night.
I love you.
I love you, too.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
No, no!
(ALL EXCLAIMING
DISAPPOINTEDLY)
All right.
Didn't I get you already?
(LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
They're very good!
I'm so proud of you, Son.
You've turned out to be
a great parent!
Just like me.
Maybe even better.
(SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
(GROANS)
(UPBEAT POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL CHEERING)
No, I'm fine.
Go ahead.
No, no, no!
(MOANS)
(EXCLAIMING)
(SIGHS)
Hey, Carl! Hey.
Hmm?
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
No, no, no.
BOTH : Me, me, me.
John?
No, no. Me, me, me.
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
Oh, poop. (SCREAMS)
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
(BOTH SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(LAUGHING)
(GROANING) Oh, no!
Stop! Stop!
(CARL GROANING)
(SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
Huh? (SCREAMING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(IMITATES QUACKING)
(IMITATES SQUAWKING)
Hello, I am Gru.
Back to work,
back to work! Back to...
(CHUCKLING)