Subtitledtrailers.com
So,
how was he like?
Mr. Grey will see you now.
He was really very smart,
very intense.
To what do you owe your success?
I've always been good at people.
I have a natural instinct
for what makes a person tick.
Anastasia.
Christian.
You do realize
that he hasn't stopped looking at you?
Have you met someone?
Are you free?
I like to see your face.
Gives me some clue
what you might be thinking.
- So you're a control freak?
- I exercise control in all things.
It must be really boring.
You're not playing fair.
You should just steer clear of me.
I'm not the man for you.
Why won't you let me in?
I had a rough start in life.
That's all you need to know.
My tastes are very singular.
You wouldn't understand.
Enlighten me, then.
- Why are you trying to change me?
- I'm not.
It's you that's changing me.
I don't know if I can be with him
the way he needs me to.
Say I did stay, what would happen?