It's happening!
Wait up, guys!
The baby's coming! The baby's coming!
- Watch it!
- I'm having a baby!
- Code Blue! Code Blue!
- Or pink if it's a girl!
Having a baby! Having a baby!
I'm coming, Ellie!
We got it!
Ellie! Ellie!
Ellie, where are you? Where am I?
Manny?
I told you it was just a kick.
Right! Right! Wow.
You really gave Daddy a scare!
Daddy got silly!
Daddy fall down cliff
and go boom, boom, boom.
Silly Daddy. Yeah.
Sorry, folks! False alarm!
It was just a kick!
- You know who I'd like to kick?
- That's the third false alarm this week.
All right, show's over, break it up!
Break it up!
I see someone else
who has a bun in the oven!
I'm not pregnant!
That's too bad.
You'd make a wonderful mother!
Manny, I know you're excited. I am, too.
But you're getting a little carried away.
Okay, okay!
Boy, you're starting to sound like Diego.
Wait a second. Where is Diego?
My hooves are burning, baby!
They are burning!
Look at this. I got to tip-toe!
I got to tip-toe!
Eat my dust, dingo!
Now? Can I look now?
Easy. Don't freak out the baby.
The baby's fine. It's the freaked-out daddy
I'm worried about.
No peeking!
Voila! Playground for Junior!
Wow.
It's amazing!
Manny.
I made it myself. Our family.
Hey, why aren't I up there?
- You can be on ours.
- You'd fit right in!
Thanks!
Of course, it's still a work in progress.
A few rough edges here and there.
I don't believe it.
You're trying to baby-proof nature.
Baby-proof nature? Get out of here.
That's ridiculous.
Manny, this is the world our baby's
gonna grow up in.
You can't change that.
Of course I can.
I'm the biggest thing on Earth!
Okay, Big Daddy. I can't wait to see
how you handle the teen years.
Come on, Sid!
I don't want you touching anything.
This place is for kids. Are you a kid?
Don't answer that.
Diego! There you are.
You missed the big surprise!
Right. Right. I'll check it out later.
Okay. See you.
You know, I think there's
something bothering Diego.
No, I'm sure everything's fine.
You should talk to him.
Guys don't talk to guys
about guy problems.
We just punch each other
on the shoulders.
That's stupid.
To a girl. To a guy,
that's like 6 months of therapy.
Okay, okay, I'm going.
Hey.
Why'd you do that?
I don't know.
So, listen,
Ellie thinks there's
something bothering you. I told her...
Actually, I've been thinking that soon
it might be time for me to head out.
Okay. So I'll just tell her that you're fine.
It was nothing.
Look, who are we kidding, Manny?
I'm losing my edge.
I'm not really built
for chaperoning play dates.
What are you talking about?
Having a family, that's huge,
and I'm happy for you,
but that's your adventure, not mine.
- So you don't want to be around my kid?
- No, no, no. That's...
- You're taking this the wrong way.
- No, go.
Go find some adventure,
Mr. Adventure Guy.
Don't let my boring domestic life
hit you in the butt on the way out.
Isn't Ellie supposed to be the one
with the hormonal imbalance?
Manny, wait! No one has to leave.
- So?
- That's why guys don't talk to guys.
- Why? What happened?
- Diego's leaving.
This should be the best time of our lives.
We're having a baby!
No, Sid. They're having a baby.
Yeah, but we're a herd, a family.
Look, things have changed.
Manny has other priorities now.
Face it, Sid. We had a great run,
but now it's time to move on.
So it's just the two of us.
No, Sid, it's not the two of us.
Crash and Eddie are coming with us?
Just Crash?
Just Eddie?
Bye, Sid.
Okay, calm down. Calm down.
I'm good at making friends.
I'll make my own herd. That's what I'll do.
Patty cake, patty cake, baker's man...
Well, at least you still got your looks.
Great.
Anybody here? Anyone?
Hello?
Poor guys. I know what it's like
to feel abandoned.
Don't worry. You're not alone anymore.
There you go.
Okay, okay. I'm okay, I'm okay.
Stay here. Stay here. And you,
you take care of your brother, now.
Momma's gonna be right back.
Momma's coming, baby!
Gotcha!
What did I just tell you kids?
Thank you, thank you, thank you!
Bad egg. Rotten egg!
A heart attack you almost gave me!
I'm sorry, darling.
It's just that I love you so much.
Now, I want you to meet
your Uncle Manny and your Aunt Ellie.
- Hi!
- Hello.
I'd like to present Egbert, Shelly and Yoko.
Sid, whatever you're doing, it's a bad idea.
My kids will hear you!
They're not your kids, Sid.
Take them back.
- You're not meant to be a parent.
- Why not?
First sign, stealing someone else's eggs.
Second sign, one of them
almost became an omelet.
Sid, someone's probably
worried sick looking for them.
No. They were underground, in ice.
If it wasn't for me, they'd be Eggsicles.
Sid, I know what you're going through.
You're gonna have a family, too, someday.
You're gonna meet a nice girl
with low standards,
no real options or sense of smell...
What Manny means to say is...
No, I get it. I'll take them back.
You have your family,
and I'm better off alone, by myself.
A fortress of solitude.
In the ice
forever!
A lone, lonely loner!
- That's a lot of aloneness.
- Precisely!
- Sid, wait!
- No! No, it's okay. He'll bounce back.
It's one of the advantages of being Sid.
Why should I take you back? I love kids!
I'm responsible, loving, nurturing.
What do you think?
I knew you would agree.
Don't cry! Don't cry.
I'll find a dry place.
Okay.
Here, let me just dry you off.
I don't know.
Being a parent's a lot of work.
Maybe I'm not ready.
Momma!
Momma! Momma! Momma!
I'm a mommy.
Where's Mommy?
Here I am.
There you go. Nice squeaky faces.
I got it! I got it!
No, no! Stop! Not me! No, stop, stop!
Hey! No biting!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
No. It's okay, it's okay. Don't cry.
Why are you still crying? Are you hungry?
Maybe you're hungry.
I know just the thing.
Hush, hush
You mean, vicious animal
I'm your baby and this is my milk
I thought you were a female!
I'm sorry, but you can't go in.
Manny says it's just for kids.
Wait a minute. You are kids!
Just don't break anything!
The sloth says the playground's open!
No, wait! Not for everyone!
No, no, no! Don't touch that!
- What are they?
- Who cares? They're fun!
- Play nice!
- Mommy, he's not sharing!
- Aren't you going to do something?
- Why? My kid had it first.
- Did not!
- Did, too!
- Liar, liar, fur on fire!
What is the matter with you?
I'm a single mother with 3 kids.
I could use a little compassion!
Slow down! No!
No, don't...
Stop, stop, stop!
- Ronald!
- That's a shame.
Stop! Stop, stop, stop!
No! No!
- Hold on, Little Johnny!
- I'm trying!
You know, experts say you should
let the kids eat whatever they want!
Do you think my ankles look fat?
Ankles? What ankles?
Ronald! Where did you come from?
Oh, no.
Okay, come on. Spit him out.
If you don't spit out Little Johnny,
we're leaving the playground this instant!
1,
2...
Don't make me say "3"!
There we are. A picture of health.
- That's not Little Johnny.
- Well, better than nothing.
Madison!
- Come on, barf him up.
- Sid?
Hey. Hey, Manny.
Little Johnny!
Wait! No, no...
I'm really sorry.
- This place is totaled.
- And we didn't wreck it.
We're losing our touch, bro.
Well, the important thing is
that no one got hurt.
Except for that guy.
And those 3.
And her.
I told you to take them back,
and you kept them!
Now look what they've done!
Okay, granted,
we do have some discipline issues.
Eating kids is not a discipline issue!
- But he spit them out.
- Well, that's super.
Let's give him a gold star! Kid of the week!
They don't belong here, Sid.
Whatever they are,
wherever you found them, take them back.
Manny! I'm not getting rid of my kids!
Earthquake!
It's okay, it's okay. Momma's here.
Do earthquakes shriek?
I thought those guys were extinct!
Well, then that is one angry fossil. Sid!
Come on, come on! Inside, inside, inside!
Nobody move a muscle.
No, no, no, don't cry. Don't cry.
We are poor, little lambs
who have lost our way
Sid! Give them to her! She's their mother!
How do I know she's their mother?
What do you want, a birth certificate?
She's a dinosaur!
Well, I put in the blood, sweat and tears
to raise them!
For a day! Give them back, you lunatic!
Look, these are my kids,
and you're gonna have to go through me
to get them!
- Sid!
Help!
Run!
Don't you have anything better to do?
Sid?
Sid must be down there.
- Well, he's dead.
- Real shame.
He will be missed.
Oh, no, no, no. Not so fast.
Okay, Ellie, this is where I draw the line.
You, Crash and Eddie, back to the village.
Yeah, that's gonna happen.
Ellie, you saw that thing!
This is gonna be dangerous!
Talk to the trunk.
Great. After we save Sid,
I'm gonna kill him.
- Ladies first.
- Age before beauty.
- No pain, no gain.
- What pain?
- Sid!
Oh, no. No, no. Not good, not good.
Ellie! Ellie, wait up!
Okay, look, if you feel anything,
even if it's nothing, you gotta tell me,
and then we're out of here.
Okay.
We need a code word!
Yeah. Something that says,
"The baby's coming."
How about, "The baby's coming!"
How's that?
Too long. We need something
short and punchy, like...
"Peaches!"
- Peaches?
- I love peaches.
They're sweet and round and fuzzy,
just like you.
You think I'm round?
Round is good. Round is foxy.
Stay close.
Are you guys
having the same dream I am?
We've been living above an entire world,
and we didn't even know it.
Run for it! Hurry!
- Diego, what are you doing here?
- Sightseeing!
- I'm looking for Sid, same as you.
- Well! Aren't you noble?
This is not the time, guys!
We need all the help we can get!
Never mind.
Here, boy! Here! Come on!
Good boy! Come on!
- Climb on.
- Are you nuts?
We're not getting on that thing!
It's either this dinosaur or that one!
Pregnant lady wants to live!
Yabba-dabba-doo!
Don't ever yabba-dabba do that again!
- I feel so puny.
- How do you think I feel?
Take cover!
Dude, you're awesome!
You're like the brother I never had!
Me, too!
Can we keep him?
- Buck!
- What?
The name's Buck. Short for Buckminster.
Long for "Buh."
A little dull.
What are you doing here?
- Our friend was taken by a dinosaur.
- Well!
He's dead. Welcome to my world.
Now go home.
- Off you pop.
- Not without Sid.
Ellie, wait.
Maybe the deranged hermit has a point.
Manny, we came this far,
we're gonna find him.
I got tracks.
Let's go.
If you go in there, you'll find your friend.
In the afterlife.
How do you know,
O Great and Wisely Weasely One?
Yeah.
Mommy dinosaur carrying her three babies
and some floppy green thing.
Yeah, we're friends
with the floppy green thing.
You got all that from the tracks?
No. Not really.
I saw them come through here earlier.
She's headed for Lava Falls.
That's where they care for the newborns.
To get there, you've got to go
through the Jungle of Misery,
across the Chasm of Death
to the Plates of Woe.
Okay! Good luck with the slow
descent into madness.
We're gonna go now.
What, you think this is
some sort of tropical getaway?
You can't protect your mate, mate.
What are you gonna do
with those flimsy tusks
when you run into the beast?
I call him
Rudy.
Oh, good. Good. I was worried
it was something intimidating,
like "Sheldon" or "Tim."
Wait. You mean there's something
bigger than Mommy Dinosaur?
- Aye.
- Eye?
Aye, aye! He's the one that gave me this!
- He gave you that patch?
- For free? That's so cool.
Yeah. Maybe he'll give us one, too.
Welcome to my world.
Abandon all hope, he who enters there!
All right! We get it!
Doom and despair, yada, yada, yada.
Sounds like a jungle of misery to me.
- Hold on.
- Why? What's wrong? Peaches?
What? No! It's just I got a funny feeling.
You're hungry! Low blood sugar.
There's some fruit!
- No! Manny!
- I wouldn't do that if I were you.
This isn't exactly your playground.
Like I'm really gonna be afraid
of a pretty flower.
Bet you didn't see that coming.
- Manny!
- For the record, I blame you for this.
Stop eating our friends, plant!
That's it! I'm tearing it up from the roots!
- Do that, and it will clamp shut forever.
- What?
All right, preggers,
don't get your trunk in a knot.
I'll have them out of there
before they're digested.
Digested?
They'll be nothing but bones
in 3 minutes.
Well, maybe 5 for the fat one.
I'm not fat!
I feel tingly.
Don't say that
when you're pressed up against me.
Not that kind of tingly.
I can feel it, too.
Help! Someone help us!
Hurry!
It's time to get...
Buck Wild.
Who's fat now?
No!
Tourists.
Barfed on by a plant.
- Awesome!
Say something.
Thanks for saving us.
Buck, will you help us find
the floppy green thing?
- That's not necessary!
- Yes, it is.
All right, I'll help you.
But I got rules.
Rule number 1, always listen to Buck.
Rule number 2,
stay in the middle of the trail.
Rule number 3,
he who has gas
travels at the back of the pack.
Come on, then. Chop, chop!
We should all have our heads examined.
That's rule number 4!
Now let's go find your friend!
It's okay. It's okay. Don't worry.
We're gonna be fine.
Please stop swaying. A little nauseous.
See? She's putting us down...
No! I'm too young to be eaten!
Nice mucus.
And I don't say that to everyone.
Listen, families get complicated!
Maybe we can work something out.
I can take them Sunday to Tuesday!
Wednesday to Friday? Weekends?
It's okay! Momma's okay.
If you eat me, it will send a bad message.
Score one for the sloth!
And the score's all tied up.
Do you think the beast will find Sid?
Or more importantly, us?
Rudy? Are you joking?
He's relentless.
He knows all, sees all, eats all.
So that's a yes.
Hey! Get off my lawn! Go on! Shoo!
I knew that guy when he was a caterpillar.
You know, before he came out.
So you're just living down here
by your wits,
all on your own, no responsibilities.
Not a one. It's incredible.
No dependents, no limits.
It's the greatest life
a single guy could have.
Hear that? This is my kind of place.
Hello?
Yeah... No, look, I can't talk right now.
Yeah. No, I'm trying to recover
a dead sloth.
Yeah.
No, they're following me!
I know! They think I'm crazy.
No... Okay, we're going
into the Chasm of Death.
I'm... I'm going to lose you.
Yeah, I love you, too.
All right, good-bye. Good-bye! Good-bye.
Okay! Follow me.
That's you in 3 weeks.
So, why do they call it
the Chasm of Death?
Well, we tried "Big Smelly Crack,"
but that just made everybody giggle.
Well, now what?
Madame.
She is not doing that!
Rule number 1.
Come on, mammoth!
You're supposed to have a good memory.
Always listen to Buck.
Now, eyes forward, back straight, and...
Oh, yes, breathe in the toxic fumes
and you'll probably die.
Toxic fumes?
- Just another day in paradise.
- Wait!
Geronimo!
- Ellie, you okay?
- You have to try this!
All right, now pile on, everyone!
Couldn't be easier!
Don't panic!
Just some technical difficulties.
Keep holding it in, boys!
I can't take it anymore!
He breathed it!
And now I'm breathing it!
Hey! We're not dead!
You sound ridiculous!
Me? You should hear you!
All right, all right. And a one, and a two...
Christmas, Christmas time is here
Stop! Are you crazy?
It's not poison.
That is so disturbing!
Stop laughing! All of you!
"Stop laughing, all of you!"
"What's rule number 1?"
They're just laughing.
What's so bad about that?
They died laughing!
Stop laughing!
You know what's funny, though?
We're trying to save Sid,
and now we're all gonna die!
- And I don't even like Sid!
- Who does? He's an idiot!
Thanks for getting me into this mess.
It's the most fun I've had in years!
Thank you for deserting the herd!
That was totally super!
Stop that!
Don't you see? We're all gonna die!
We gotta do everything, huh?
Sometimes I wet my bed!
That's all right!
Sometimes I wet your bed!
I'm not sure how much of that
you could hear.
- I heard all of it.
- Right. Yeah.
- You wet my bed?
- That was gas talk, dude.
Well, better get moving.
Aren't we forgetting something?
Here, Rudy, Rudy, Rudy!
I'm so lonely.
Okay. Here you go, guys.
What? You're not gonna
eat your vegetables?
How are you gonna become
big, strong dinosaurs?
No. I've raised them vegetarian.
It's a healthier lifestyle.
I mean, look at me.
I have the pelt of a much younger sloth.
Excuse me!
I'm trying to have a conversation here.
No, no, no. That's not for us, kids.
It's way too feathery and fleshy and...
And alive!
No! No, no, we do not eat
live animals, period!
Now, go! Fly!
Be free,
little flightless bird.
My bad.
Hey, where are you going?
This is how you resolve conflict?
No wonder you're single!
Come on. Am I talking to myself here?
I say, "They're vegetarian."
You say, "Grrr."
I say, "Can we talk about talk this?"
I don't call that communication.
See? That's your answer to everything.
What are you afraid of?
You're the biggest thing on Earth!
Aren't you?
Hey!
They'll never survive.
It's dangerous by day.
But it's even worse at night.
Plus, their guide is a lunatic.
What? You mean, Buck? He's wacko!
I am not!
Totally bonkers.
And his feet smell.
Shut up! You shut up.
Oh, you little...
Gotcha!
He's strangling his own foot.
- Shouldn't we get moving?
- What?
And give Rudy a midnight snack?
Not likely!
The skull's right.
Take a load off, mammals.
We'll camp here.
Now, who's hungry?
I am!
You don't need the calories!
There I was, my back against the wall,
no way out,
perched on the razor's edge of oblivion,
staring into the eye
of the Great White Beast.
- Were you killed?
- Sadly, yes.
But I lived!
Never had I felt so alive
than when I was so close to death.
Just before Rudy could suck me
down his gullet,
I grabbed hold of that gross,
pink, fleshy thing
that dangles at the back of the throat.
I hung onto that sucker, and I swung
back and forth,
and back and forth, and back and forth,
and back and forth, and back
and forth, and back and forth,
until finally, I let go
and I shot right out of his mouth!
I may have lost an eye that day,
but I got this!
- Rudy's tooth!
- Dang!
It's like the old saying, "An eye for a tooth,
"a nose for a chin, a butt for a..."
Well, it's an old saying,
but it's not a very good one.
- You are Super Weasel!
- Ultra-Weasel!
Diesel Weasel!
What? He is.
Now let me tell you about the time
I used a sharpened clam shell
to turn a T-Rex into a T-Rachel.
- Yes, master.
That's enough fairy tales for one night.
Come on, Ellie, you should rest now.
Life of the party.
All right, you guys get some shut-eye.
I'll keep watch.
Don't worry, Buck. We got this.
Night time is possum time.
Yeah! We own the night, baby.
Good night, Rudy.
Wait, wait. What about me?
Sleep well, kids!
We have a busy day tomorrow.
Foraging, hunting,
missing my friends,
who probably aren't missing me.
You're a real softie, you know that?
Manny?
Crash? Eddie?
What's going on? Are you okay?
I'm sorry. I just wanted to keep you safe,
and now you're in the most dangerous
place in the world.
Hey. This isn't your fault.
It's bigger than both of us.
We have to get Sid.
Yeah, but if I had been
a better friend to him,
- we wouldn't be here.
- Better friend?
Are you plucking my whiskers?
You risked your life, your mate
and your baby to save your buddy.
Not the best husband or father,
but a darn good friend!
Hey!
Everybody, stop!
I smell something.
It smells like a buzzard's butt fell off
and then got sprayed on
by a bunch of skunks.
That's Sid.
Mammals, we have ourselves
a crime scene.
A tuft of fur. Half-eaten carcass!
Hunk of... No!
Broccoli.
Here's what I think happened.
Dinosaur attacks Sid,
Sid fights back with piece of broccoli,
leaving dinosaur
a vegetable.
Are you nuts? Sid's not violent.
Or coordinated.
Yeah. And where's the dinosaur?
All right. All right, good point.
Theory two.
Sid's eating broccoli,
dinosaur eats Sid,
dinosaur steps on broccoli,
leaving broccoli
a vegetable.
Buck, when exactly
did you lose your mind?
3 months ago.
I woke up one morning
married to a pineapple.
An ugly pineapple.
But I loved her.
Buck, I think you missed
a little clue over here.
Well, your friend might be alive,
but not for long.
Rudy's closing in.
- Whoa!
You got it. The Plates of Woe.
Or whatever's left of them.
Single file, everyone! Head for Lava Falls.
- What's that sound?
- It's the wind. It's speaking to us.
- What's it saying?
- I don't know.
I don't speak Wind.
- Ellie!
- I'm fine. Don't worry about me.
I'm just taking my...
Ellie!
- Manny!
- Get to the ledge!
Ellie!
Ellie! Where are you?
It's okay! I'm up here!
Hang on, Ellie! We'll be right there!
Wait! Sloth down!
Wait. Wait. Time out!
Hold up. You guys are getting fast!
It's not so bad down here.
Nice weather, friendly neighbors.
Hi, neighbor.
- Rudy.
- Rudy?
- Never heard that kind of dino before.
- That's Sid!
- We'll have to move fast.
- Manny! Pineapples!
- Pineapples?
- She gets cravings.
Pomegranates? Grapefruits! Nectarines?
She's ordering a fruit cocktail.
Come on, think!
Peaches!
Peaches?
Peaches! The baby! What, now?
This? Not good.
The baby's coming!
Did you guys hear that?
'Cause sometimes
I imagine it in my head, but...
Can you try to hold it in?
Can somebody slap him for me?
Done and done.
Just sit tight. We're coming!
There's only one thing to do.
Possums, you're with me.
Manny, you take care of Ellie
until we get back.
What? No, you can't leave now!
She's off the trail!
What about rule number 2?
Rule number 5 says
you can ignore rule number 2
if there's a female involved,
or possibly a cute dog.
You know I just make up these rules
as I go along.
- Yeah, but, but she's... You have to...
- Manny, it's all right.
I got your back.
Now you're talking! Come on, lads.
- Take care of our sister, mister.
- No pressure.
What does that mean, "I got your back"?
I mean, I'd rather they covered the front.
That's where all the good stuff is, isn't it?
We gotta move.
Okay. All right. It's okay.
Daddy's... Daddy's coming.
I gotta say, sweetheart,
you really got timing.
Go away! Go away!
Stranger danger! Stranger danger!
Don't worry. It's just lava.
Deadly boiling lava!
- Boys, are you ready for adventure?
- Yes, sir!
- For danger?
For death?
Can you repeat the question?
Jump!
That's right! Come on!
Have you ever flown one of these before?
No! First time, actually.
- There she is!
- Ellie!
Manny!
I need to get to her!
Listen. I'll protect Ellie.
- You stop those guys.
- But...
Manny, if they reach her, it'll be too late.
You have to trust me.
All right. Let's do it.
My paws are burning, baby!
They're burning!
I got to tip-toe.
Tippy-toe. Tippy-toe.
Excuse me, twinkle toes!
Giving birth here.
Right. Sorry. You okay?
Am I okay?
Do you know anything about childbirth?
No, not really, but Manny's coming.
Diego, I'm scared. Can I hold your paw?
Yeah, of course.
Just go with the pain.
- It's just a contraction.
- No!
Look! He's right there!
- Roger!
- No! Sid!
I know! Roger!
How about we get Sid first
and then go back for Roger?
Never mind!
Buck?
No, no, Buck! Buck, wait! Sid's that way!
Tell that to them!
Bring it on, you chicken-headed freaks!
Don't worry about a thing.
You're doing fine.
It's going great.
Excuse me.
Just keep breathing!
Diego!
Just breathe! That's the important thing.
Grab that ammo!
Bogey, 3 o'clock! Fire!
This is awesome!
Light it up!
- Yeah!
- Hasta la vista, birdy!
Let's get our sloth!
We're hit! We're hit! Mayday! Mayday!
We're losing altitude! Hold these!
Tastes like fish.
Okay. That's just weird.
- I love you, bro!
- I know!
Snap out of it! Come on!
Pull!
This is the end of Sid the Sloth!
- Help!
- No, Sid! It's me!
- And me!
I don't want to panic anybody,
but who's flying this thing?
Oops!
No, no, wait! Wait! My kids!
I never even got to say good-bye.
You can do it! Push! Push!
I can't do it!
Just one more big push!
You have no idea what I'm going through!
Okay, forget I said that.
Let's do this together.
I liked you guys better
when you were extinct.
Getting dizzy.
Manny! Come on, buddy.
I think we're getting close.
She's perfect.
I think we should call her Ellie.
Little Ellie.
I got a better name. Peaches.
Peaches?
Why not? She's sweet and round
and covered with fuzz.
Peaches.
I love it.
I saw that, tough guy.
No, no. That last dino
caught my eye with a claw, and...
All right, so I'm not made of stone.
Incoming!
It's Sid!
- It's a boy!
- That's its tail.
It's a girl!
Hi, sweetheart. Hello, hello!
It's Uncle Sid. Yes, it is.
You're so beautiful. She is!
She looks just like her mother.
Thank goodness.
No offense, Manny! No offense.
You're beautiful on the inside!
It's good to have you back, Sid.
Never thought I would say this,
but I missed you, buddy.
Now I wish my kids were here.
You could have been friends.
Ellie!
I promised myself I wouldn't cry.
I didn't.
I forgot what it was like
to be part of a family.
What about you?
Ever thought about having kids?
All right, mammals, let's get you home.
This is it, mammals.
Right where you started.
This was fun!
We could make it a regular thing.
I don't know about that.
Right! Right. Yes, because of
all the mortal peril, of course.
Well, the Buck stops here.
We couldn't have done it without you.
Well, obviously. But good times, just the...
We're not alone, are we?
Hello, Rudy.
Run!
Over here, you colossal fossil!
Looking for something?
Why don't you come and get it!
To the cave! Go!
- Stay with the baby.
- We'll be fine. Go.
Wuss.
Pop goes the weasel!
Come on! Move!
- Diego! Catch!
- Got it!
Through the hole, over the valley.
One more loop...
Come on, lads! Heave!
Better luck next time, snowflake.
This isn't going to hold him long! Let's go!
Hold up, guys!
Way to go, Momzilla!
Come here, kids.
Well, let me tell you something.
You're where you belong now.
And I'm sure you're going to grow up
to be giant, horrifying dinosaurs
just like your mother.
And Momma,
take good care of our kids.
- You were a good parent, Sid.
- Thanks.
- Can I baby-sit for you?
- Not a chance.
- Come on. I work cheap!
- All right, I'll think about it.
Yes!
Never happen.
He's gone. What am I supposed to do now?
That's easy. Come with us.
You mean up there?
I never thought of going back.
I've been down here so long,
it feels like up to me.
I'm not sure I can fit in up there anymore.
So? Look at us.
We look like a normal herd to you?
So long, big guy.
That's our cue! Come on, Peaches.
He's alive!
Buck?
I... I got to...
Yeah.
Besides, this world should
really stay down here.
Take care of them, Tiger.
"Always listen to Buck."
We're almost out!
Rudy!
Is everybody okay?
Where's Buck?
Don't worry. He's where he wants to be.
- Is he gonna be okay?
- Are you kidding?
Nothing could kill that weasel.
It's Rudy I'm worried about.
I know this "baby makes 3" thing
isn't for you,
but whatever you decide to do...
I'm not leaving, buddy.
Life of adventure? It's right here.
But I got a whole speech here.
I've been working on it.
How can I show you
that I'm strong and sensitive?
Noble yet caring?
Thanks.
They grow so fast, huh?
Yeah. I mean, look at my kids.
Seems like they were born one day
and then gone the next.
They were, Sid.
Yeah. That was a lot of work.
That's right, sweetheart.
Welcome to the lce Age.