Subtitledtrailers.com
So, how was the first day of school?
It was find, I guess...
I don't know.
Do you ever look at someone and wonder
what is going on inside their head?
- Did you guys pick up on that?
- Sure did. Something's wrong.
We're gonna find out what's happening,
but we'll need support.
Signal the husband.
He's passed over to Reed,
comes across center ice...
Huh-oh.
She's looking at us.
- What did she say?
- Oh, sorry sir, no one was listening.
Is it garbage night?
We left the toilet sit up?!
What?! What is it, woman?! What?!
Signal him again...
So, Riley, how was school?
- Seriously?!
- He's gotta be kidding me!
For this, we gave up
that Brazilian helicopter pilot?!
School was great, all right?
What was that?! I though you said
we were gonna "act casual"?!
Riley! Is everything okay?
She just rolled her eyes at us!
All right, make a show of force, I don't
want to have to put the foot down.
No! Not the foot...
Riley, I do not like
this new attitude.
- Oh, I show you attitude, old man!
- No! No, no, no! Breath!
What is your problem?!
Just leave me alone!
Reporting high levels of sass!
Take it to DEFCON 2!
DEFCON 2!
I don't know where this
disrespectful attitude came from.
You want a piece of this, pops?!
Yeah, well...
Prepare the foot!
Keys to safety position!
Ready to launch on your command, sir!
Just shut up!
Fire!
That's it!
Go to your room!
The foot is down.
Good job, gentleman.
That could have been a disaster.
Well, that was a disaster.
Come!
Fly with me, Caccinia.