Relax.
Anything in here would be dead by now.
There she is,
the Indominus Rex.
Specimen collected. Sent to the surface.
Roger that.
Air One, clear for takeoff. Begin tracking.
- Copy that.
- Go, go!
Tracking on.
Land One, the asset is secure.
We got what we came for.
We're coming back for you. Close the doors.
Marine One, I gotta close the gates.
Get out of there.
Understood. We're heading out.
Marine One, I need to close the gates.
Confirm position.
Can you hear me? Are you out?
Marine One?
- Guys?
- What is that?
Marine One, I'm closing the gates.
Seriously, guys,
I'm kind of exposed out here.
Marine One. Confirm you're out, Marine One.
Confirm position. Can you hear me,
Marine One, where are you?
Come on!
I can't reach them!
- Come on!
- What?
Behind you!
What is going on? I can't hear you!
No, no! Wait! Don't go! No!
Throw him the ladder.
Come on! Bring it down!
Slow down! No, no, no!
Don't go!
Oh, God!
No, wait! No, no! No!
Oh, God, no!
God, no!
We're gonna stall! Cut it now!
- Give him a chance!
- We're gonna die here!
Come on! Come on!
No, no, no!
Oh, God!
I said cut it!
Don't do it! It's horrible!
I don't wanna die!
Yeah!
- Yeah!
- Come on!
DNA sample secured.
Tell the boss we're coming back home.
3 years after the fall of Jurassic World,
the debate over Isla Nublar rages on.
The island's long-dormant volcano,
reclassified as active,
has shown considerable unrest
in recent months.
Geologists now predict
an extinction-level event
will kill off the last
living dinosaurs on the planet.
Since the disaster that shocked
the world in 2015,
the Masrani Corporation has paid out
more than 800 million in damages
to settle class-action lawsuits
brought by survivors.
Activist groups have mobilized
around the globe
in what has become the flashpoint
animal rights issue of our time.
With an eruption expected at any moment,
the US Senate has convened
a special committee
to answer a grave, moral question.
Do dinosaurs deserve the same protections
given to other endangered species
or should they be left to die?
I think that we should allow
our magnificent and glorious dinosaurs
to be taken out by the volcano.
Murderer.
Silence, please.
As deeply sad as that would be,
we altered the course of natural history.
This is a correction.
Are you suggesting the Almighty
is taking matters in his own hands?
Senator, with all due respect,
God's not part of the equation, no.
What I mean is that, in the last century,
we amassed landmark technological power
and we've consistently proven ourselves
incapable of handling that power.
80 years ago, who could've predicted
nuclear proliferation?
But then there it was.
And now we've got genetic power,
so how long is it gonna take
for that to spread around the globe
and what's gonna be done with it?
It ain't gonna stop
with the de-extinction of the dinosaurs.
I'm not sure I know
what you're talking about.
I'm talking about man-made,
cataclysmic change.
What kind of change?
Change is like death.
You don't know what it looks like
until you're standing at the gates.
Yes, absolutely!
We would love to have
a photo op with the senator.
As a matter of fact, I do have
the dinosaurs' best interests in mind.
I'm a paleo-veterinarian.
- Is that a real thing?
- That's a real thing.
No, I haven't seen one with my own eyes.
You know, not everyone can afford
to spend their life savings...
Claire!
Oh, uh...
- Hello. Hello, um...
- Congresswoman Delgado.
Congresswoman Delgado.
I'm Claire. I'm the lead organizer here.
Of course, but if I could just get
a moment of your time?
Great. Thank you. Um...
So, our mission here
at the Dinosaur Protection Group
is to secure federal funding
for a safe, natural...
That was, like, 40 seconds.
You're getting better.
You gotta stop letting your mom shop for you.
You don't need to insult me
every time someone pisses you off.
Dude, I'm a doctor, not a telemarketer.
What is your job again?
You plug in cords, right?
It's actually more important than it sounds.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Go on.
- Do you have kids?
- Two girls.
Okay. So, your kids, an entire generation,
has grown up in a world
where dinosaurs are living and breathing.
But soon, they're gonna
have to watch them go extinct.
Or not.
If people like you make a difference.
Set up a meeting
with my office after the hearing.
Great.
Yes!
We now go live to the Capitol...
- Claire, it's on.
- Turn it up.
...the US government
will take preventative action
to protect the dinosaurs on Isla Nublar.
After thorough deliberations,
the committee has resolved
not to recommend any legislative action
regarding the de-extinct
creatures on Isla Nublar.
This is an act of God.
And while, of course, we feel
great sympathy for these animals,
we cannot condone government involvement
on what amounts to a privately-owned venture.
They're all gonna die and no one cares.
We do.
Give me one second. Let's get back to work.
Okay, everyone, come on.
Hello?
- May I speak with Ms. Dearing?
- Yes, this is Claire Dearing.
Good morning, I'm calling
from Mr. Benjamin Lockwood's estate.
Would you mind holding for a second?
Yes, of course I'll hold.
Ms. Dearing, you're early.
Would you like to step in?
Thank you.
I will inform Mr. Mills that you've arrived.
John Alfred Hammond,
the father of Jurassic Park.
But of course you knew that.
Hello, Claire. I'm Eli Mills.
I work for Ben Lockwood.
We actually met once, 7, 8 years ago,
- and you don't remember.
- Of course I remember.
- Haven't you run his foundation since...
- Since college, yeah.
- You remember?
- Yes.
Wow. Cool. He wanted someone young
and idealistic to spend his fortune
and I used to be both.
Follow me.
Let me give you a bit of history.
This is where it all began.
Before the island,
Sorna, Jurassic Park, all of it.
Hammond and Lockwood built
a custom lab in the sub-basement,
extracted the first DNA from
amber right beneath our feet.
Oh, my goodness.
What they did here was a miracle.
I still believe that.
So do I, Claire.
So do I.
And I still believe it matters
what happens to those animals.
There is something Mr. Lockwood
would very much like you to do, Claire.
You can call it a favor for an old friend.
We have a piece of land.
A sanctuary protected by natural
barriers, fully self-sustaining.
A new home where the dinosaurs
will be secure and free.
You're gonna get them out?
You're gonna save them?
No, Ms. Dearing.
I'm going to save us.
We could both use a touch
of redemption, couldn't we?
Lovely to see you again.
And you, Mr. Lockwood.
This was all John Hammond's dream.
To let these creatures live in peace.
So, we have created sanctuary.
No fences. No cages.
No tourists.
Just as Mother Nature intended.
John said it best.
"These creatures don't need our protection.
"They need our absence."
When we were young,
we both shared this passion,
John and I.
What fools we were,
trying to run before we'd learned to walk.
As all young men do, I suppose.
But we learned.
Unfortunately, in the end, it drove us apart.
Life teaches us some very hard lessons,
doesn't it, Claire?
Yes.
- Sir Benjamin.
- Hmm?
Ah.
My bloody medicines.
Will you excuse me, Claire?
Of course.
Eli here will help you with the details.
We will save them.
What a gift
for our children.
Thank you.
Iris?
Does he have children? I thought I saw...
Was there a little girl?
He has a grandchild.
His daughter died in a car accident.
That's awful.
Yeah, I know, but they're
very close. Really close.
So, what do you need from me?
There was a tracking system
in place at your park.
Radio-frequency ID chips in each dinosaur.
- I remember.
- Right.
So, if we could access that system,
our ability to locate and capture those
animals safely would increase tenfold.
We need your handprint to access the system,
but what I really need, Claire,
is you.
Moving endangered species isn't exactly
legal, but it's the right thing to do.
No one knows this park as well
as you do and we need that expertise.
- How many can you save?
- 11 species. For sure.
I mean, more if we can,
but time is against us.
I'm afraid there is one animal in particular
that poses a real challenge for us.
- Blue.
- I didn't know she had a name,
but Blue is potentially
the second-most intelligent
piece of life on this planet
and she's the last of her kind.
She must be preserved.
She can pick up your scent a mile off.
You'll never capture her.
Well, we thought you might know
someone who could help.
Maybe you could convince him.
Oh, Time, she is a freight train chugging
Oh, stalling Time is, too
When the light at the end of the tunnel
Is growing small behind you
Hey, Owen.
I still love you in the morning
Owen!
Oh, boy.
Hi.
Back for more, huh?
Can I buy you a beer?
Did you bring them, or do we
gotta, like, go somewhere?
I'm sorry.
Seriously?
I can't believe you think that you left me!
Replay the conversation
in your head, all right?
You said, "You wanna go
live in your van, like a bum?
"Go ahead, Owen."
And I said, "Okay."
So, how is that you leaving me?
Because I left. I left you.
You left because I told you to.
And then, I left.
Because you didn't wanna live
in a van on the side of the road.
- No. No, no, no.
- Remember?
Because you wouldn't let me drive
the damn van for 5 minutes.
I'm chivalrous. What can I do?
You are so stubborn.
Well, look at you now.
You're saving the world.
I'm trying, at least.
You can't just run away
from everything, Owen.
So, you're what...
Dating an accountant now?
An insurance actuary?
Your skin looks nice.
Dermatologist?
Owen...
- Does he check you for moles?
- Stop.
A ventriloquist?
This is not why we're here, okay?
Yeah, I know why we're here.
Lockwood's little flunky called me.
Rescue op.
Save the dinosaurs from
an island that's about to explode.
- What could go wrong?
- I'm going.
- Don't.
- I don't have a choice.
What? Of course you have a choice.
So, what, I should just build my own cabin,
play pool, and drink beer all day
while these dinosaurs go extinct?
Yeah. I like pool.
Blue is alive.
Jesus, Claire!
You raised her, Owen.
You spent years of your life
working with her.
You're just gonna let her die?
Well, yeah.
Come on, you're a better man
than you think you are.
You should write fortune cookies.
Forget it...
There's a charter flight
leaving tomorrow morning.
You're on the manifest.
I just wanted to let you know.
All right, chow time, chow time.
Whoa, whoa.
Back up. Back off.
Hey, hey, hey. Jeez.
Take it easy. Echo.
Jeez, there's plenty of food.
God, you guys been eating sugar or something?
You're hyper today.
Okay, okay. Back up.
Thank you, Blue.
Whoa, whoa.
Did you get that?
Relax. You're more likely to die
riding on a horse than in a plane.
No, I'm not, because I won't get on a horse.
My chances are zero.
Planes are the safest way to travel.
You call this a plane?
My cousin has a drone bigger than this.
- Owen!
- Franklin, you wiener, get on the plane.
Didn't think you were gonna ever show up.
Oh, um...
This is Zia Rodriguez.
Zia.
- Hey, how you doing?
- Yeah, real good. How are you?
Good.
Franklin Webb. Systems analyst.
Nervous flyer?
Would you ride a thousand-pound horse
that's been abused all its life?
I rode my motorcycle through
the jungle with a pack of raptors.
We're not compatible.
Maisie?
You're always hiding from me.
This is not my job, looking for you.
Maisie!
Come out!
Boo!
You silly sausage.
You'll be the death of me. You know,
one day, my heart might really stop.
Then what would you do?
Go and live in the forest with the lions?
- There are no lions in the forest.
- Your grandfather's been asking for you.
- Really?
- Mmm.
So, you go see your grandfather,
and then you go straight to your bath.
- I don't want a bath.
- What?
- Queen's English, girl. Bath.
- Bath.
Bath, not "bath," you're not a wild animal.
Stop.
Hi, Grandpa.
Ah, there you are.
Come over and sit by me.
I've missed you.
I was on safari all the way through
the Cretaceous to the Jurassic in one day.
Oh, my. What'd you see?
Mostly herbivores.
There was one T. Rex, though.
Casualties, of course. Iris included.
She jumped out of her skin.
You have your mother's wicked sense of humor.
Do I look like her?
Oh, yes.
You could be her mirror image.
Did my mother ever visit the park?
Once, a long time ago.
She would've saved them, too, you know.
She would have saved them all.
That's two klicks past the LZ.
Claire.
Ken Wheatley. Welcome back.
Quite an operation you've got going on here.
Mr. Lockwood takes his
humanitarian efforts very seriously.
Where's the, uh, raptor wrangler?
Animal behaviorist.
- Owen Grady.
- Hey, Owen. Ken Wheatley.
And you are the Great White Hunter?
I guess. I'm the expedition facilitator.
Oh, God! It's hot.
It's about to get a whole lot hotter.
Keep it moving! You're all clear!
Go! Go! You've got the green light!
This way! Let's go! Let's go! Keep it moving!
Hold it! Hold up!
Need some bug spray?
Bug spray?
The T. Rex would be dead by now, right?
No, it's impossible to know
the max lifespan of a clone
in a completely different environment.
Take a caveman that would've lived 20 years.
Feed him prime meals, give him health care,
he's gonna live 5 times as long.
So, she'd be dead by now? Right?
Bad memories?
Some were good.
What was that?
Is it the T. Rex?
I have to see this.
Hey! Miss? Miss!
This area is not secured.
Look at that.
Never thought I'd see one in real life.
She's beautiful.
Can we...
Okay, let's go.
Okay. Okay.
Okay, main system...
And turn on the controls.
It should be working.
Come on, tiger.
Do you know what you're doing?
After you, tiger.
Are we sure these
biometric chips are still transmitting?
Battery would be dead by now.
The dinosaur is the battery.
They're powered by body heat and movement.
Hand.
How much longer until...
I'm in.
There's a large concentration
on the east dock.
That's our boat. We've already
captured a bunch of them.
Without the tracking system?
The big herbivores are easy to find.
Can you isolate that raptor?
- I need a species code.
- D-9.
There she is.
I'm gonna need to borrow your truck.
I'm coming with you. We don't know
what kind of condition she might be in.
Miss, things could get hairy out there.
These are powerful sedatives. One too many,
and she could have respiratory failure.
Also, I'm not as soft and witless
as your comment implies.
Let's go, beefcake.
Oh, Owen?
Be careful, okay?
If I don't make it back,
remember, you're the one who made me come.
I'll be all right.
We're not going to get
any closer to her in this thing.
- We should stop here.
- Hold up.
Load out, look alive, stay alive.
- We got your back, brother.
- Yeah.
Claire, I'm going to have to track her alone.
I'll need you to be my eyes
if she runs. Copy?
Copy that.
Wheatley, I'm on fresh sign.
Wait for my signal.
There you are.
Hey, girl, you miss me?
Easy. Hey!
Hey.
I brought you something.
Here you go.
That's right.
Okay.
Hey!
You know me.
Eyes on me.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
You know me.
That's right.
Hold your...
I told you to wait for my signal.
Back your men up right now.
No, wait! No, no! No, don't shoot her!
Wheatley, you son of a bitch!
Owen!
What are you doing?
You shoot me and that animal dies.
I think we have the drop on you, sweetheart.
She's losing blood. And if I don't treat her,
she'll never make it back to camp.
How about this?
That animal dies, I shoot you.
You're gonna take care of her.
Let's move out!
Cut the cord and let's go!
Let's get out of here!
No, no, no! Wait!
Wait, are they protecting us?
What's going on?
I don't think so.
Why am I here?
Hey, Mills, we got her done.
Mission accomplished.
Just in the nick of time.
Wheatley, what the hell is going on there?
We're a day behind schedule already.
I want that money in the bank
by the time I get back, all right?
Okay, good. Listen to me.
No more delays, okay? If we don't...
- Mr. Mills?
- Not now, Maisie. Thank you.
- If we don't get those animals...
- Mr. Mills, are the dinosaurs safe?
I said not now!
Mills? Mills?
I'm sorry, honey. This is an important call.
If you go up to the library,
I'll meet you up there in a few minutes.
- Okay.
I'll tell you all about it, I promise.
Wheatley, you get those animals here now!
I want that bonus. We got the blue one.
Bring her to me first!
All right.
No!
Hello, can anyone hear me?
Hello?
Hello, is anybody there?
Can anybody copy?
I'm... I'm trying everything. It's jammed.
"Just take the job, son, build your
people skills." Yeah, thanks, Dad.
That's it.
Proximity alert.
Something's coming.
Where does that tunnel lead?
Well, it connects to the rest of the...
Park.
It's the T. Rex, it's the T. Rex!
Claire, it's the T. Rex.
It's the T. Rex, it's the T. Rex.
Will you stop? It's not the T. Rex!
Probably.
"Probably"?
Lava! Lava! Lava! Lava!
Deep breaths, Franklin.
See? Not a T. Rex!
How is this better?
Claire, what do we do? What do we do?
It's stuck!
Chair!
Come on! Let's go!
Come on, Franklin!
We made it! Yeah!
Come on, come on, come on!
Yes, yes, go, go!
Go, go!
Claire!
Holy...
Run!
Oh, my God!
Go! Go!
- Okay.
- We're okay.
- Buckle up.
- It's okay.
Get in!
Owen!
We gotta get out.
We just fell from the cliff. We're alive.
We're alive!
Franklin, move!
No, no, no!
No. Claire, we're gonna sink!
Water's leaking!
Oh, God. We need to get out!
Franklin, watch out!
I wanna go home!
Owen. Owen!
Owen?
Owen. Okay.
Move! Move!
No! No, no, no!
Push!
Owen! No.
- Where's he going?
- Okay, don't panic. Don't panic.
We're running out of air.
We're not gonna make it.
We are. We are. Take a deep breath.
Where is Zia?
It was a double-cross.
They took her, she must be with Blue.
Hey! Can you still track them?
Not anymore.
It was a lie.
It was a lie. Bastards!
It was all a lie!
Not all of it.
Let's move it! Move! Move!
Anything of value, I want on that boat!
- How you doing?
- The bolt won't give!
Just button it up,
and we'll tow it on! Let's go!
Lock it up! Move it out!
Come on, now.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Hang on! Wait up!
Stop that truck! Stop it!
Hey, sweetheart. Hello, hello.
Beautiful.
You're gonna feel that when you wake up.
Hey, put your weapon down!
You got the barrel pointed right at her head!
They have Zia. They're loading out.
If they already had the dinosaurs,
why did they need us?
They needed the tracking system
to capture Blue.
There she is. She don't look good.
We need to get on that boat.
The rock's good. We're safe on the rock.
It's the boat or the lava, Franklin.
All right, boat's good.
I'm all about the boat.
Go, go, get on the boat!
Get on the boat, now! Go, go!
- Move it, move it!
- Go, go, go!
Get that truck!
- Franklin!
- Hey, get that truck going!
Okay.
- You okay?
- Am I dead?
Not yet, kid.
Come on!
Come on. Give me your hand! Reach!
Come on, reach!
Hold on!
Mr. Mills?
Your visitor's waiting.
Mr. Eversoll.
It's a pleasure to meet you in person
after all this time. How are you?
- Excuse me.
- Yeah?
- Where are the dinosaurs?
- The dinosaurs are, uh, are en route.
Oh, so, am I supposed to sell these ones?
You don't need to worry, okay?
They will be here soon.
I don't really work with amateurs, so I'm
gonna contact my buyers and call this off.
They will be here tomorrow,
and your buyers won't be disappointed.
Trust me, whatever their interest,
agricultural, industrial, sport hunting,
we will have something to suit them.
11 species, each with unique
biopharmaceutical properties.
I estimate 4 million per species.
4 million is a slow Tuesday
where I'm from.
You're wasting my time.
You ever made 100 million on a Tuesday?
Huh?
All this is in the past.
I wanna talk to you about the future.
I'll give you 10 minutes.
The whole point of selling
the Isla Nublar dinosaurs
is to finance our future operations here.
It's, uh, seed money.
Call it an overture to something
much more ambitious.
Yeah, and more lucrative, I guess.
Right, we've reactivated the old facilities,
updated the technology, and imported
the best geneticists from around the world.
This operation has been
many years in the planning.
Genetic power is an uncharted frontier.
The potential for growth
is more than you can fathom.
This way, please.
If the entire run of our sorry history
has taught us one irrevocable lesson,
it's that man is inevitably drawn to war
and is willing to use
any means necessary to win it.
You're gonna weaponize them?
We've been using animals
in combat for centuries.
Horses, elephants.
The Soviets used disease-bearing rats
against the Germans at Stalingrad.
Yes, yes.
Our geneticists have created a direct
descendant of Henry Wu's masterpiece,
the animal that took down Jurassic World.
Indominus Rex.
Her DNA, retrieved from the island
way before its destruction,
forms the architecture
of a completely new creature.
Every bone and muscle designed
for hunting and killing.
And thanks to Owen Grady's research,
it follows human command.
We call it the Indoraptor.
Grandpa?
Grandpa.
Maisie, what are you doing up?
There was a man here today with Mr. Mills.
It was probably just some business
about the sanctuary. That's all.
I heard them talking.
They're going to sell the dinosaurs.
- They're bringing them here.
- Oh. Huh.
- I'm sure you misunderstood.
- I know what I heard, Grandpa.
Maisie, it's way past your bedtime.
Let's talk about this in the morning.
- But...
- Maisie, I'll find out tomorrow.
Go to bed.
Good night.
Good night, my heart.
Jesus.
It's okay, Blue, just a little longer.
Oh, my God! You guys are alive!
- Oh, look what they've done to her.
- Who are these assholes?
Animal traffickers.
Look how they're treating them.
They're not gonna take them
to a sanctuary, they're gonna sell them.
Not Blue, they need her for something else.
- Like what?
- I don't know, but she's...
She's hemorrhaging, and I don't have
instruments and they want to keep her alive.
Hey.
- You're all right, you're all right.
- Claire, come here.
Come on. Put your hand here.
Steady pressure.
Hey, hey, hey.
Watch out.
I can't take the bullet out
without a transfusion from another animal.
Which one of you knows how to find a vein?
Oh! I did a blood drive for the Red Cross.
Great. Okay.
Franklin, take over for Claire.
No, no, no.
Franklin, now!
Steady pressure.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Is it in my mouth?
- Did it get in my mouth?
- Mmm-mmm.
- You sure?
- You're good.
I can feel it on my face.
All of the animals should be sedated.
Look for any kind of Tetanuran,
their blood type should be close enough.
Look for carnivores with 2
or 3 fingers. No more than 3.
I think there's one onboard.
You gotta be kidding me.
She's tranqued.
Okay, okay. Okay, I got it. Come on.
Okay.
Oh, no. Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Come on.
- You're gonna have to do it.
- I can't. The skin is too thick.
I have to use both my hands to put
pressure on the vein. You gotta do it.
- I... I can't... I can't reach.
- You're gonna have to climb up there.
Oh, I'm not... No, no.
I'm not gonna climb up there.
You'll be okay. It's like riding a bull.
"Riding a bull"? I didn't grow up at
a rodeo or wherever you came from.
She's asleep now. I can't say that she's
gonna be asleep a minute from now so get up.
Okay, fine.
Oh, my God, she stinks.
Gently. Gently. No, no, no.
Good job.
You're making this look totally normal.
You're gonna have to jam it
in there, it's really thick skin.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- Okay. 1, 2...
- 1, 2...
Stab!
Owen!
It's working.
The pee is silent.
That door is open.
I got it.
The bars! The bars, Owen.
Owen, I can get through there. Come on.
Jump, Owen!
Owen, jump. Now!
Did you see that?
Uh-huh.
Please tell me you got the blood.
This is Delta.
She's one of the holdover theropods,
one of the survivors from the second group.
Now, watch this. I show
anysign of weakness whatsoever...
See that? Day 176. Blue is showing
unprecedented levels of compliance.
Here I am with Blue.
She's a theropod from the new group.
I show signs of weakness...
Hey.
I'm okay.
She's pretty extraordinary.
Blue, displaying levels
of interest, concern,
hyper-intelligence, cognitive bonding.
See that?
She's tilting her head,
she's craning forward.
Increased eye movement. She's curious.
She's showing empathy.
Okay, I'm gonna make an incision
in her leg to remove the bullet.
It's a lot of muscle tissue.
She's gonna be okay.
Blue is the key.
That's it. You have Blue,
you get these raptors to do anything.
- You're sure she'll live?
- If it dies, we have blood samples.
No, no, no. That's not good enough.
The raptor is a behavioral specimen.
We need her in good health.
I didn't shoot the damn thing.
What do you want me to do, huh?
You don't have the faintest
comprehension of what I'm doing here.
Do you understand the complexity
of creating an entirely new life form?
No, but I understand the complexity
of paying for it, okay?
All your money will have been wasted
if I don't get Blue here in good health.
To get the next iteration under control,
it needs to form a familial bond
with a closely related genetic link.
- English, Henry.
- It needs a mother!
Blue's DNA will be part
of the next Indoraptor's makeup.
So, it will be genetically coded to recognize
her authority and assume her traits.
Empathy. Obedience.
Everything the prototype
you have now is missing.
Okay, so how long is this gonna take?
It's not a sprint, Mr. Mills.
It's a marathon.
A marathon sounds expensive.
Besides, time is running out,
and so is my patience, Henry.
You have to understand,
this is all uncharted territory.
A wolf, genetically, is barely
distinguishable from a bulldog,
but within that gray area
is art.
Spare me the poetry, Henry.
Can you do it? Can you do it?
Yes, I can do it.
Well, then do it.
Thank you.
God, you're a pain in the ass.
Hey. Hey! Maisie!
What is that? What is it?
Keep her in there and keep the door locked.
You want to keep her locked in?
That's exactly what I want.
Sir Benjamin needs to see you now.
I believe it's important.
All crew, prepare for docking.
Let's move it, boys.
Jeez! Will somebody shut that thing up?
It sounds like my ex-wife.
We're here.
Where?
Just get in your truck and let's go.
- Move. Move!
- Move, move, move!
You got a heartbeat?
Yeah. Do you?
I need blood samples.
I'm not here to help you reset the food
chain, so take your own damn samples.
What a nasty woman.
Go, go, now, now. Go.
Attention, all crew. Attention, all crew.
Drivers, get to your vehicles.
Hey!
- What the hell is going on?
- I was...
I needed an extra pair of hands.
He volunteered.
- Are you deck crew?
- Aye, aye.
We're loading out. Follow me.
Uh, does that mean
we're leaving the ship right now?
That is what "loading out" means.
Now get moving. Come on, follow me.
- Come on, kid. There's lots to do.
- Shit!
- Oh, no. He's not gonna make it.
- Get a move on. Come on.
- Move it! Come on. Move!
- We have to help him.
Stay here, I'll get him.
There's no time. Let's go.
I got 5. I'm on it.
Why is this truck still here?
- Good to go!
- Roll out!
Where are they taking them?
- We're about to find out.
- Let's go!
Ready to roll!
Keep it coming!
Move it out! Keep it rolling!
Good to go!
Come on, girl.
Yes!
This is Lockwood's estate.
He must have one big-ass garage.
Let's go! We want this offloaded in 10 mikes!
Big door's open.
Did you really think
you could get away with it?
In my own house.
You entrusted me
to guide your fortune into the future.
- I have done that.
- Damn you!
Pick up that phone.
I want you to call the police.
It'll be easier if the story comes from you.
As you say, sir.
You know, I've been thinking,
John Hammond was right.
It was an unholy thing that you did.
I'm not the only guilty one here, am I, sir?
Hey.
We hit that town, we call
the cavalry, shut this down.
Whoo. Hello.
You should have stayed on the island.
Better odds.
Hi, Claire.
I just wanted to come and apologize.
I didn't wanna bring you into any of this,
but it was the only way
that we could get the raptor.
We needed it.
Come on.
So, what? This is it?
I mean, you're a smart guy, you could have
started a foundation,
cured cancer, but instead you,
what?
Sell endangered species?
I saved these animals.
You betrayed a dying man for money.
Claire, I admire your idealism,
but we both exploited these animals.
At least I have the integrity to admit it.
I never, ever did anything remotely illegal.
You authorized the creation
of the Indominus Rex.
You exploited a living thing
in a cage for money.
How is that different? Huh?
And you, the man who proved
raptors can follow orders.
You never thought about the applications
of your research, Owen?
How many millions a trained
predator might be worth?
You two, you're the parents of the new world.
Hey! Let him go.
- Owen.
- I think I'll break it.
Let him go.
Claire, I just want...
Say, how we gonna end this?
Well, as far as everybody else is
concerned, they burned up on the island.
Buyers on approach. Looks like a full house.
Roger that.
- Good evening.
- Welcome, gentlemen.
Welcome.
And these guys are development rep
for Aldaris Pharmaceuticals.
Great.
The guy in the beard is a proxy for
Gregor Adlrich, a Slovenian arms dealer.
Equine buyers.
Rand Magnus, an oil magnate from Houston.
What's their interest?
Strictly personal.
His kid wants a baby Triceratops.
Glenn, how's Janet?
She's doing fine, thanks.
Straight ahead, Glenn.
Well, he only wants carnivores. Two of them.
Looks like Lockwood's
gonna have a very good night.
Will he be joining us?
Um... That's very unlikely.
Grandpa?
Grandpa, wake up.
Grandpa!
Grandpa, wake up. Wake up.
Iris!
It's over.
What a tragedy.
I suppose now he's gone,
you'll be looking for another situation.
No.
Maisie needs me.
I'm her guardian now.
What she needs is no longer your concern.
You don't understand her the way I do.
I understand her value.
But I raised her.
I raised both of them.
- Please, Mr. Mills.
- Goodbye, Iris.
Do you remember the first time
you saw a dinosaur?
First time you see them, it's like a miracle.
You read about them in books,
you see the bones in museums,
but you don't really believe it.
They're like myths.
And then you see
that first one alive.
This is not your fault.
But it is.
No.
This one's on me.
I showed them the way.
Listen.
You and I are gonna have plenty
of time to talk about this later.
If there is a later.
Yes, there is.
I got a cabin to finish.
What is that?
Well, look who just woke up.
Go.
We're getting out of here.
Welcome, ladies, gentlemen,
to this extraordinary evening.
Let's dive right in with lot number one,
the Ankylosaurus.
She's a herbivorous quadruped,
late Cretaceous.
This is one of the largest armored dinosaurs,
known by paleontologists as a living tank.
What are you doing?
Escaping.
You sure about this?
Nope.
I have $4 million, anyone 5?
- 5.
- $5 million.
$5 million. Do I hear 6?
- $6 million.
- $6 million, thank you.
Any increase on 6? 7. $7 million.
$8 million.
9 million on the phones.
Do I hear 10 million?
- 10 million? 10 million.
- 10.
$10 million! Once, twice...
Sold!
To the gentleman from Indonesia.
Congratulations, sir.
Lot number two, ladies and gentlemen.
A juvenile Allosaurus.
A fierce and an aggressive predator.
Sold!
Sold.
Wonderful.
Wonderful bidding.
Come on. You're good. Let's go.
- Move it out.
- Here we go.
Bring it on back. Let's go.
Okay.
Hey! Hey, you. Look at me! Look at me!
Hey!
Come with me. Come with me!
Okay, there you go.
You're welcome.
Hey, wait!
Please, please wait.
That's Lockwood's granddaughter.
Hey. Hey, kid. You wanna
come down out of there?
- Uh...
Do you remember me?
Yeah?
My name is Claire. What's yours?
Maisie.
Maisie Lockwood.
This is my friend, Owen.
I saw you with the Velociraptors. Blue.
Oh. Oh, yeah?
Uh...
You like dinosaurs?
So do I. Tell you what,
you come on down from there,
I'll tell you everything you need
to know about Blue.
That sound all right?
All right, yeah.
Come on down.
Sweetie, we need some help
finding your grandfather.
Can you take us to him?
No.
You made it down here all by yourself, huh?
Brave kid.
Looks like you could use a friend.
He's gone.
Listen, I'll tell you what, we were
just about to go and find our friends
and then get the heck out of here.
You wanna come with us?
We could use a friend, too.
- 19.5!
- 19.5.
Do I hear 20? Do I hear 20?
20? Thank you. Thank you.
20. Do I hear...
$21 million!
21 million...
Sold! And now, ladies and gentlemen,
that we are halfway through the evening...
...we'd like to offer a special treat to our
discriminating buyers.
This evening we will preview
a new asset that we've been developing.
A creature of the future
made from pieces of the past.
Ladies and gentlemen, please be warned,
this is the perfect blend
of the two most dangerous creatures
that have ever walked the earth.
We call it the Indoraptor.
The perfect weapon for the modern age.
Built for combat.
With tactical responses more acute
than any human soldier.
What is that thing?
They made it.
Mr. Mills and the other man.
What man?
Him.
Designed by Mr. Henry Wu
with an intelligence quotient
comparable to the Velociraptor.
Biospecs include a heightened sense of smell
and trained to respond
to a pulse-coded laser targeting system,
enabling it to isolate and track prey
in complex environments. Voilà.
Now, first, the laser sets the target.
Once locked on, the acoustic
signal triggers the attack.
This animal is relentless.
Now, modifications are still being made...
20 million!
No, this is a prototype.
Uh, not for sale.
21!
- It is still a prototype, but...
- 22!
23!
24!
$24 million.
25 million!
Do I hear 26?
That thing can't leave this building.
26!
- Any advance on 26?
- 27!
$27 million from the back.
What are you doing?
This animal is not for sale.
If you wanna create an addict,
you have to give them a taste.
He's a prototype.
This prototype is worth
$28 million right now.
Relax, we'll make some more.
So will they.
Hey, buddy.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
Once. Twice.
Sold to the Russian friend.
Well done, sir. And congratulations...
for this magnificent animal.
Oh, God!
Get this thing out of here!
Hey, you! Turn it out!
Mills!
Mills, where are you?
I want my bonus!
Holy cow!
What are you?
I didn't see you on the island.
Oh, you're a tough guy.
Look at you.
You're some kind of hot rod
with really pretty teeth.
This'll make a perfect centerpiece
for my necklace.
Open wide.
No. No.
Please.
Move! Move! Out of the way!
Don't!
You two, you deserve each other.
Maisie, come with me.
You got your money, now walk away.
- Oh, what are you gonna do, huh?
- We're gonna stop this. All of it.
How? What, are you gonna go back in time
before Hammond decided to play God?
- You can't put it back in the box!
- We have to try.
It's too late. Maisie, come.
Oh! So, you're gonna take care of her now?
Huh?
You have no idea what she is.
What do you think drove Hammond
and Lockwood apart, huh?
Lockwood never had a grandchild.
He just wanted his daughter back.
And he had the technology.
He created another.
He made her again.
Go.
Come on!
Come on.
Eggs need to go in a sterile environment.
Where are those genome kits?
Get this to Mills. Be very careful,
it's extremely valuable.
You, I need blood samples from the raptor.
Don't just stand there like an idiot!
Get me 50 ccs carfentanil
and a phlebotomy kit!
It's right there! Now!
Come on. Come on.
I need this raptor's blood.
Sure, go ahead.
Where is that kit?
Okay, now listen to me.
It is better for you to cooperate.
I'm gonna get this blood
with or without your help.
This blood's contaminated.
I designed this animal myself.
It's pure.
Every cell of her body was created
in the most controlled environment
under the most demanding of conditions.
Yeah, but I did an intravenous
blood transfusion with a T. Rex,
so, it's a sock drawer in there.
You what?
Franklin! What are you doing?
Saving your life!
Yes!
Stop!
Don't move.
Now step away from that cage. Now.
Easy now.
Run. Run!
Dave, do you copy? Dave, you there?
Run!
You see that?
That's hydrogen cyanide.
If it reaches the containment
level, it'll kill them all.
The ventilation system is down.
Can you bring it back up?
The server's unresponsive.
I have to reboot the whole system.
- So, reboot it.
- I'm trying.
What?
- Franklin, we don't have time.
- I know, I know, I know.
Okay.
Go. Go.
Run, run.
Hey. Here. You're okay.
Put pressure on it. Don't look at it.
Look at me. Look at me.
- You have to go find her.
- I can't leave you here.
Go. Go, I'll be fine.
Run!
Maisie, stay down!
Follow me. I know a way on the other side.
Come on.
Come on!
This way!
I got you.
Hey!
Come on.
What the hell?
Hey!
You good?
Yeah. You?
Nope.
Hey, we got a problem downstairs.
I need you to come see this.
They're all dying.
The blast damaged the ventilation system.
We did everything we could.
I can open the gates from here.
Claire, be careful.
We're not on an island anymore.
Claire.
You press that button,
there is no going back.
We can't let them die.
I had to.
They're alive, like me.
Don't! Don't!
Hey, girl.
Owen.
It's okay, she won't hurt us.
Hey.
Blue, come with me.
We'll take you to a safe place, okay?
How many times do you have
to see the evidence?
How many times must the point be made?
We're causing our own extinction.
Too many red lines have been crossed.
And our home has,
in fundamental ways, been polluted
by avarice and political megalomania.
Genetic power has now been unleashed
and of course, that's gonna be catastrophic.
This change was inevitable
from the moment we brought
the first dinosaur back from extinction.
We convince ourselves that sudden change
is something that happens outside the
normal order of things, like a car crash,
or that it's beyond our control,
like a fatal illness.
We don't conceive of sudden,
radical, irrational change
as woven into the very fabric of existence.
Yet, I can assure you, it most assuredly is.
And it's happening now.
Humans and dinosaurs
are now gonna be forced to co-exist.
These creatures were here before us.
And if we're not careful,
they're gonna be here after.
We're gonna have to adjust
to new threats that we can't imagine.
We've entered a new era.
Welcome to Jurassic World.