Edited at https://subtitletools.com
TIMM:
I think on a kind of a primal level,
I think there's just something about
having superpowered characters team up
with other superpowered characters
is just very appealing.
All right.
DiDIO: Each one ofthem
are true individuals
and they all have
their own sense of right and wrong.
While they might not share
exact same beliefs
they do share a common good
and a common goal.
So they then have to adapt and change
and become bigger and better heroes,
to unite and work together.
WOLFMAN: And that's great drama
and that’s great storytelling.
It is what has allowed
the Justice League to continue
for the last 50 years.
JOHNS: There is a great history
to explore in the Justice League.
The team and these characters
live in all these different media.
Comic books, animation,
video games, toys.
Every generation meet these characters
and a different take
on the Justice League.
And now we are seeing
the next generation
meeting the Justice League
through this film.
DiDIO: If you wanna follow
the history of Justice League,
it actually starts
not even with the Justice League,
it starts with the Justice Society.
The Justice Society features a lot of
the characters that existed in the 19405
and brought them all together
in one big story. It was more a club
and an organization
than a superhero team,
and it was more about sharing adventures
than actually going on
adventures together.
Then you flash fon/vard
to the late '503, early '603
when the Silver Age comics are starting,
they're reintroducing these
new interpretations of our characters.
So it would only seem to follow suit
that the next interpretations
of the Justice Society
is a new group
and this was called the Justice League.
It was a smash hit.
LEE: Brave and the Bold number 28,
Justice League number 1,
been around since 1960.
What is that? Carry the one...
Like, a long time. They've been around
a long, longtime. (CHUCKLES)
They came together because of
a giant starfish called Starro.
That was the big threat.
DiDIO: So you start to see
Justice League now becoming
an integral portion of the DC Universe.
The Justice League becomes the book
where all characters seem to appear.
So, if there's one comic
you're supposed to buy that was the one.
My personal favorites are those stories
which are the ones where they go out
and try to convince
new characters to join the team.
The Atom joins later.
Green Arrow joins later.
They go out there and they search out
characters like Zatanna.
They offer the position to Metamorpho.
He turns them down
'cause he doesn’t want to be a hero.
And they keep on introducing
new characters.
MORRISON: The thing that really
did it for me was the run of stories
that Len Wein wrote in the '703
which were just really great adventures.
What he would do, it wouldn't be
an adventure would finish
and then there’d be a new one.
There would be a new one, but there was
plot threads that ran through it
so it was very much
like television today
where we have an individual episode
but there are massive plot threads
that will run through and play out
and mysteries that you have to
think about and solve.
So, his Justice League for me
was real inspiration.
JOHNS: And then they did
Crisis on Infinite Earths
which is the famous comic book storyline
by George Pérez and Marv Wolfman.
Crisis came out in the mid ’803.
All the DC heroes, Superman, Batman,
Wonder Woman, Hawkman,
Green Lantern, Flash, etc, etc.,
you can go on forever, were all created
between 1938 and 1941.
Almost 50 years later, the best
characters have been continuing.
Superman, Batman, and Wonder Woman
were published non-stop.
Some of the characters were starting
to get older.
They don ’t feel as modern anymore.
We needed something
to make them special again.
Also, DC was too confusing
for new readers.
It had a strange continuity, we had
this Multiverse of different planets
filled with multiple versions
of the superheroes.
You didn't know
who all the characters were.
And my pitch was, let's start with
getting rid of the Multiverse.
Let's bring it down
to our basic characters.
Superman, Batman, Wonder Woman,
one of each.
Let’s think about what works
and what doesn’t work
and how can we make it work now
for 1985?
JOHNS: When Crisis came out,
they relaunched a lot of titles.
Superman and Wonder Woman and Flash,
but also Justice League with
Giffen, DeMatteis and Kevin Maguire.
It was not the usual team
you saw and the tone of it was funny.
There was a lot of humor to it.
It was this weird mix of characters
and from the outside
it was like, oh, wow,
they're trying to do something new.
It was wonderful.
People really liked it.
They were going against the trend
of grim and gritty comics.
It was a great take on the team.
And it was cool
to see these strange characters together
that we 'd never seen come together
and form the Justice League.
And so for years and years and years,
the Justice League was never
the Big Seven, as they called them.
Then you flash forward
to Midsummer’s Nightmare
which is really
a standalone, independent story.
And that’s the first time you see
the seven interacting again.
And lo and behold, the reaction
from the fan base is very strong.
Then ultimately that gets you to
the big launch point which is JLA.
When Grant Morrison takes hold
of the book and really takes
all the primary characters,
puts them together,
creates villains and situations
that really
are worthy of bringing
those seven characters together.
MORRISON: When I committed to it,
I said, can we bring back
the Big Seven Justice League?
Can we focus on giant scale adventures
that only they could deal with?
The big idea I had, though,
was that the Justice League
was so close to the
Greek pantheon of gods.
Let's make a point of that,
let's actually assign them, you know?
The Flash is Hermes. Superman is Zeus.
Batman is Hades.
And it really ﬁts beautifully
'cause the DC characters
are such big archetypes.
What I could then do was go back to the
Iliad or the Odyssey
or to Celtic or Norse myths and there
was such a great wealth of stuff
that could be adapted
or science fictionalized or recreated.
So I think that was
what I brought to it,
a sense of grandeur, a sense of scope
and the fact that these characters
could reach out to every single corner
of the DC Universe
and explore it in a new way.
LEE: If you go back to the earliest
stories of the Justice League,
there wasn't a lot of conflict
between the characters.
It wasn't until later
that modern creators came in
and decided if we bring more conflict
between these characters,
even though they're heroes,
it makes for a more interesting story.
It makes for a more interesting team.
Because it more resembles real life.
MORRISON: We tried to position
them as professionals
even though they would
sometimes disagree or fall out.
It was all about,
"Let's get the job done. "
And I used to love the interplay
of using all those powers together
to defeat an enemy
that seemed undefeatable.
But if you combine those skills,
and if you're smart enough
to get the recipe right,
then the Justice League can pretty much
solve any problem.
You do this and you do that
and you do this
and we’ll save the world.
That's probably my favorite
run of all time.
It was really a special time
for Justice League.
LEE: The New 52 was a big publishing
initiative we launched in 2011,
where we basically looked
at the entire DC Universe and said,
if we could start over,
how would we do it?
And so one of the ﬁrst things we could
do was redefine the Justice League,
what brought these characters together,
and really show readers
the first glimpses of the interactions
of the world’s greatest superheroes
and do it in a realistic way
where we showcase the differences
between the personalities.
We were back to the team. It was Batman,
Superman, Wonder Woman, Flash, Aquaman,
Green Lantern. And that's the first time
we brought in Cyborg.
That's the core team we started with
and kind of went back to the basics.
Over the years there's been a lot
of changes but it always comes back,
no matter how many changes happen
in the comic books,
it always comes back to,
these are the original characters.
JOHNS: My love for DC Comics,
and speciﬁcally
superheroes ’cause I’m all things DC,
comes from Super Friends which was
this Saturday morning animated series.
LEE: Back then all we really had
was animation
so the Super Friends
was the closest thing we had
to seeing the Justice League
come to life
'cause you could see them move
and they talked
and they interacted and they had
a theme song and that’s what made me
go outside and put a towel around
my neck and run around like a dork.
It was done under really restrictive
TV broadcast standards and practices.
They were not allowed to show characters
punching other characters,
so any kind of action they had,
it was more like,
Superman would ﬁght a tornado
rather than fight another villain.
There were things like that
which kept it from its full potential.
TIMM: When we came along and did
our Justice League show
in the early 20003...
It gave you a chance to take something
that was like a static image on a comic
and bring it into
cinematic kind of storytelling.
After we had done two seasons
ofJustice League,
Cartoon Network said, "Yeah, we would
like you guys to do another season.
But we want to rebrand
the show somehow."
I came up with this name,
Justice League Unlimited.
And I thought, what does that mean?
And that basically means
instead of having
just seven superpowered characters,
now we've got 50 some odd
superpowered characters.
Basically, any character
in the DC Universe is now
automatically a member
of the Justice League.
But it allowed us to kinda
dig deeper into the DC bench,
so that we could use
characters like The Question,
and Hawk and Dove, and Captain Atom.
Characters who are
interesting to us as comic book fans.
And they weren't necessarily
household names as the other characters.
But it was something that allowed us
to expand the scope of the show.
And it turned out to be
quite a big hit with the fans.
I always say it was my favorite show
of all the shows I’ve ever worked on.
Because every episode was different
than every other episode.
And then, doing the Justice League
as a series of feature-length movies,
it's interesting, it kinda gives us
a little more of a narrow focus
in terms of, instead of having
season-long story arcs,
we ’re basically telling
movie-length stories,
with still a pretty large ensemble cast.
So, it's tricky from
a storytelling standpoint
to make sure that
each character is there for a reason.
It’s really tough to accommodate
seven lead characters.
We always do try to balance it out.
You wanna make sure
they at least get one
really good action sequence in the film.
It’s a juggling act,
it's a challenge.
-How many of you are there?
-Not enough.
SNYDER: It's challenging to have
all these amazing superheroes
together on the screen
to tell this big, epic story
with action and spectacle,
but also a lot of character.
And I think Zack does an amazing job
balancing all of that out.
Wait until the camera comes around Ben.
SNYDER: It is super exciting
to finally bring
all these superheroes,
the Justice League,
to the screen for the first time.
-This is amazing.
-This is crazy.
FISHER: The day we were all up
on the wall for the first time,
it was like watching
my 8-year-old dreams come true.
It took me back to those days
watching the cartoons,
I almost shed a tear, I will say
I held it together pretty good.
It's groundbreaking.
Wow, it's like a cave!
Like a Batcave.
MILLER: lswearl've been
blacking out and entering comic frames.
Barry.
MILLER: And living in the world
of this invented universe,
and then coming to like,
"Whoa, where am I?"
It's very hard to describe the feeling,
when you look out
and you see thatAlex Ross painting.
And you see it in front of you,
and it's these real people.
It's so amazing!
He's back!
I had this moment the other day on set
where I looked up and I saw
Jason, Gal, and Ben,
and Ezra, and Ray there,
and I thought, "This is a piece of
history happening right now.
And I'm lucky enough
to be a part of it."
Well, I knew you didn't bring me back
'cause you liked me.
I don't not...
AFFLECK: It's interesting, because
pop culture has chewed up and spit out
so many pop icons
over the years.
That's part of what pop culture does,
is sort of consume
characters and icons and ideas.
And you start with them
looking cool and interesting,
and when it's done with them
they seem retro,
then they seem just absurd and goofy
and hopelessly dated.
And lot of these core DC characters
still don ’t seem dated.
They somehow still work
in stories today.
And I think that's just the mark
of characters that are very well drawn,
that they still have
this kind of resonance.
LEE: The fun and beauty
of comic books is that,
when it’s a shared universe,
you're really standing on the shoulders
of these creative giants before you.
And everyone acknowledges
and understands
that their ideas will be used,
and change and evolve
to kind of further this giant storyline
that we're all creating.
My man!
DiDIO: As comic book storytellers,
we 've been telling the stories
for these characters
for over 50 years.
So there '3 so many stories out there,
so many great touchpoints
for people to tap into
and pull the ideas out
and mold and create it
to what works best
for whatever medium.
What works best for television.
What works best for the screen,
so I’m gonna be interested
where they take them.
We should always have new versions,
we should always make the books
relevant to the current generation.
Keep the characters up-to-date.
Don't let them become
your granddaddy's superhero.
You need characters
who will reflect the modern age.
-S|owpoke.
-Oh, it's on.
CHARLES ROVEN: I’ve been really blessed
to be part of the evolution
of the DC Universe.
You have these characters,
and you get to play
with their motivations.
And as long as you honor the canon,
there's still a lot left that you can do
and that’s a lot of fun.
Big round table.
Six chairs, right there.
But room for more.