Subtitled By Asmita/BioHapzard
Psagmeno.com
Subtitles/Trailers/Screenshots
If we can put this
tremendous machine of ours...
which has made this victory possieble...
To work for peace...
We can look forward to the greatest age
in the history of mankind
Speed of progress in the satellite project
Can not be taken as an index
of our progress...
in ballistic missiles.
I feel we are on the brink
of an areal expansion...
of knowledge about ourselves
and our surroundings..
Those are beyond description of
comprehension this time.
For the first time,
we are putting cameras in the space...
and looking down on the Earth...
allowing us to discover places, things
we never seen before.
The most intelligent inhabitants
of the future world...
won't be man or monkeys.
That Will be machines.
We set sail on this new sea...
because there is new knowledge to be gained.
Whether this new ocean...
will be a sea of ​​peace...
or a new terrifying theater of war.
"To tame the savageness of man...
" And nature, hope the life of this world."
Let us dedicate ourselves to that.
The city wide protests have...
Promising more gridlocks
in the days of weeks ahead...
Mark my words
There will never be a more
screwed up time in Washington.
But we can't let it stop us.
Maybe now is not the best time to ask
Monarch is on the cast of being shut down
Brooks. We are broke!
When this war ends,
we will never get approval
for our expedition.
I am not confident in our presentation.
I mean all of our material are loose slip.
In one day, one day...
I could have all this organized.
That we today,
have concluded an agreement...
to end the war
and bring peace with honor in Vietnam.
all American forces will be withdraw.
We don't have a day.
Hello there.
Bill Randa here to see Senator Willis.
Of course, Mr. Randa.
I left you a message this morning about
rescheduling today's appointment
But he should have some thing available
in the coming weeks.
God.
Al, you looking well.
You didn't get the message, Randa?
- To reschedule?
- For the fifth time? I must have missed
It'll be quick.
Don't get comfortable. You got five minutes.
I'm late for a meeting.
What imaginary monster
are you hunting this time?
This is a satellite photo...
of an uncharted island in the South Pacific.
It has defied discovery until now.
Many civilizations spoke of it in legends.
Skull Island.
The land where God did not finish creation.
It is notorious for the...
of ships and planes that
have gone missing there.
Like the Bermuda Triangle?
Or like that baloon foil hat that
I like to wear in the weekends?
It's more like the triangle in the hat...
but we like to think
it's much more than that.
The 1954 Castle Bravo nuclear test...
Wasn't test.
They were trying to kill something.
I believe there is an ecosystem out there
in the likes of which we can't imagine
And the place to find it is this island.
A place where myth and science meet.
Randa it's a fairy tale.
Harry Truman didn't think so
when he funded Monarch in 1946.
In terms of sheer waste...
Monarch ranks right up here
in the search for alien life.
Yeah, but those guys are nuts.
We should have shut it down years ago.
This is an opportunity for our country.
Listen, Senator,
Landsat is setting a mission to the Island
We should piggybank on that operation.
With your permission, of course.
What are you hoping to find?
Resources, medicine,
the cure for cancer, geological discoveries.
The Possible alternative fuels, Senator...
Listen, to be honest...
we do not know for sure what's in there.
Okay. But I'll tell you what we do know.
Tomorrow night, the Russian Novosat
passes over this sector.
In three days, they are gonna have
the same images as we have
So whatever's there...
You want us to find it first.
Right?
I don't believe I'm saying this...
but that almost makes sense.
Thank you.
So I will get the piggybank for you. I will
But listen to me. this is it.
It's gotta end. This is it
You promise me? The last favor? ok?
Senator?
One last thing.
I am going to need a military escort.
- Hey, Mills.
- Yeah?
How many letters did you end up writing her?
Ten, fifteen.
How many letters she write you?
I don't know, three, four.
man, you got a shitty mom.
I'll be trying to telling her
when I see her in the next 48 hours.
hey, Mile have a shitty mom.
Right?
Sir?
chapman
Do you need anything, sir?
Roger that
What are you gonna do
when you get back to the world, chapman
I am already set up with
the Eastern Air Lines.
Grace and Billy all moved in Atlanta...
Waiting on me.
That's you sir?
All this for what?
Sir?
Get out of here, chapman. Go have some fun.
Everything okay?
Tip top
Colonel Packard!
There's a phone call for you.
This is Packard.
Packard, General Ward.
You and your boys up of one last op?
I would not be opposed to that, sir.
Yours order to head home
are already processed.
Sure you do not want to take some time?
I'm here to execute
whatever orders I'm given, sir.
Don't get too excited.
The scientists on Landsat
discovered a new island on their Satellite.
They need helicopter
transport for a survey job.
Roger that. And sir?
Yes?
Thank you.
Randa, I do not get it.
You already got us a military escort.
Why do we need a tracker? And why SAS?
SAIGON DISTRICT-GUANNÃM
Former SAS.
No links to anyone.
And he rescued 12 pilots
in Danang, at 72.
But your source says that
he spends most of his working hours...
Is your Yale degrees supposed to
lead us though the Jungle, Brooks?
My father told me never judge a man
by where he drinks...
Only how he hold it.
You aren't bored with me here?
You go.
Well. Okay.
So, How much did you tell him?
Just Enough to get him to say yes.
Now there is a man worth talking to.
An uncharted island?
Let me list all they ways you gonna die.
Rain, heat, mud, disease carrying flies
and mosquitoes.
Sure you could load up on the
Atabrine for the malaria...
but what about the other bacteria?
I mean how I even started on the things
that want to eat you alive.
We'll double then.
I have no idea how dangerous this is.
I want five times that.
Plus a bonus if we make it back.
If?
Pay him.
I think Mr. Conrad should
be fairly compensating.
Here is to profit during peace.
One question.
You came here looking
for a tracker.
Who or what am I tracking?
This is all the
information that we have.
Okay? There is no map.
Only satellite images.
So we need someone like you...
with your skill, and unique expertise
in unchartered jungle terrain...
To lead us on our ground expedition.
We are just scholers and scientists.
We need someone with experience.
In case things go sideways.
Men go to war in search
of something, Mr. Conrad.
If you would found it...
you would be home by now.
- Weaver.
- Yeah, it's Jerry.
Hey, Jerry.
Tell me, do we get it?
That Landsat thing?
You got it
I did?
Hello?
there is the Athena docked in Bangkok.
Pier 14, 6'o clock tomorrow night.
1800 tomorrow.
Thank you. I really owe you one.
I don't get it. Why do you want a
gig documenting a mapping mission?
When you're at the cover of Time?
Jerry, when three sources
tell you the same thing word for word...
You know they are lying.
There is something going on here,
something that nobody is talking.
BANGKOK, THAILAND
PIER 14
I can not believe we're doing this.
A day away?
One day away!
And no, now we gotta go to another Island...
with another jungle.
Vietnam is not a island, Dumbass.
Key West is...
and that's exactly where
I need to be right now,
with a drink in my hand.
Key West ain't an island, either.
It's a key.
You ain't funny, Cole.
Mason Weaver, photographer.
Mason Weaver is a woman?
last time I checked
Can I help you?
Two years in the country.
Where have you been?
Embedded with MAC V-SOG.
You in the shit.
I respect that.
Cause people like you,
lost us support back home.
You aren't actually gonna blame
the people without guns...
For loosing the war, are you?
Camera is way more dangerous than a gun.
And we did not lose the war...
We are abondaning.
Right.
Hello and welcome.
I am Lansat field supervisor,
Victor Nieves
this is my collegue, Steve Woodward
Our data wrangler
Our expedition takes
us to a place...
Every nautical trade route known to man
has avoided for centuries.
As our satellite shows...
the island is surrounded
by a perpetual storm system
Allowing it to remain hidden
from the outside world.
But with Colonel Packard's
helicopter transport.
we will be the first to break
through to the other side.
We, are also pleased to be
joined for the fisrt time
By the resource exploration team...
led by Mr. Randa...
and the company by biologist,
Ms. San...
and geologist, Mr. Brooks.
Our focus will be on
the Island surface
There is, what lies beneath.
Mr Brooks.
Simple really
We are using explosives to shake the earth,
and create vibrations...
Helping us to map the sub
surface of the island.
We will fly over the south shore and
then strategically drop seismic chargers
that will help us understand
the density of the earth.
You are dropping bombs?
Scientific instruments.
Do you hear that, boys?
we are scientists, now
You guys are not scientists.
We'll then land, and make base camp...
for ground excursions led by Mr. Conrad.
Me to Jack Chapman.
All right. Once on the island...
the storm interfarence will block
all radio contact with the ship.
That means, we will be by ourselves
Three days later, refuel team will meet us
here on north of the Island...
north of the island.
That might be our only safe departure...
for unknown period.
So a tip for everybody...
Don't miss it, please.
What are you doing down here?
I could ask you the same thing.
Why does a geological mapping mission
needs explosives.
Seismic charges for the geological survey.
And you believe that?
I did not say that.
Have you met Colonel Packard yet?
Yeah.
The guy bound pretty tight
But as a decorated war hero.
It's the package they come in
And you?
Isn't shooting a mapping mission
start down for a photojournalist?
The right photo help shape opinions.
And win you a Pulitzer.
Well, Captain Conrad.
What about you?
How did British Special
forces get dragged into this?
Just Conrad. I'm decommissioned.
They offered me money.
You don't strike me as a mercenary.
You don't strike me as a war photographer.
Anti war photographer.
What are you writing there, Chap?
Letter to my boy.
DEAR BILLY
"Dear Billy...
"I know I said I would at
be home by your birthday,
but I lied straight to your face.
"I'm a terrible dad.
"I hope this letter makes out for you".
It's too short.
This storm look a lot
max near in person.
maybe we should consider
postponing the mission.
How far away is this island?
50 miles. maybe more.
Take us closer.
You wanna launch, do it from here.
Can you punch through that, Colonel?
- Our opening is now.
- Bring This whole right here?
Yeah, it's a real low pressure pocket.
I appreciate your passion, Randa...
but as a field supervisor
of the controlling agency...
I say we abort. that's it,
we are gonna abort.
Wise call.
I'm sure the Landsat inspector
will be inspired by your courage.
I hope you inspired by my common sense.
This is only a map surveying
To one of the vast unchartered areas
on the face of the earth.
And you want to call it on account of rain?
Stay on the boat if you want to.
It could be years
before we get another shot at this.
I'm told your unit is capable
of handling inclement weather, Colonel.
Why don't we leave it to Colonel Packard
to break the tie?
There is no way
I'm getting on that helicopter.
We did ask on those helicopters.
Should not they know why?
Why? And raise an alarm?
It is purely a precaution, Brooks.
Right.
Two mike to launch.
Still this end to come
Nothing he wouldn't do himself.
He is taking the lead.
That means he miss his bed, I miss my bed.
Don't you miss your bed?
Do you even have a bed, Cole?
You got a bed, right?
See you at the rendevzous, Chapman.
Yes sir.
SEISMIC LOADS
Complete FOB lockdown, and clear the deck.
One mike to launch.
- Battery?
- Check.
- Generator start?
- Engine start?
- Checked three times.
This is Fox. Leader of the Fox Group.
It's time once again...
Griffin and ants show.
As usual, remember...
... Hold on to your butts!
Attention pilots. You are clear to takeoff.
Launch, launch, launch.
Combat formation.
Keep visual.
Fox five let me know when you're close.
Fox Five is in the slot.
Roger that.
Fox Team, follow up on me. Keep together.
Let's do this!
Maintain course.
Nothing we haven't done before.
"Dear Billy.
"You ever look inside a hurricane
and decide?
"Maybe I should fly straight through it."
"Because that is what just happen."
You might want to hang on.
Fox Leader to Fox Group.
Switch to inertial navigation.
And remember the story of Icarus...
whose father gave him wings, they flex.
Warned him not to fly too close to the sun.
But the exhilaration was too great.
So he flew higher and higher...
until the sun melted his wings...
and he fell into the sea.
The US Army is not an irresponsible father.
So they gave us wings to fight hot **
Pennsylvania steel.
Guaranteed not to melt.
Oh wait, that's pretty, huh?
Let's take him low and level.
Fox Leader to Fox Group.
Clear up, survey as told.
Fox Seven, prepare set her on deck.
Copy Fox Leader. Proceedl to Zone Six.
Put us down over there.
Everyone else, stay with the team leader.
Gears, get it, Come on,
Let's move it!
READY SYSTEM
Ready for seismic **.
Roger that.
Fox Group, let it fly.
Copy all. Fox Three.
Heading 0-9-0.
Are you seeing what I seeing?
The seismic response is incredible.
Hey, Randy, you're not gonna believe this.
The bedrock,
It's practically hollow.
Incoming!
Look out!
On guard, Fox Five!
Fox Eight is down! Four Fox is down!
Respond, Fox Three!
Oh My God!
Does anyone know what that is?
I don't know, man. God dammit...
Three km west of **
Jesus! I never saw anything like it!
Roger.
Is that a monkey?
What the hell is that?
Somebody talk to me, man.
Turn right to 2-5-0.
Visual contact.
Fox Leader to Fox Group.
Form a perimeter. Ready gunners position.
Shit!
Fox leader to Fox Group. Fire at will!
- What the hell is that?
- I don't know!
Pull out now. Pull out.
I don't take orders from you!
Get us the hell out of here!
Fox Nine is down!
Fox Six, we got  trouble.
We are going down.
Fox Five, this is Fox leader.
Fox Nine is down.
1 klik north of the river bed.
Insert recovery team.
Fox Five is hovering.
We got men going out the door.
I need help here. I need...
Shit!
Kill this son of a bitch.
Pull up!
Brace for impact!
Mayday! Mayday!
Mayday!
Yourself, you idiot!
Watch out!
Oh God!
Prepare to crash!
Brace!
Fox Leader is down!
Fox Five in bound to pick up!
We have him in sight.
Hold tight, Colonel Packard,
We're on our way!
Hang on, Briggs. I'm coming.
Going down.
I repeat, we are going down!
Listen, I want you to tell
me something right now.
- Do you love your mama?
- I love her!
- How much do you love your mama?
- I love her so much.
Calling all units! Is anybody airborne?
I repeat, is anybody airborne?
They're all down. Everyone.
We are on the south side of the island.
There is a river a couple
of klicks from here.
If we sticks to its bank,
we make it to the EXFIL
site on the north shore.
And then what? All our choppers are down.
We'll find a way to signal the ship.
They'll send a search party.
We just have to make it by the exit window.
I should be sitting at a desk.
are we just not gonna talk about this?
My best guess is
we're scattered over 4 to 5 miles radius.
We must head north and join anyone we find.
Are you alright?
I don't know how to answer
that question right now.
I don't know what that was either.
All that money that they paid you?
I hope you're worth it.
You really not gonna talk about it?
You know, this is not normal, right?
Stuff like that doesn't just happen!
This is Fox Leader to Fox group.
Anybody with ears,
need respond.
Flex, Chapman.
Fox Six, Chapman.
Say again your last.
4 klicks west, the highest peak in..
November Alpha 3-0-0.
Out.
Roger that, Chapman.
West highest mountain peak.
Oliver.
Fox Six confirmed, we're the Sea Stallion.
Chapman, hold your position.
We will go to you. There is not
on that sea stallion to kill this thing.
Survey your perimeter.
Locate possible ambush sites. Over.
Chapman.
Reles.
Taking a non R day, you're good to go
I'm good to go sir, sir.
506 Get him up.
Chapman, all stations.
Recon the environment.
Cole, what's wrong with you?
How you even got an appetite right now?
Eating for living.
We just got taken down by a monkey
this size of a building!
Yeah!
That was an unconventional encounter.
Is that all your brain
telling yourself right now?
There was No tactical precedents.
We did the best we could in the situation.
Griffin. Cole.!
Thank God you guys are okay!
Good to see you, sir..
How many left?
Seven survivors.
Seven confirmed KIA.
Slivko, and the rest are Unknown.
Where is Randa?
How you doing?
I'm fine. Thank you.
Good.
Glad to hear it. I was worried about you.
You are going to tell me
everything I do not know...
or I'm gonna blow your head off.
Monsters exists.
No shit.
Nobody believed me.
Yesterday, I was a crackpot.
But today.
So, This was never about geology.
You dropped those charges
to flush something out.
Who are you?
You heard of the USS Lawton?
Neither did the public
Out of the thousand young men on the ship
I was the only survivor.
They told my family she
was sunk in battle...
but I know what I saw.
It had no conscience.
No reasoning, just destroy
I spent the last 30 years...
trying to prove the truth of what
I learned that day.
This planet doesn't belong to us.
ancient species owned this
earth long before mankind.
And if we keep our heads
buried in the sand...
they will take it back
My agency is known as Monarch.
We specialize in the hunt for
massive unidentified terrestrial organisms
You knew that thing was out here?
Sorry for your men, Colonel. I truly am.
Get us home with proof.
So we can send the cavalry.
I'm the cavalry.
It's called the Hollow Earth Theory.
Randa hired me...
because I wrote paper...
Substantiating what most people think
is a crackpot idea.
That there is this massive
underground species
- Isolated from the surface world.
- Has it ways.
Randa believed this island
may be one of those.
An emergence point for whatever lives below.
ancient species like what we just saw.
I thought he was out of his mind.
This is Slivko, do you read?
Anybody out there?
We are headed north of the ex fil location
Everyone here seems way too calm right now.
You copy?
Anybody?
We're out of range,
Slivko.
Shit.
Save it for when we get closer to the group.
Nobody move.
Easy.
- Silvko.
- What?
Put it down.
These men did not die in vain.
I swear to God...
Their deaths will not go unanswered.
Now, Let's get to Chapman
and those munitions.
You ever heard of the story of the
mouse, lion and the Thorn?
Yeah.
There you go then.
In case we have see that primate again.
You do know that the story is about a mouse
who turn a friend with a lion...
after taking out the thorn
out of his paw, right?
No it's not.
The mouse kills the lion with the thorn.
Who told you that, Cole?
My mother.
That actually explains a lot.
Watch out those tree!
- Let's go come on!
- What is that?
Watch your six!
Up In the trees!
Cole!
No!
We got you!
I can't get a shot!
Cut off the legs!
I have you!
Take it out, guys! Move out
Stay tight
What the hell is this?
Go, Behind you!
Stay Calm.
Conrad.
Stay back!
Guys.
Nobody shoot! Nobody shoot.
No. No need for that.
Come on now!
Everybody keep your wigs on now!
What?
I did not believe it
when they said you would come.
I was up all night...
Just thinking about how me and Gunpein
dreamt to this moment.
And now Here it is.
Twenty-eight years, 11 months...
8 failed attempts to get back to the world
and instead, the world comes to me?
Ain't that a fact?
They Never smile.
Did you Crash here?
Sorry miss.
Lt. Hank Marlow of the 45th.
You are more beautiful..
Than A hot dog and a beer...
At Wrigley Field on opening day.
But you are real.
Right?
I told you. Did not I tell you?
I Said...
"It's fine".
There you go.
There's something out there, man.
There is a lot out there.
Now, Come on. We gotta get home.
You don't want to be out here at night.
You probably noticed a lot of weird things
on this Island
As long as we stay in here,
where the people live, we'll be alright.
That wall...
Is that supposed to keep out that thing?
No, he's not the one
we're trying to keep out.
What?
These people live up in
the top of the trees,
while we are down in the roots.
Some of them don't even seem to age.
No crime...
No personal property.
They're past all that.
Thank you.
So Good news.
They say you can shack up here.
I didn't hear them say anything.
They don't speak too much.
been here as I long as I have,
you will start to understand, you'll see.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
We can not stay here.
We have to get off the island.
We have lives.
I have a life.
Nieves now is not the time. Alright?
What lands here tends to stay here.
As far as I can tell...
this ship washed up about 10 years
before I did.
You've been here since '44?
Yeah
And What happened with the war? Do we win?
Which one?
That Makes sense.
This is all halo ground to them.
So if you like your hands,
don't touch anything.
Look at that.
P s a g m e n o .com
The way they tell it,
for thousands of years...
the people of this island lived out of fear
It's hell of a long time to be scared.
And then one day,
the damnest thing happened.
Some of the things they were afraid of...
Started protecting against the things
that were eating them.
But nothing lasts forever, I guess.
And this is where they honor
the last of their saviors.
Yeah.
That's Kong.
He is king down here.
He is God to these people.
Kong is a pretty good king.
he's to himself mostly
This is him home. We are just guests here.
But you don't go into someone's house
and start dropping bombs...
unless you're picking a fight.
Was it Kong the one who killed your friend?
No.
One of them did.
Kong is God on the island...
but the devils live below us.
And what are they called?
The Iwis won't speak their name.
But I call skull crawlers.
Why?
Cause it's sounds unique.
Okay.
I just made that name up.
I am trying to scare you.
I'm trying calling them that.
- Are you feeling it?
- Yes...
- I like the name...
- It's very good.
I never said the name out loud,
Before It sounds stupid
now that I say just..
You Call them whatever you want.
Big lizard things. Nasty.
They come from the vents.
Deep down.
That's why Kong got so mad.
Cause bombs woke up a bunch of them.
I tell you what, you're luckey.
He's out there too
or you would not have made it this far.
Like crappy basterds. Neat as hell.
He can handle those...
You don't want to wake up the big one.
- How big is it?
- It's bigger than...
The White daughter's whole family.
Kong is the last of its kind
but he's still growing.
And you better hope he does.
Because the Iwis say once Kong goes...
Then the big one comes out.
And it's good night Irene.
Listen, There is a refueling team...
coming to the north end of the island
in three days.
You should come with us.
At the north end of the island?
We're gonna get out of here.
- In three days?
- Yes.
We can't get to the north end in three days.
It is impossible. That's it. No way.
At least not on our foot
That is one ugly ass bird.
Dear Billy...
this place is hell.
The monsters exists.
Under beds they sign to pay checks
- Come on, man.
- It seems like...
Maybe he want's to go kill that ape
instead of get ourselves out of here?
Yeah!
Are we gonna make it?
- Where?
- At the ex fil!
We getta be there in three days!
We'll make it, we're gonna make it.
Yeah, Cole but what happened to Chapman...?
Colonel said he is there.
he's there.
We were this close...
to get it working.
Gunpei and we're gonna take off
to the open sea trying to get home.
And one of that things got him.
There she is.
Well that's lovely.
Damn right.
Is this thing even float?
Me and Gunpei spent six years of our lives
to buliding this thing.
It is called the Great Fox.
And she floats.
I pulled the engine parts from my P-51...
His old Zero.
On a B-29 on the beach
one day out or something.
You gotta be kidding me.
This machine is made out of pure tetanus.
I know she isn't pretty to look at...
but it's nothing a couple
of extra hands can fix it.
Unless you got a better idea,
I suggest we get craking
Alright.
Come on, get up!
Well, look at that.
he Bleeds.
We did that.
We hook up with Chapman...
There is enough munition
on that down Sea Stallion...
to finish the job.
Magnificent.
You know why I carry
this instead of an M-16?
I took it off a farmer
who fight for the NVA.
He surrendered right after
we levelled his village.
He was 50 years old.
Saying that he haven't see a gun
till we showed up.
Sometimes, the enemy does not exist...
until you are looking for one.
What happens
when they show up on your door step?
I still have his gun.
Best of luck with that, soldier.
Okay. So they have got 48 hours
to make it to the North Shore.
Slivko, did you get to any back there?
Yeah, pop's a mechanic.
I can't fix this, he'll disown me.
He never sees me again.
Hold up on that, Churchill.
Russia was our ally.
Now You say we're at war with them?
It is more of a cold war.
The Cold War like...
That they take the summers off?
What about the Cubs?
The cubs owned a world series yet?
The Cubs?
No, not even close.
Were they ever good?
That must be my team. Where are you from?
- Detroit.
- Okay.
The tigers there.
They win all this year?
- I do not know.
- I doubt it. Yeah.
Hey, what do you think will win a fight?
A tiger or a Cub?
A tiger will win.
Yeah, because the puppies are babies.
A full grown tiger can eat a baby.
Think it through.
We also put a man on the moon.
No kidding
What did they do? Just leave him out there?
What's he eating?
Tang.
Come on, we are loosing.
Fox leader. this is Chapman, over.
Dear Billy...
Sometimes life just punch you in the balls
Dammit.
What kind of music is that?
What happened to swing?
Benny Goodman?
You're like a time traveler man.
Telling you, this is the new sound.
WRIGLEY FIELD HOME OF CHICAGO CUBS
I do not know if I'm gonna like
whoever is under this beard.
I really hope that thing you call a boat
can get us upriver in 36 hours.
Because if we miss that window...
We are rather literally off the grid.
When I first wrote that paper
on the Hollow Earth theory...
All committee laughed out loud
Not Randa.
The one guy in the crowd
who actually took me seriously.
It felt good.
Then I thought he was crazy
when he said these monsters.
I can't tell when I am talking...
- Or when I am not talking.
- You are talking.
- Really?
- Yes.
- I'm talking?
Your mouth is moving
What?
I'm gonna stab you for the end of the night.
Really?
Just kidding.
If the boat does not work,
we just take the train.
Is not it odd, most dangerous places,
aurora is the most beautiful?
I'm trying to take a
long exposure photograph
but my flashlight broke
Try this.
Thank you.
- Royal Air Force?
- My father's.
He threw it to me from the train
as he rolled off to fight with the Nazis.
It was like John Wayne to me.
Took our mythic hero.
Did he come back?
His plane went down near Hamburg.
They searched for him for months but...
I suppose no man comes home from war.
Not really.
Mills, quit dickin' around.
I going off perimeter.
Colonel Packard...
this mission to the crash site
I understand going after your man.
But the rest of it...
This is beyond us
You do not like the way I'm running things?
Then you know where the door is.
You set this in motion
when you put this place on the map.
And I will not cut and run.
I know an enemy when I see it.
This man's name was Gunpei Ikari.
If you take away the uniforms...
and the war...
Then he became my brother.
And we swore
we'd never leave each other behind
Let's get off this island.
Not yet!
- Behind the lines.
- Yes.
Bind it up, Let's go!
Keep going!
Third time's the charm.
Here we go.
let's go. let's go.
Come on.
Yes.
Yes!
I guess this is good bye.
Thank you.
If you're ever in Chicago,
look me up, I guess.
Yeah, no. Let me, let me help.
A man has gotta do what...
Are you okay?
I'm Okay, I'm okay.
Allow me.
You should see me in the library.
I got a wife.
Had a wife.
Have a wife?
I guess I don't know.
Got hitched right before I deplyed.
Got a telegram from her the day
before I got shot down.
She said we just had our baby boy.
I have a son out there.
Grown man I've never met
Yeah, she definitely thinks you're dead man.
Hey!
I'm just saying
You don't know that.
You'd be surprised how long people wait.
The truth is that
I do not expect him to be waiting.
That will be fine either way.
I just want one last chance to see them.
That would be good enough for me.
We are gonna get you home.
Fox Five, come back.
Is there anyone out there?
This is Fox Five. We hear you.
Yeah! We're on a boat...
- We're on a boat headed up north on river.
- A boat?
Where did you all get a boat?
We clean up, there is lika a crazy
Santa Clause, a time traveler.
Of World War II. You'll meet him.
What kind of boat?
It is more like a plane a boat really.
And it's called
We need that location Slivko.
Send up a flare so we could find you..
Roger that, Fox Five.
Fire in the hole!
There!
Yes!
I repeat, we have a visual.
2 clicks to our north.
Roger that, Fox Five. Fox One, out.
rendezvous point, in one hour.
Load up!
Can we fit everybody?
Yes!
We are going home!
Man Down!
What the hell, man?
He is gone.
Grab your gear. We have to keep moving.
We are going shore
meet up with Packard
No. Wait a minute!
Is nobody gonna say anything about the...?
He is gone!
And he ain't coming back.
There is nothing to say.
Oh my...
That flare was only 2 clicks north
They should be here soon.
Unless the were eaten by something
that's bigger than us.
Fuck!
Oh, shit.
Slivko!
I thought I'd not see you guys again.
- I thought you were crazy.
- I wish I had been.
- What's the count?
- What you see...
It is what we got.
We lost one too.
Good to see you fellas!
Who the hell is this?
Heads up to hitchhiker.
Lieutenant Hank Marlow
of the 45th suit sqaddron of the 15th.
You've been here since world war 2?
Yes sir. I missed the parade?
I'll be damned.
Lieutenant.
We're gonna get him home, sir.
We follow this river...
We'll make it to the boat,
we'll make it to the north shore in time.
That Sounds good.
But we're not leaving yet.
We still got a man out there, Conrad.
Wait a second. You got someone out there?
Chapman.
he is with the Down Sea Stallion,
Just west of it.
West? We can't go west!
That's where those skull things live.
We have a old saying here.
"East is best, west is worst!".
That's why we say it!
A little southwest...
We could talk about that
But we are gonna need a lot more guns
if we're gonna go west.
Guys. I think that we
should listen to Marlow.
This is crazy.
Hey.
Your job is find the lost men, right?
Okay, sir.
But if we reach that position,
and he is not there...
We don't send out a search party.
We're back here by nightfall, understood?
In 24 hours, we got to be
on the other side of this island.
Roger that. Hear you loud and clear.
You heard the man.
We're moving out in 10.
It's a good group of boys.
We are all gonna die together out here.
Good group of boys to die with.
I'll tell you that..
You should not have come to here.
when do you get to tell me
this is a bad idea?
This it a bad idea.
Yeah, you smell that?
It's death.
What the hell is this place?
This is what left of Kong's parents.
I have taken enough photos of mass graves,
to recognize one
The crash site is just only
other side of this valley
We'll cross through and
make it to the highest point west.
This place is a real no no, sir.
We need to be going to the
north side right now.
And you're welcome to do that, my man.
By your self.
I'm not leaving Jack out there.
Now, Who's with me?
We can make it.
Now stay sharp keep an eye out.
I've only got here 28 years. What do I know?
Cole...
Won't got time for that man.
Put the cigarette out.
Watch those fumes!
Idiots.
Let's go. We gotta move!
Run!
In Here!
Quite.
I told them to stand by
this was a no no.
Dammit.
Alright let's move.
Rather on me.
Somebody cover the civilians, quick
Let's Move!
Oh shit.
Randa!
Set up the 50!
Death before dishonor.
1045 Go!
Bring the torch! Do your thing!
Slivko!
Gas!
TOXIC GAS
Marlow!
The sword!
Slivko, Hang on!
This thing is moving!
Now look, Colonel.
You may out rank me...
but I've been here a hell a lot longer.
And I'm telling you...
that thing there just shredded us
was only the first of them
Now we are on their turf...
... And we need to turn back!
Turn sweet.
Not as long as Chapman still out there.
I'm Sorry, Colonel Packard.
Chapman is dead.
Nothing changes then!
We're still going to that crash site.
What's that in the crash site
that you want so badly?
Weapons!
Enough to kill it.
Kong didn't kill Chapman.
But It did kill these men!
My men!
You can't kill Kong, Colonel.
Kong is God on this island.
It is the only thing
keeping that lizard things underground.
He's right, Colonel. We can't kill Kong.
And that other creature?
That's the threat.
And there are more of them down here.
If you take away
that species' natural competition
they will proliferate out of control.
Then we will end them too!
After we bring this thing down.
I can not let you do that.
Wait! Hold your fire.
This is one war, we're not gonna loose.
It's nuts!
You hear me? This is nuts!
Please! You need to listen to him!
We are not at war, Colonel.
You are making a mistake.
Your lies got my men killed!
- And you're gonna get us all killed.
- It's not our fight.
Whose side are you on, Captain?
Okay, Colonel.
You will find your Sea Stallion
3 click off that ridge
Now, I'm gonna take these civillians
back to the boat.
And we wait for you there.
Alright?
Saddle up!
Let's go kill this thing!
Steve...
You running with the big dogs or
stayin' on the boat?
I don't wanna be on that.
Marlow, You okay?
We need to stop him.
You want to talk off him about it agian?
He seemed really good for it first time.
He is losing his grip.
Follow me...
We'll be off this rock alive.
Dear Billy...
I'm trying to get home with you and Mom.
Be strong.
I love you.
Make sure those get back to his family.
Dear Billy...
Your dad was one of the best.
There is a water close by.
Are you lost? Which way?
Hang on.
Wait here.
Gonna get to high ground to find the river.
Hey! I'm coming too.
I'll be right here.
Keep your eyes open.
Up in the trees, too.
Why?
Ants.
Big ones.
There's one.
It sounds like a bird,
but it's a fucking ant.
Gather up everything you can,
including those seismic charges.
They got us attention the first time.
This is a bad idea.
Let's just get on with it
Mills, Cole...
Prep this ordnance.
Make him a special gift out of that Naplam.
The boat must be around that bent.
We have to go,
Now.
Don't shoot!
Conrad, which way were you going?
You said you need to
get back to the boat.
It's that way.
Wait for us till dawn.
If you aren't back by then...
Just go.
Where are you two going?
We gotta save Kong.
Not without me, man.
Oh God.
Men!
Place the chargers.
It's time to show Kong...
... That man is king!
On one.
On Two.
On three.
Packard!
Don't do it.
Asked you fellas nice the first time.
We don't want to fight here, Packard.
This this brought us down! He killed my men!
Kong was just defending its territory.
We are soldiers!
We do the dirty work!
So our families and our countrymen
don't have to be afraid!
They should not even know that
a thing like this exists!
You've lost your mind.
Put that detonator down.
Stop!
The world is bigger than this.
Bitch, please!
Slivko, get it out of there!
You know it's the wrong thing to do, son.
Put it down, sir.
Packard!
Come on.
It's over.
That's the big one.
Fall back.
Go!
Colonel.
Sir!
Die motherfucker...
- Kong.
- Kong's down. Let's go!
They told us to leave at dawn
- I know.
- It's dawn.
I know!
So what are we going to do?
This is the edge of the island.
Weaver, get up on those
rocks and fire a flare.
Well, then like, Brooks will see it.
I will buy you time.
This way.
Come on.
Every second counts.
Cole!
Come on, man, we gotta fall back.
Go live your life.
Get out of here.
- Cole, no!
- Cole!
Cole, no!
No, don't!
Cole!
Come on. Come on.
You son of a bitch.
Come on! Run!
Come on!
Run!
Come on! Hurry!
Come on!
Marlow, will you help me?
- Clear!
- Okay!
Come on, Basterd!
Weaver!
Weaver?
hey, hey hey!
You're okay?
So what do you think fellas?
This went to Key West?
I think it is, brother.
This place will change.
Word will get out.
It always does.
No, it's not coming from us.
We will meet again.
Don't know when.
But I know we'll meet again.
Subtitled by Asmita/Biohapzard
Psagmeno.com
Subtitles/Trailers/Screenshots
If you want to see a cub go crazy...
see what happens if this guy gets paid well.
High ball, great hit.
An the impossible dream
just became possible!