We get the wheels,
we get la feria,
we keep moving on.
No messing around.
You mess those wheels up
this time, Chong,
I'm gonna have your ass.
Move!
- Right there, homes.
- There's nobody, homes.
Where's your party, boy?
Turn down the radio.
You inviting the cops, too,
or what?
I want El cromo.
Gonna get some green
for this shit
right here, homes.
Fuck.
Hey.
Uh, guys?
Those are chrome-plated lugs.
You're gonna strip them.
Look at this guy, eh?
The plating flakes off.
Yeah?
This is a lease.
No one's gonna pay to ride...
Shit.
Come on, man.
Uh, guys, guys.
What the fuck?
Guys, seriously,
you don't wanna do this.
Take him out.
Fuck him up!
No! Not the car!
Get that puto!
Fuck him up, man!
Fuck him up!
Get him!
Hit that fool!
Motherfucker!
Shit.
Fuck.
Everyone's asleep, Burt.
Sleepwalking.
Between the ice caps,
the pornographers,
poisoned water, mutants...
it's all connected.
Hey, Clyde. It's 2029.
Why are we still
talking about mutants?
Hey, it's me. I'm in the car.
Yeah, it was a good trip.
Killed it up and down
the fence.
USA! USA! USA!
USA! USA! USA! USA!
Wolverine.
I knew it was you.
Oh, fuck.
Please!
I'm in trouble!
You're the only one
that could help!
Get the fuck away from me!
Please!
Logan!
Who was that?
I don't know, some crazy lady.
Don't worry.
As I live and breathe,
the Wolverine.
And he's a junkie now.
Who the fuck are you?
You know, you got some
buckshot in your door.
I heard you was in Phoenix.
But then, last night,
some friends of mine
in Texas HP called...
and told me they found
3 dead cholos
in a pullout on 54.
Not unusual, I know.
Except one was missing a hand,
another one a leg.
So they was thinking...
it was either an escaped
tiger or Freddy Krueger.
But neither one of them
can drive...
one being fictional,
the other one extinct.
And since the wheel lugs
they found
belonged to
a '24 Chrysler...
and, well...
this is a '24 Chrysler.
She found you yet?
Gabriela?
See...
I'm not looking for you,
Wolvie.
Well, not really.
I'm looking for someone
who's looking for you.
She took something of mine
when I wasn't looking.
Something for which
I am responsible.
Mexican lady.
Has her sights
on you now.
Doesn't ring any bells?
I don't know any Gabriela,
so get the fuck
out of my car.
Oh.
You know...
I know
what you're hiding, amigo.
The old cue ball
south of the border.
What do you want?
A little co-operation.
I'm a fan, by the way.
Fuck, fuck!
No, Mr. Esperanza, no.
I know I said June,
but I need the boat now.
Why would that mean
the price go up?
Listen to me.
I know you wanted 70...
Okay, what if I could
put together
$45,000 cash right now?
Hello? Hello?
Shit.
Hey, Sam.
Morning.
"I know that virtue
to be in you, Brutus.
"As well as I do know
your outward favor.
"Well, honor is the subject
of my story."
He's having a bad day.
They're all bad days.
He needed these
6 hours ago.
This is not enough,
you know.
Won't see us
through the week.
I'm working on it.
Your turn.
I've had a rough night.
Poor you.
In other news,
he told me last night
he's communicating
with someone.
He's not talking
to anybody.
Don't be so sure.
He's got all these details.
I thought that tank was
supposed to act as a barrier.
It's got them cracks in it.
Just please stop.
Bottom left.
You're not listening.
He's been asking questions
again about why we're here.
I think he's trying to
read my mind.
That's what
these are for.
Eating his curds and whey
Then came a big spider
Which sat down beside her
And frightened Miss Muffet...
Friends, I have
good news for you today!
It's not about what you do.
It's not about your deeds.
You can't
live up to God's rules.
He knows that you can't.
It's okay, we're imperfect.
Make way, sir.
I said make way!
The new Quesalupa
from Taco Bell!
Get it with chicken!
Get it with steak!
And with the cheese baked
right in the shell...
it's the next big thing!
Go now while supplies last.
Who are you?
You know who I am.
You're the man
who puts me to sleep.
We both could use
some sleep.
No! No!
What are you doing to me?
Charles.
Come on, now.
How long have I been here?
What are these?
You remember
what they are.
The shots
mellow the seizures.
The pills
keep them from happening.
How about you blow on them
to make them safe?
Fuck off, Logan.
So you remember
who I am now.
I always know who you are.
It's just sometimes
I don't recognize you.
Take the pills.
You leave me alone
with that fucking albino.
He doesn't listen to me.
I know a damn speciation
when I see one.
A what?
Speciation.
New mutant, a young one.
There are forces
trying to kill them.
Forces?
They want help.
Forces, forces.
It's too bad you're not
in that business anymore.
They don't want me,
they want you.
Oh, yes, that's how
fucking stupid they are.
They're waiting for you
at the Statue of Liberty.
The Statue of Liberty
was a long time ago,
Charles, a long time.
There are no new mutants.
Understand?
Hasn't been a new one born
in 25 years. Not anywhere.
You always thought...
we were part of God's plan.
But maybe...
Maybe we were God's mistake.
What a disappointment
you are.
When I found you...
you were pursuing a career
as a cage fighter.
A warm capper to a life
as an assassin.
Hooked on barbiturates.
You were an animal.
But we took you in.
I gave you a family.
And they're gone now.
Logan.
Logan...
What did you do?
Answer me!
Why are we here?
No one should live
like this.
Drugged in a fucking tank!
It's for your own good.
No, it's not!
You're waiting for me
to die.
I don't wanna fight...
but there's things
we need to discuss.
What things?
Well, would it be
considered nagging...
if I was to repeat
my previous observation...
that the dose is too low
to suppress the seizures?
It's what the guy gave me.
Wasn't in a position
to make demands.
I almost died this morning.
That seizure was...
It was barely a minute.
It felt a lot longer than a minute.
I couldn't breathe.
You're less affected.
You know
he needs a higher dose.
And I know you got more
money squirreled away.
That money's
to get us out of here.
No, not us.
You and him.
You're saving
to buy a Sunseeker.
"Sun" is the keyword.
I hardly see myself cowering
below decks like Nosferatu.
Do you?
Folding your underpants,
and making him spotted dick.
Found this in your pocket.
Adamantium.
If you are planning
to blow your brains out...
could you wait till you're
out on the high seas?
I just mopped
these floors.
I don't need this shit.
A year ago, you asked
me to help you.
And God knows
I've tried.
But I can't help you,
Logan, not really...
if you're not
going to talk to me.
I hear you at night.
You're not sleeping.
You don't wanna
talk about that.
Or the booze
you're drinking.
Or the pus you're wiping
away from your knuckles.
Or the blood
I wash from your clothes.
Or the fresh wounds
in your chest.
The ones
that aren't healing.
And I'm pretty sure...
you don't wanna talk
about the fact
that you can't read
the label on that bottle.
It says, "Ibuprofen."
That was my favorite mug.
Stay out of my shit.
Something's happening
to you, Logan.
On the inside you're sick.
I can smell it.
Best night ever!
Hey, driver.
I love you.
You're such a doll.
Mr. Logan.
Oh, Jesus.
Please. We need a ride.
Not available.
Call a cab.
My name
is Gabriela Lopez.
I don't wanna
know your name, lady.
There are men after us.
We need to get out of here.
Go north,
cross to Canada.
Anyone can do that job.
I'll give you $50,000.
How did you find me, huh?
'Cause you are fucking up
my life, lady!
The people after you,
they're on my ass now!
Sightings were posted.
Laura, go inside.
What sightings?
People said someone who
looked like the Wolverine
was in El Paso, driving.
Said he looked old.
Hey!
I told you
to stop it with that ball!
Bad girl!
No, please.
I told you, bad girl!
Mamacita's gonna
have to pay for that.
Stop, please. No.
Shit!
They're gonna
have to pay for damages.
And she has cash.
I've seen it.
You should get your fat ass
back in your office.
You'll get your money.
Don't let her call anyone,
please.
They will find us.
They will kill us.
I am a nurse.
Was. In Mexico City.
When did that happen?
This morning.
Near the border.
I got away
from them, but...
...now they know my car.
Look, I gotta go.
No, wait. Please. Here.
Please, wait! Look.
Look. Here, take this.
It's $20,000.
Here. Take us
to this address.
You can have $30,000 more
when we get there.
My friends there
will give it to you.
They will be waiting.
They will give you anything.
Where did you get this?
My boyfriend.
He wants to kill me
and take her.
And that's your daughter?
Yes.
I know
you're still good inside.
I know you want to help us.
You don't know
anything about me.
Please!
I promise, there will be
no problems if we leave now.
I can't just leave
to North Dakota!
We have to be there Friday.
Or what?
Or we miss our chance
to cross.
Please.
You have to. Please.
I like those.
Huh?
They make you look younger.
Charles, listen.
I gotta go away
for a few days, okay?
I got a long ride
for some good money...
but when I get back,
we're gonna get outta here.
We're gonna
drive down to Yelapa.
get ourselves a boat.
And we're gonna
go live on the ocean.
Will you be safe there?
Yeah. We'll be safe.
Look what Logan got us,
Charles.
Be back
in a few days.
Shit.
Logan.
Yeah?
What happened?
Did something go wrong?
The job was wrong
to begin with.
Logan!
What?
Who does this belong to?
Who's that?
Thought you were supposed to
see shit coming.
I can track mutants.
I'm a glorified truffle pig,
not a clairvoyant.
Go inside
and keep Charles quiet.
Go inside now!
You need to turn around,
asshole.
This is private property.
Yes, it is.
In fact,
I believe it belongs
to a multinational
smelting company...
based in Shanghai.
Where are you keeping
the old man? Hmm?
Is he over there?
Or is he there?
That'd be smart.
I'd like to meet him.
I'm told the HSA
classifies his brain
as a weapon
of mass destruction now.
Damn shame,
what happened back east.
He's been dead for a year.
I need the girl.
What girl?
The one that goes along with
that ball you're holding.
There's no girl here.
I know you went
to the motel.
Yeah, I was called there.
There was no girl.
It was just the woman.
Just the woman.
Such as she was.
So, you saw Gabriela.
But you didn't call me.
That hurts.
You didn't shoot
the poor thing, did you?
No, did you?
I asked you first.
I don't like guns.
Of course.
I wish
you'd called me, Logan.
Like I asked.
See?
You're not the only one
that's been enhanced.
Logan. Logan!
This is Laura.
Caliban, come!
This is who
I've been telling you about.
This is Laura.
We've been waiting for you.
Come, come here.
It's okay.
Come.
Laura.
It's okay. It's okay.
Come.
Come. It's okay.
You can stay here, Laura.
It's safe.
We can look after you here.
Come on.
Looks like ex-military.
Bounty hunter, maybe?
Worse.
Is he by himself?
Yeah, not for long.
You get him back
in his ride,
take him out to the wash
and dump him.
What if he wakes up
before I get there?
Text me where you are.
We'll pick you up.
Yes.
Logan.
Hey. Hey!
You'll get it back
after I figure out
what you and your mother
have got us into.
No, Logan.
What?
I think the...
Logan, the woman that you met,
that's not her mother.
So she talks?
We're communicating.
Communicating.
Take these now.
We have to get out of here.
It's not safe here anymore.
And you can't have an attack
out there, you understand?
Yes, but this is the mutant
that I told you about.
She needs our help.
She's not a mutant.
Yes, she is!
What's her gift, Charles?
Eating? Pipe throwing?
It's okay.
Oh, yeah.
Take the gun.
Dump the body.
Text me when you're
on the way back.
You have anything else
you need?
Food for the kid?
You're fucked now, mutie.
It's okay.
- Choo-choo.
- It's not a choo-choo.
It's okay. Sit down.
We gotta go.
What?
What's going on? Where?
Stay here.
Don't move.
Where are we going?
Hey, don't worry.
He will be back for you.
Logan, the girl. You've got
to go back for the girl.
Logan, what about the girl?
Logan.
Logan, we mustn't forget
about Laura.
She's not our problem.
Shit!
Ah, shit!
Logan.
Yeah, I'm thinking.
The child.
Logan,
we mustn't forget Laura.
Please be quiet.
Logan.
Huh.
Charles Xavier.
Where's Caliban?
America's most wanted
octogenarian.
I'm a nonagenarian,
actually.
Ah.
Where's Caliban?
Why don't you tell me
where the girl is first?
Or I could ask Cue Ball.
He seems quite friendly.
I told you,
she's not here.
Where's Caliban,
motherfucker?
Well, I left him
in the same ditch
he was gonna leave me in.
Jesus, Wolverine,
seeing you like this
just breaks my damn heart.
As soon as I rip it out
of your chest, fuck-stick.
Go get her.
Laura.
That a girl!
Hey, baby.
Laura...
Laura!
Honey, you wanna stay
where you are.
You wanna see
your friends, right?
Command, stop.
You said alive or dead.
Laura!
Laura.
No. No.
Move! Go!
Stop shooting!
She heals! Move! Go!
Holy shit!
Gotcha!
Ah!
Come on, hold her down.
As I told you, Logan,
she's a mutant like you.
Hold on!
Very much like you.
Laura, are you all right?
Ahh!
Move!
Hold on!
Fuck! Come on!
Come on!
Shit.
Fall in! Let's go!
Oh, watch out!
Ah!
Sit back.
Bring me the tracker.
You.
Who the hell are you?
Hey! I asked you a question.
Who are you?
You know
who she is, Logan.
No, I don't.
Does she remind you
of anybody?
I read about you
when I was a kid.
I believe you're thinking
of someone else.
Hmm.
Now, if I'm not mistaken,
you used to work for my team.
You were helping round up
all those old mutes.
What changed?
You got religion?
I'm gonna need you to do
one more thing
for the good guys...
and track one more
special mute for me.
I'm not helping you.
Of course, you'd say that.
But I got a theory that
people don't really change.
Beware of the light.
Caliban, I bet that's what
your mama told you
every day when you was a kid.
Beware of the light.
Now, let's not bring out
the worst in each other.
The girl is not worth it,
trust me.
She's not a natural fuck-up
like you.
She's a business mistake,
a R&D gone bad.
There's liability.
They can't have things
with patents
running around,
hurting people, can they?
We need to get her off the board
before she hurts anybody else.
Someone you care about, maybe.
So, get to sniffin'.
My name is Gabriela Lopez.
I am a nurse.
And for 10 years, I worked for
Transigen Research
in Mexico City.
Transigen is owned
by an American company.
What I am about to show you
is illegal...
in the U.S. and Canada.
They told us we were part
of a pharmaceutical study.
But, of course, that was a lie.
These children
were born in Transigen.
They were born here...
and have never left.
They have never seen
the sun or the ocean...
rain or snow...
or any of God's creatures.
They have no
birth certificates...
no names...
besides the ones
we have given them.
They were raised in the
bellies of Mexican girls.
Girls no one
can find anymore.
Their fathers are
semillas geneticas...
special seeds in bottles.
- Birthday? No birth.
- Maria.
We do not dress them up
for Halloween.
We do not call them "baby"
or kiss boo-boos.
Don't think of them
as children.
Think of them as things...
with patents
and copyrights.
Comprende?
Si, senor.
They thought
we were too poor
and stupid to understand.
We're poor, yes...
but we are not stupid.
Use your powers.
This is business.
They are making soldiers.
Killers.
These are babies
of mutantes...
North Dakota.
Mmm.
You took that woman's money.
You said you would take
the child there.
What is she?
She's your daughter, Logan.
Alkali has your genetic code.
Not just mine.
Logan...
I don't want to talk
about it.
I don't wanna hear
about it anymore.
Logan...
Just stop.
I have to pee.
Last ride.
You're welcome.
Stop it.
For God's sake,
I can do this myself!
Yeah, well,
you're not doing it.
Just get on with it.
Not with you
standing there.
Trust me,
I'm not lookin'.
Hello.
Hi, there!
You know you gotta pay
for that, right?
Hey! Where's your
mommy and daddy, huh?
Come on.
That's enough. These, too.
Shit!
Not okay!
Sorry.
Um, do you sell
phone chargers?
Uh...
Come on. Get in the car.
As the children
became older...
Laura. Laura.
...they became
more difficult.
They could not
be controlled.
The company made their bodies
into weapons.
Tried to teach them to kill.
But they did not
want to fight.
A soldier who will not fight
is useless.
Inside this building...
they are working on
something new.
Something they think
is better than the children.
Something they say
is without a soul.
Would you like to hear
my full lab report, Dr. Rice?
You can't get
good sushi here.
It's the Mexican equivalent
of Denver, Colorado.
They must have
been successful.
About a week ago, they told
us to shut our program down.
They started putting
the children to sleep.
We are going to save
as many children as we can.
I read about a place,
up north.
A place for mutants.
They call it Eden.
If you are watching this...
it means that I am dead.
I am not sure if
any other children survived.
We were separated.
There is no more money.
That was a lie.
She's not my child.
But I love her.
You may not love her.
But she is your child.
Please. I beg you...
take her to safety.
Is this where
we're hiding out?
We're not hiding out.
We're gonna get
a couple of hours' sleep...
clean up,
get some new clothes,
get a new ride
and get outta here.
Harrah's Hotel and Casino
welcomes you
to Oklahoma City.
Please keep right
for valet parking.
Hey.
The fun never stops at
Harrah's Hotel and Casino.
Hey, keep it out front,
all right?
Come on, let's go.
Hey, Laura.
Let's go.
We need clothes.
Going up.
No, no, stop. Not a toy.
Uh, no, no, sorry, chair.
What? Okay.
Push up again.
Thank you.
Going up.
Come here. Stand there.
Just stand there.
Logan, it's yours.
What?
I'm not gonna wear it now.
In the room. We'll get
changed in the room.
You're a low-down,
lying Yankee.
Prove it.
This is a very
famous picture, Laura.
It's almost 100 years old.
In life,
in death, oh, Lord
Abide with me
I first saw this picture
at the Essoldo Cinema
in my hometown...
when I was your age.
...who art in heaven
Hallowed be thy name
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done
Shit.
I've heard
that you're a low-down,
Yankee liar.
Prove it.
You read these
in your spare time?
Oh, yeah, Charles,
we got ourselves an X-Men fan.
You do know
they're all bullshit, right?
Maybe a quarter of it
happened, and not like this.
In the real world,
people die.
And no self-promoting asshole
in a fucking leotard
can stop it.
This is ice cream for bed-wetters.
Logan...
Her nurse has been feeding
her some grade-A bullshit.
I don't think
Laura needs reminding
of life's impermanence.
Didn't you say something about
finding us a new ride?
Two more pills
in 1 hour.
Give 'em to him.
Why, Shane?
A man has to be
what he is, Joey.
Can't break the mold.
I tried it
and it didn't work for me.
Joey, there's no living
with a killing.
There's no going back
from one.
Right or wrong,
it's a brand.
A brand sticks.
Now you run on home
to your mother,
and tell her
everything's all right.
And there aren't any more
guns in the valley.
Who are you guys?
More cops? 'Cause I told
the other guys
everything that I...
Get up!
In your cage, tracker.
You did your job.
Fellas.
Shit.
Knock yourselves out.
I'll tell you what.
8 grand...
I'll have her freshly painted
for you, new tires...
mounted, balanced,
and complete paperwork.
I'll give you 10 as-is,
if you can forget
the paperwork.
Well, you still need new
tires, man, they're bald.
How long will that take?
An hour.
Jesus.
You gotta be
fucking kidding me.
Sir, are the keys in...
Sir!
You have
the keys in it? Sir!
Shit!
Charles. Charles!
Argh!
Going up.
Oh, shit!
You all right?
We gotta get outta here.
I'm so sorry.
Emergency
personnel are still on scene
at Harrah's Casino Hotel
in Oklahoma City...
where at least 400 guests
were stricken
with temporary paralysis
yesterday.
Many are noting
a similarity
to the Westchester incident
over a year ago...
that left
over 600 injured...
and took the lives
of 7 mutants,
including several
of the X-Men.
Knock it off.
I said, knock it off!
She's a child, Logan.
And, point of fact,
she's your...
How long has it been
since you took your meds?
Tell me,
how long has it been?
I don't know!
2 days.
You saw
what happened yesterday.
If that shit
had gone on any longer,
everyone in that casino...
I did what I had to do
to save Laura.
You didn't do anything.
You just freaked out
and had a fucking seizure!
I guess you prefer me
pharmaceutically castrated,
rambling on like a lunatic.
So much easier for you.
Easier? Jesus!
There is nothing easy
about you, Charles, nothing!
Yes, yes, please be
like the rest of the world...
blaming someone else
for your boring shit.
I know, Pop, I'm such
a giant disappointment.
You honestly derive
no sense of purpose...
from what we're doing?
Okay, what are we doing?
Hmm?
There is a young mutant
sitting in our car.
Yeah, I see that.
And where we're taking her,
there are others.
Does that mean nothing
to you?
Yeah, means nothing to me.
Especially since
Nurse Gabriela...
made all that Eden shit up
with fucking comic books.
What are you
talking about?
Give those to him,
will you?
Take out two pills
and give them to him.
Logan! Logan!
Give 'em to him.
Now!
I wanna see it.
Dr. Rice.
It's under control...
Motherfucking auto-trucks.
Language, Logan.
And you're screaming
at a machine.
Oh, what? She can gut a man
with her feet,
she can't hear
a few naughty words, huh?
She can learn
to be better.
You mean, better than me?
Actually, yes.
And, by the way,
Laura's foot claws...
are the obvious result
of her gender, you know.
Is that a fact?
In a pride of lions,
the female...
is both hunter
and caregiver.
Good to know.
She uses her front claws
for hunting...
and the back claws
defensively.
Oh, yeah?
Thus,
ensuring their survival.
Hey, hey!
We should help them.
No, we have to keep going.
Someone will come along.
Someone has come along.
Alert. Alert.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, uh, you need a hand?
Ready? Go!
Ah. Good, got it.
Come on, let's get home.
Laura!
Thank you so much
for your help.
I'm Kathryn.
James.
This is my son, Nate.
Hi.
Hey.
That's your daughter?
Yeah, that's Laura,
and that's my dad...
Chuck.
Come on, Laura, let's go.
Well, can we show
our appreciation
and treat the three of you
to a decent meal?
We don't live far from here.
Uh, no, thanks.
That would be lovely!
My name is Dr. Rice.
But you can call me Zander
if you like.
My colleague tells me
you've been
somewhat resistant.
He believes you've been
dispensing
delayed information...
to allow your friends
to stay one step ahead.
I'm offering you
the possibility
of redemption, Caliban.
To protect the world,
and in the process,
save your friends.
The girl is a rather
small price to pay for that.
Unlike you, she's impure.
She wasn't made by nature.
She's a mistake of my own.
I did what I could
and they burned me
and beat me.
Your colleagues are savages.
I agree.
The Reavers
were very ineffective.
But I'm bringing
new tools to bear.
But I still need someone
to point us
in the right direction.
No, I can't help you.
Breathe, breathe.
Now, what does he have?
The old man.
Alzheimer's? ALS?
A degenerative brain disease
in the world's most
dangerous brain?
What a combo.
Be nice.
Now, you know we got company.
That's wonderful.
Everybody, have a seat.
Nate, sit up.
James, why don't you sit
at the end of the table?
You wanna say grace?
Say grace, baby.
Uh, thank you, God,
for this food...
and for our new friends,
the Howletts.
Mmm. They came
to our aid.
Amen.
Here we go.
Here you go, Charles.
Thank you, sir.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, there's plenty more
if she wants.
She's fine. Thank you.
This is delicious.
- Oh, thank you.
- It's so good.
Where are you all headed?
Uh... Oregon.
South Dakota.
Um...
Well, Oregon
and then South Dakota.
Vacation?
Uh... Yes.
Uh, long overdue.
We're city folk.
Always wanted to take a road trip,
see the country.
Um... And meet
the people in it.
That sounds lovely.
Been trying
to get Will here
to take a vacation
for years now.
Oh. If we go traipsing
all over the country,
who's gonna take care
of this place?
Exactly.
I say, let it go.
And live off what?
The Lord will provide.
I'm still waiting for
the Lord to provide me
with a new thresher.
All the same,
I'd love to travel someday.
And I bet you will.
I could drop
out of school.
Okay, let's not go
that far.
I mean, I'll do it.
- No. No.
- Why not?
You wanna travel,
I wanna travel.
Son. Son.
That sounds good
to you, right?
This is the perfect plan.
Why would you want
to do that, Nate?
Careful, you're speaking to
a man who ran a school...
for a lot of years.
Right, Charles?
Yes, it was a...
It was a special needs
school. Um...
Uh-huh.
That's a good description.
He was there, too.
Oh, yeah, no. Um...
I got kicked out a few times.
I wish I could say
you were a good pupil,
but the words
would choke me.
Ma'am, I can't thank you
enough for this.
Uh, it was great.
But we have a long drive
ahead of us, so...
But you need to rest,
don't you?
Yeah, we'll find
a motel somewhere.
The nearest one
is two hours from here
and it's not even
that nice.
We have a perfectly fine
room upstairs
for your father
and your daughter and
you can sleep in the living
room on the convertible.
Kathryn, it's very,
very nice of you,
but we really should go.
We can leave
early in the morning.
Break of dawn,
as it were.
Okay, why don't we
wash up, Pop?
Okay.
Sit.
Um, sweetie,
you want some dessert?
2 days on the road,
only one meal,
and hardly any sleep.
She's 11, I'm fucking 90.
Well, that's 101 reasons
to keep moving.
I'm not a box
of avocados, Logan.
And then what?
We stay the night, then what?
Then we take her to
her friends in Eden.
And then we buy
the Sunseeker.
Take the pills.
Oh, shit!
What's going on?
Nate!
Go fill up the tub
before we lose pressure.
Honey, check the sink.
They shut it off again.
They are just not going to
let this thing go.
Well, you might as well
handle it now.
It can wait till the morning.
We just had rain last night.
We got 3 houseguests
and a sink full of dishes.
All right, all right.
The pump station
that supplies us
is a mile
and a half from here.
Sometimes it gets itself
shut off.
- By assholes.
- Hey!
No.
My son is happy
to go with you.
No, no, no,
that's fine.
The men that do this,
sometimes they can be...
I can go.
No, you got homework.
All right, I'll go.
Just, uh,
let me get my dad settled.
All right.
I'm just saying,
I don't care what the lawyer says.
But it's dangerous.
I'm not gonna hurt
our chances.
Want TV? There's TV here.
I'm fine.
Okay. Get some rest.
You know, Logan...
this is what life
looks like.
A home,
people who love each other.
Safe place.
You should
take a moment and feel it.
Yeah. It's great.
Logan. Logan!
You still have time.
Charles, the world is not
the same as it was.
We're taking a risk hanging
around here, you know that.
And where
we're going, Eden...
it doesn't exist.
Her nurse got it
from a comic book.
You understand?
It's not real.
It is for Laura.
Get some rest.
Canewood Beverage bought up
everything out here,
except for us.
When we wouldn't sell,
they tried eminent domain...
then screwing
with our water.
Couple of months ago,
somebody poisoned our dogs.
So, out on the highway
today, those trucks...
Who knows. Maybe.
Hey, look at 'em.
Look like dinosaurs
with their 20-ton bodies
and tiny little brains...
shucking their cloned-up
super corn.
You know it tastes
like shit, too.
Why do people eat it?
They don't. They drink it.
Corn syrup.
It's in those drinks
that everyone's having...
to stay awake, cheer up,
feel strong, sexy, whatever.
Used to be a time when a bad
day was just a bad day.
Mine still are.
Those are for
breakaway roping.
barrel racing...
and right here
is for pole bending.
They're all second,
third place.
I'm not too good at it,
but my dad makes me.
Do you want to listen?
Do you like it?
Um, here, you can
take it for tonight...
and I'll get it back
from you in the morning.
Looks like we're gonna
be here a while.
Should hold it.
Yeah.
Till next time.
Thanks.
Hey, so, uh,
how long has your girl
been like that?
Huh?
Mute.
Uh, since the beginning.
Mmm.
Well, in a lot of ways,
I envy you.
They get to be Nate's age,
with the nonsense that comes
out of their mouths...
Makes you wonder the
whole point of it all.
Shit.
Don't worry.
We won't need it.
Stay here.
Evening, Mr. Munson.
What brings y'all
this way?
Why don't you ask
your boys?
Mr. Munson,
you understand you're
trespassing right now, right?
I have an easement with
the previous owner
of your property.
Huh. Bullshit.
"Previous" being
the operative word.
Who's this?
Just a guy telling you
to get back
in your nice truck.
Go play Okie dickhead
somewhere else.
Hey, Carl...
it looks like Mr. Munson
hired some muscle.
Looks that way.
He's a friend of mine.
A friend with a big mouth.
I hear that a lot.
Then you probably
hear this, too.
More than I'd like.
Then you know the drill.
I'mma count to three...
and you're gonna
start walking away.
I got rights
to this water.
1.
I have a lawyer now.
2.
3.
Ah. Ah.
You all right, boss?
- You know the drill.
- Pick up my goddamn hat.
Get the hell out of here.
You okay, boss?
Fuck off.
Go!
You've had training.
Some.
Hey, don't wake her yet.
Let her sleep another hour.
You know, Logan...
this was, without a doubt...
the most perfect night
I've had in a very long time.
But I don't deserve it.
Do I?
I did something.
Something unspeakable.
I've remembered
what happened in Westchester.
This is not the first time
I've hurt people.
Until today, I didn't know.
You wouldn't tell me.
So we just kept on
running away from it.
I think I finally
understand you.
Logan...
He's fantastic.
You said you only needed
the girl!
I told you I was forced
to bring a new tool to bear.
Your friends
had every chance.
And so did you.
Nate?
Put her down.
Honey.
Stay down there, Will!
Stop!
Kathryn!
Charles!
Hold this.
It wasn't me.
Here he comes.
I could pick him up,
meet him halfway.
No, no, no.
Let them come to us.
We struggled
with the X-23s.
We assumed,
because they were children...
we could raise them
without a conscience.
But you can't nurture rage.
You must simply design it...
from scratch.
Who the fuck is that?
Will Munson!
Just hold on, Charles.
Munson,
God damn it, come out here!
Munson!
Come out here now!
Come out here now, Munson.
There's that asshole.
Hello, asshole.
Listen, I'm willing
to let bygones be bygones.
I don't know what
Munson's paying you...
but Canewood can start
you out at 5 G.
A week, that is.
You best stay
where you are, pal.
I'm the law out here.
No, no, no.
What in high...
What? Oh, shit!
Shoot him!
We need to intervene.
Well, he only listens
to you, Doctor.
24!
Get back here!
Stop! Stop now!
Hold this down,
right now, tight!
Our boat.
What?
The Sunseeker.
No.
Come!
24!
Need some help
out here!
I guess we're gonna have to
take care of this now.
- Pierce!
- Give me that.
Get your lily-faced
ass out here!
Listen to me!
What the fuck
do you think you're doing?
All right,
we gotta go around that truck
and flank them farmers.
Follow my lead.
Bring extra ammo,
take these clips.
Come!
Now!
Pick her up.
Beware the light.
What the hell are you?
Sit down.
Hold still.
Get him on the truck.
Yeah.
Go.
It's all right,
it's all right.
It's all right.
You did fine, 24.
You're healing.
Just breathe.
You're a newborn,
by any measure.
Just breathe.
Your body has work to do.
Hemostasis, angiogenesis,
epithelialization...
stromal cell proliferation.
This will help you heal.
Make you stronger.
Well...
It's got water, and...
It's got water.
Fuck this. Fuck this.
God!
Fuck! Fuck!
Fuck!
Shit!
Fuck! Fuck!
Fuck!
Motherfucking...
Shit!
Fuck! Fuck!
Welcome back.
I was starting to think
I was gonna have to tell...
that nice little girl
out in the waiting room...
her daddy's gone.
I'd always hoped...
that I'd get the chance
to meet someone like you.
There's so few of you left.
Nice to meet you, too, Doc.
But I really
got to get on my way.
No, no, don't do that.
What you need is rest,
and treatment.
You need to check yourself
in somewhere.
I'll be fine.
No, you're not!
I mean, I know
that you're different...
but that doesn't
change the fact
that something inside you
is poisoning you.
You got to check yourself
into a hospital.
Find out what it is!
I know what it is.
Please, mister, if you don't
want to go to a hospital,
maybe I can help you.
Maybe I can run
some tests.
Look, Doc. You seem
like a nice guy, all right?
You wanna save a life,
save your own.
Forget we were here.
Let's go.
Hey!
You can't just take shit,
you know.
I don't know
how you got me here...
but thank you.
De nada.
Yeah.
You can talk?
What the fuck?
Why in the fuck...
What's all this
bullshit been
for the last
2,000 fucking miles?
What? Shut up.
Shut the fuck up!
Jonah, Gideon,
Rebecca, Delilah, Rictor.
What? Who's that?
Who is that?
Jonah, Gideon, Rebecca,
Delilah, and Rictor.
North Dakota.
What?
North Dakota, por favor.
Shit, okay. Look...
No. Por favor.
This place. Okay?
Your nurse,
she read too many stories,
you understand?
Too many stories!
I've seen it!
I've seen it, okay?
This all here...
None of this...
No existo, okay?
You understand me?
This Eden
does not exist. No!
Si! Eden!
It's a fantasy, kid.
See that?
Those are the names
of the people
who just made this...
They made this
whole thing up.
Okay? This whole...
It happened once,
and they just turned it
into a big, fucking lie!
That's all this is. No!
Fuck.
No.
I know, I understand.
This is a long way.
You understand?
I am not taking you
to North Dakota.
I am fucked up.
And I cannot get you there.
It is a 2-day drive.
And I am not taking you...
Don't fucking hit me!
Don't hit me!
Jonah, Gideon...
Stop saying those names.
...Rebecca...
Delilah, Rictor.
Right now.
Stop saying those names.
Stop it! Stop!
Jonah, Gideon, Rebecca...
Fuck it. Fine, fine.
You wanna go?
I'll take you there.
See for yourself.
Let's go to
fucking fantasyland.
We understand
the importance
of containment, Dr. Rice.
But you can't leave
a war zone behind
like you did in Juarez.
Well, try to
remind yourselves
that these are all
little killing machines.
Machines who would've happily
disemboweled your family.
Not all.
I was told you want
these assets off-board,
dead or alive.
Are you changing my brief?
No.
All right, then.
Save tissue from this one.
He's a good tracker
and had a high IQ.
Here you go.
Hey.
Hmm?
Let me drive.
Absolutely not.
Quit looking at me.
No comprende.
You are dying.
You want to die.
Charles told me.
What else did he tell you?
To not let you.
Hey, hey, hey!
Rest.
Keep it steady.
Swing him toward me.
Yeah.
Easy. Easy
Is this good, Rictor?
No, not so much. Less.
Hey!
Where am I?
Hey, what is it?
Where did you get that?
Where we came from.
They gave it to us
when we would fight.
It makes you stronger.
It makes you crazy,
is what it does.
It'll kill you.
No, not if you use it
in small doses.
It's helping you heal.
Where's Laura?
She's asleep down there.
Do you want me
to wake her up?
No.
You had a nightmare.
Do you have nightmares?
Si.
People hurt me.
Mine are different.
I hurt people.
You know what it is.
It's made
out of Adamantium.
It's what they put
inside of us.
That's why it can kill us.
Probably what is
killing me now.
Anyway...
I got this
a long time ago...
and I kept it as a reminder
of what I am.
Now I keep it to, uh...
Actually, uh...
I was thinking of
shooting myself with it.
Like Charles said.
I've hurt people, too.
You're gonna have to learn
how to live with that.
They were bad people.
All the same.
Not funny.
That is not funny!
Hey! Hey, pal.
How long have I been out?
How long have I been
in that bed?
Two days.
You've been sitting here
for two days?
Hey, go inside and tell
everyone to get packing.
You can't do that.
You can't just stay here.
We had to wait.
It was the plan.
And everyone had till today
to find their way here.
If you keep waiting,
Alkali will find you
and they will kill you all.
You need to get out!
We're leaving tomorrow
before dawn.
We're gonna cross
the border.
It's a safe haven.
Same coordinates?
Yes, between noon and 5:00.
Satellites are blind then.
Your asylum approved.
Copy.
Swing it
to your right, Laura.
A little more. Yeah.
You see the woods?
Si.
It's an 8 mile hike
through there.
And you see that pass?
Mm-hmm.
That's the border.
That's where
we will be safe.
Come inside.
Laura told me
all that you did for her.
She was lucky to have you.
Take it.
She says it's yours.
That's why
you did it, right?
Yeah, well...
Look, I don't need it.
You do, okay?
Suit yourself.
Your friends,
they seem nice.
Kind of reminds me...
Hey, hey,
what's going on?
Huh?
You're with your pals.
You made it.
Where will you go?
Nearest bar, for starters.
Hey, I got you here.
That's all I signed up for.
I even gave back
the money.
Such a nice man.
Hey, I never asked
for this!
All right?
Charles never asked for this.
Caliban never asked for this.
And they are 6 feet
under the ground!
Now, I don't know what
Charles put in your head...
but I am not whatever it is
you think I am, okay?
I only met you,
like, a week ago.
You got your Rebecca,
your Delilah...
your blah, blah, blah,
whatever.
Everything you asked for,
you've got it!
And it is better this way.
Because I suck at this.
Bad shit happens to people
I care about.
You understand me?
Then I'll be fine.
Run!
Towards the mountains! Run!
Run, Bobby, run!
Ah!
Go! Go!
Move faster!
We need to reach them before
they get to the border.
Move out!
Let's go, let's go!
Run! Run!
Corre, Jonah! Run!
I want you to breathe.
It's just
a flesh wound, baby.
There she is.
We got her.
Back it up! Contain her.
Get behind me!
You took all the medicine.
It's wearing off.
Go to your friends.
Go.
Laura?
You'll know when.
9 o'clock.
That green juice
is wearin' off, huh?
You know, for an old mute,
it's kind of a short high.
Be hard to
keep them claws out, soon.
Waste this dick, Logan!
Please stop,
Mr. Howlett.
I'm gonna have to
tell these men
to fire
on these children.
You don't want that.
You can see the effects of
the serum are wearing off.
You will not survive
further wounds.
Allow me to
introduce myself.
I'm Zander Rice.
I believe you knew my father
on the Weapon X Program.
Yeah. He's the asshole
who put this poison in me.
Yes, he was one of them.
I think
I might have killed him.
I think you're right.
Why don't you show
some respect, mutie?
You're lookin' at the man
who wiped out your kind.
My friend Donald overstates.
He makes it sound more brutal
than intended.
The goal was
not to end mutant kind...
but to control it.
I realized
we needn't stop perfecting
what we eat and drink.
That we could use
those products
to perfect ourselves.
To distribute gene therapy
discreetly
through everything...
from sweet drinks
to breakfast cereals.
And it worked.
Random mutancy
went the way of polio.
We embarked
on our next endeavor.
Growing mutants of your own.
Precisely.
Dangerous times, James.
You can't...
Argh!
Showtime, boy!
Get up, boy.
Get up, boy!
He did that. Get up!
Laura! No!
Laura!
Please.
Ah!
Go.
Let's go.
Go, go, go!
Go! Get out of here! Go!
Go. Go, go, go!
Go, go!
Go!
Run!
No!
No, no. No.
Take your friends, and run.
No.
Run. They'll keep
coming and coming.
Listen, you don't have
to fight anymore.
Go, go.
Don't be what they made you.
Laura... Laura...
Daddy.
So, this is what
it feels like.
No!
Daddy.
Dad.
"A man has to be
what he is, Joey.
"Can't break the mold.
"There's no living
with a killing.
"There's no going back.
"Right or wrong,
it's a brand.
"A brand that sticks.
"Now you run on home
to your mother.
"You tell her
everything's all right.
"There are no more guns
in the valley."
Let's go.
We gotta move.
There's a man goin' 'round
takin' names
And he decides who to free
and who to blame
Everybody won't be treated
all the same
There'll be a golden ladder
reaching down
When the man comes around
The hairs on your arm
will stand up
At the terror in each sip
and in each sup
For you partake
of that last offered cup
Or disappear
into the potter's ground
When the man
comes around
Hear the trumpets
hear the pipers
100 million
angels singing
Multitudes are marching
to the big kettle drum
Voices callin',
voices cryin'
Some are born
an' some are dyin'
It's Alpha's and Omega's
kingdom come
And the whirlwind
is in the thorn tree
The virgins are all
trimming their wicks
The whirlwind
is in the thorn tree
It's hard for thee
to kick against the pricks
Till Armageddon
no Shalam, no Shalom
Then the father hen will
call his chickens home
The wise men will bow down
before the throne
And at his feet they'll
cast their golden crown
When the man comes around
Whoever is unjust
let him be unjust still
Whoever is righteous
let him be righteous still
Whoever is filthy
let him be filthy still
Listen to the words
long written down
When the man comes around
Hear the trumpets
hear the pipers
100 million
angels singin'
Multitudes are marchin'
to the big kettle drum
Voices callin',
voices cryin'
Some are born
an' some are dyin'
It's Alpha and Omega's
kingdom come
And the whirlwind
is in the thorn tree
The virgins are all
trimming their wicks
The whirlwind
is in the thorn tree
It's hard for thee
to kick against the pricks
In measured hundredweight
and penny pound
When the man comes around