Minions!
Minions have been on this planet
far longer than we have.
They go by many names.
Dave, Carl,
that one is Norbit.
He's an idiot.
They all share the same goal.
To serve
the most despicable master around.
Finding a master was easy.
Keeping a master...
That's where things got tricky.
But nonetheless,
they kept on looking.
Without a master,
they had no purpose.
They became aimless.
And depressed.
If this went on much longer,
they would surely perish.
But then
one minion stepped forward.
Kevin felt pride!
He was going to be the one
to find his tribe
the biggest,
baddest villain to serve.
Stuart felt hungry mostly,
he was going to
be the one to eat this banana.
And bob...
Bob was frightened
of the journey ahead.
Subtitledtrailers.com