Subtitledtrailers.com
The IMF is uniquely trained
and highly motivated.
Specialists without equal
immune to any countermeasures.
But it is an agency of chaos.
The time has come
to dissolve the IMF.
Now, I want you to choose
your next words very carefully.
Where is Hunt?
Last I heard,
he was tracking the Syndicate.
How come the CIA hs never discovered
any intel regarding the Syndicate?
Do you want the polite answer,
or the truth?
We've never met before, right?
Follow me!
- Benji.
- Ethan! Where are you?
The Syndicate is real.
A rogue nation
trained to do what we do.
An anti-IMF.
They're coming after us
with everything they've got.
Are you ready?
This may very well be
our last mission.
Let's make it count.
So, what's the play?
You want to bring down the Syndicate?
It's impossible.
How do you know we can trust her?
Desperate times...
Desperate measures.
- You have your seat belt on?
- You're asking me that now?!
Oh, hey, boys!
What did I miss?
Ethan?
Benji!
Open the door!
- Open the door!
- Yeah, I'm trying!
Oh, my God!
The other door!