(SHRIEKS)
♪ To the head bone ♪
♪ The head bone's connected
to the horn bone ♪
♪ The horn bone's right
above the wing bones ♪
(LITTLE MONSTERS GIGGLING)
(GROWLS) Ah!
I scared you!
No, you didn't.
Okay! Remember our field
trip rules, everyone.
Uh, no pushing, no biting,
and no fire breathing!
(ROARS) What did I just say?
Eighteen, nineteen...
Okay, we're missing one.
Who are we missing?
Oh. Mike Wazowski.
Thanks, Joe.
Good luck finishing
your crossword puzzle.
Sorry, Michael.
I didn't see you.
That's okay.
When I was on the bus,
I found a nickel!
I wish I had pockets.
Okay, everyone, partner up.
Get your field trip buddy.
Jeremy! You and me?
Okay, no biggie.
Hailey? No?
Pairing up with Claire?
Great choice.
She's a good egg.
Russell.
Mike? Wazowski?
We car-pool?
We're cousins.
BOTH: Hey!
Okay. Good catching up.
Well, Michael, it looks like
it's you and me again.
(AGREES NERVOUSLY)
(LITTLE MONSTERS
CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
Come on, Karen.
We're falling behind.
(LAUGHING) Please
don't call me Karen.
TOUR GUIDE: Now, stay close together.
We're entering
a very dangerous area.
Welcome to the Scare Floor.
LITTLE MONSTERS: Wow!
(MALE MONSTER CHATTERING ON PA)
(WORKERS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
TOUR GUIDE: This is where we
collect the Scream Energy
to power our whole world.
(ALL GASP)
And can anyone tell me whose job
it is to go get that scream?
ALL: Scarers!
That's right!
Now, which one of you can
give me the scariest roar?
ALL: Me, me, me!
Oh! Sir! Right here!
Little green guy,
two o'clock!
(ROARS)
No, it's like this.
Hey, guys, watch this one.
(ROARS)
Hey, I got a really good...
(BOTH ROARING)
(ROARS LOUDLY)
ALL: (GASPING) Wow!
Whoa.
Well, hey there, kids. Are you
on a tour with your school?
Yeah!
MRS. GRAVES: Yes.
We're here to learn
about Scream Energy
and what it takes
to be a Scarer.
Well, hey, you're in luck, because
I just happen to be a Scarer.
I learned everything
I know from my school,
Monsters University.
Whoa.
It's the best
Scaring School there is.
You wish!
Fear Tech's the best.
Okay. You guys
watch us and tell me
which school's the best.
All right?
(WHISPERS) MU is.
(BELL RINGING)
FEMALE MONSTER ON PA: West coast
coming only.
Scarers coming only.
MALE SCARER: Oops.
Stop right there.
Don't cross over
that safety line.
Human children
are extremely toxic.
Look at that!
(LITTLE MONSTERS CHATTERING)
Whoa! Hey, guys,
watch the eye! Ow!
LITTLE MONSTER 1: Look at that!
It's amazing!
LITTLE MONSTER 2: I know!
ALL: Wow!
MIKE: Excuse me. Fellas.
How about we do tallest in the back?
(GASPS)
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
LITTLE MONSTER 3: Look, he's going to
do a real scare!
(PANTING)
(ROARS)
(MIKE SIGHS)
Cool. I want to
be a Scarer.
Yeah. Me, too.
Come on, guys.
I want to see.
Out of the way, Wazowski.
You don't belong
on a Scare Floor.
(RATTLING)
Brian! Do not step
over the line.
Mrs. Graves, Michael
went over the line.
(GASPS) Michael!
(DOOR CREAKING)
MOTHER: See?
I told you. He's fine.
FATHER: Well,
I thought I heard something.
(SCRATCHING)
(BOY GASPS)
(BOY SCREAMS)
(ALL GASP)
What?
(ALL CHATTERING) Are you okay?
FEMALE MONSTER: You could have gotten hurt!
That was real dangerous, kid. I
didn't even know you were in there.
Wow. I didn't even know
you were in there.
(CHUCKLES)
Not bad, kid.
Michael, what do you have
to say for yourself?
How do I become a Scarer?
(MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
Monsters University!
Anybody getting off?
(SIGHS)
Well, everyone, I don't
mean to get emotional,
but everything in my life
has led to this moment.
Let it not be just the
beginning of my dream
but the beginning
of all of our dreams.
Gladys, promise me
you'll keep auditioning.
Marie, Mr. Right is
out there somewhere.
Phil, keep using the ointment
till that thing goes away.
I wish you all the best.
Thank you all so much!
(MIKE PANTING)
I'm welling up with tears.
Now, get off.
(EXHALES)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
Hello. How are you doing?
(BICYCLE BELL RINGS)
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
Ah!
Whoo-hoo!
(CHUCKLES)
COACH: Stroke! Stroke!
Come on,
put all you have into it!
Okay! First thing on
my list, get registered.
Hey there, freshman.
I'm Jay the R.A.,
and I'm here to say that
registration is that away!
Okay, Jay.
Have a great first day.
Hey, I'm Kay! Here's
your orientation packet.
Thanks, Kay.
You can drop your bags off here
and get your
picture taken with Trey.
Say hooray!
Hooray!
I can't believe it.
I'm officially
a college student!
Okay, everyone, I'm Fay,
and I'll be giving you your
orientation tour on this perfect day!
(TOUR PARTICIPANTS CHATTERING)
FAY: Here are the labs
where students learn
to design and build the
doors to the human world.
(DOOR BUZZING)
Looks like the professor
is about to test a door!
The MU cafeteria serves a full
buffet, three meals a day.
I personally believe we have some
of the best chefs in the world.
Oh! Yeah!
Yeah! (LAUGHS)
The campus offers
a wide variety of majors,
but the crown jewel of MU
is the Scaring School.
(ALL MURMURING)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
Welcome to the debate team.
We're happy to have you.
I disagree for
the following reasons.
True happiness is a
theoretical construct...
Hey there! Keep
your eye on the sky
at the astronomy club!
Hey, hey, hey! Come
join the improve club.
You'll wish you were a...
Never... Always...
Ah, dang it!
MU's Greek Council. We sponsor
the annual Scare Games.
(STAMMERS) The Scare what now?
The Scare Games!
A super-intense
Scaring competition!
They're crazy dangerous,
so anything could happen.
A bunch of guys went
to the hospital last year!
You could totally die.
And it's worth it.
You get a chance to prove
that you are the best!
MIKE: Cool.
MALE DORM PROCTOR: Wazowski, Room 319.
You know, your roommate
is a Scaring major, too.
(GASPS)
"Hello, I'm your roommate."
Oh, that's too bland.
Don't force it.
Just let it happen.
Your lifelong best friend
is right behind this door.
(EXHALES SLOWLY)
(GASPS)
Hey there.
I'm your roomie.
Name's Randy Boggs.
Scaring major.
Oh! (STAMMERS) Mike
Wazowski, Scaring major.
I can tell we're going
to be best chums, Mike.
Take whichever bed you want.
I wanted you to
have first dibs.
Ahh!
(GASPS) You just disappeared.
Sorry. If I do that in Scaring
class, I'll be a joke.
No, it's totally great.
You got to use it.
Really?
Yeah, but lose the glasses.
They give it away.
Huh.
(PRACTICES GROWLING)
(RATTLES)
MIKE: Okay!
Unpack. Check.
Hang posters. Check.
Now I just need to ace my
classes, graduate with honors,
and become
the greatest Scarer ever.
Boy, I wish I had
your confidence, Mike.
Aren't you even
a little nervous?
Actually, no.
I've been waiting
for this my whole life.
I just can't
wait to get started.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(BELL TOLLING)
Oh, man! I can't be
late on the first day!
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(PANTING RAPIDLY)
Wow.
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
(SCOFFS)
You got to be kidding me.
I'm so nervous!
Relax. It will be fine.
Good morning, students.
(STUDENTS SHUSHING)
Welcome to Scaring 101.
I am Professor Knight.
Now I'm sure all of you were the
scariest monster in your town.
Well, bad news, kids.
You're in my town now,
and I do not scare easily.
(GASPS)
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
Dean Hardscrabble.
This is a pleasant surprise.
She's a legend.
She broke
the all-time Scare Record
with the scream
in that very can!
I don't mean to interrupt.
I just thought I'd drop by
to see the terrifying faces
joining my program.
(ALL MURMURING)
Well, I'm sure my students
would love to hear
a few words of inspiration.
Inspiration? Very well.
Scariness is the true
measure of a monster.
If you're not scary
what kind of a monster are you?
It's my job to make
great students greater,
not make mediocre students
less mediocre.
That is why at the end of the
semester there will be a final exam.
Fail that exam and you are
out of the Scaring program.
(GASPS)
(ALL MURMURING)
So, I should hope you're
all properly inspired.
(STUDENTS GASP)
KNIGHT: All right. All right.
Who can tell me the properties
of an effective roar?
Yes?
There are actually five.
Those include
the roar's resonance,
the duration of the roar,
and the...
(ROARING)
(ALL GASP)
Whoops. Sorry.
I heard someone say "roar,"
so I just kind of went for it.
Oh, excuse me, sorry.
I didn't mean to scare you there.
Hey, how you doing?
Very impressive, Mister...
Sullivan.
Jimmy Sullivan.
Like Bill Sullivan, the Scarer?
Yeah. He's my dad.
(ALL MURMURING)
He's a Sullivan!
I should have known.
I expect big things from you.
Well, you won't
be disappointed.
Uh... I'm sorry. (STAMMERS)
Should I keep going?
No, no.
Mr. Sullivan's covered it.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Huh.
Everyone take out
your Scaring textbooks
and open them to chapter one.
Hey, bub.
Can I borrow a pencil?
I forgot all my stuff.
Ah! All right. Yes. There we go.
That will get it.
Mmm... Yeah.
RANDY: Come on, Mike.
It's a fraternity
and sorority party.
We have to go!
If we flunk that Scaring
final, we are done.
I'm not taking any chances.
RANDY: You've got
the whole semester to study,
but this might
be our only chance
to get in good
with the cool kids.
That's why I made these cupcakes.
Oops.
(CHUCKLES) That could
have been embarrassing.
When I'm a Scarer, life
will be a nonstop party.
Stay out of trouble, wild man.
(CHUCKLES) Wild man.
(CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMS IN SURPRISE)
What the...
(SQUEALS)
(SCREAMS) Archie!
(BOTH SCREAM)
Boo!
Hey! What are you...
(SHUSHING)
Wait... You're shushing me?
Hey! Hey! You can't...
(MUFFLED MUTTERING)
MONSTER 1: Where did he go?
MONSTER 2: He's dead meat.
That guy's in big trouble.
Yeah, he is.
MONSTER 3: Hey, guys!
Over here!
(CHUCKLES)
Fear Tech dummies.
(MUFFLED PROTESTS)
(GASPING) Oh, oh!
Sorry about that, buddy.
Why are you in my room?
Your room? This is my...
This is not my room.
Archie! Come here, boy.
(MIMICS PIG) Archie?
Archie the Scare Pig.
He's Fear Tech's mascot.
Why is it here?
(SNIGGERING)
I stole it. Going to
take it to the RORs.
The what?
Roar Omega Roar.
The top fraternity on campus.
They only accept
the highly elite.
Okay, I'll lift the bed,
you grab the pig.
Ready? One, two, three. What?
No, no... Oh! What...
That's it.
Don't let go.
Careful. He's a biter.
(MIKE WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMS)
Whoa! Whoa, hey...
(YELPS) Whoa!
(GROANS)
(SQUEALING)
I got him!
Uh-oh! Whoa!
(CHUCKLES)
That was awesome!
What am I doing?
James P. Sullivan.
Mike Wazowski.
Listen, it was quite
delightful meeting you
and whatever that is,
but if you don't mind,
I have to study my Scaring.
(BLOWS RASPBERRY) You don't
need to study Scaring.
You just do it.
Really? I think there's a
little more to it than that.
But, hey, thanks
for stopping by.
(GASPS) Let go of that!
My hat!
My pig!
(CHUCKLING)
Ooh!
Hey! Come here!
Hey!
(CONTINUES CHUCKLING)
Catch it!
Ooh! Yeah!
(SCREAMS)
Ride it to frat row!
(YELPING)
♪ Tentacles and serpent's
wings, they... ♪
Hey!
Whoa... Ow!
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(MONSTER WHOOPING)
(YELPING)
Wow!
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHOOPING)
Whoa!
(CHUCKLES)
Go, go, go!
(SCREAMS)
Hey...
Come on! Hey!
Ooh!
Cupcake?
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
Whoa...
(GRUNTS)
(SULLEY LAUGHING)
Ooh! (GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(BELLS RINGING)
(SQUEALS)
Got it! (CHUCKLES)
(WHOOPING)
Fear Tech's mascot!
MU rules!
(ALL CHEERING)
ALL: (CHANTING)
M-U! M-U! M-U!
JTC PRESIDENT: Did you
see him catch that pig?
You are Jaws Theta Chi
material, freshman.
Oh, thanks.
I don't know...
No, no, no.
He's an Omega Howl guy.
Back off.
We saw him first.
No way. We did!
JOHNNY: I'll take it
from here, gentlemen.
Johnny Worthington, president
of Roar Omega Roar.
What's your name, big blue?
Jimmy Sullivan.
Friends call me Sulley.
This guy's a Sullivan?
Like the famous Sullivan?
I can't believe it! That is crazy!
(LAUGHING)
Chet, calm down.
I'm sorry.
Sulley, any freshman with the guts
to pull off a stunt like that
has got "Future Scarer"
written all over him.
Hey, did you see me ride the pig?
That took guts.
Slow down, squirt. This party
is for Scare students only.
Oh, sorry, killer, but you
might want to hang out
with someone
a little more your speed.
Uh... They look fun!
Oh, hey there. Want
to join Oozma Kappa?
We have cake.
Go crazy.
Is that a joke?
(JOHNNY GROANS)
Sulley, talk to your friend.
Oh, he's not really
my friend, but sure.
You heard him. This is a
party for Scare students.
I am a Scare student.
I mean for Scare
students who actually,
you know, have a chance.
Aw, snap!
(ALL LAUGHING)
My chances are
just as good as yours.
You're not even in the
same league with me.
Just wait, hotshot.
I'm going to scare circles
around you this year.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, okay.
I'd like to see that.
Oh, don't worry. You will.
KNIGHT: Ready position.
Common crouch.
(ALL GROWL)
I want to see matted fur and yellow teeth.
Basic snarl.
(ALL SNARL)
Show me some slobber.
Drool is a tool,
kids. Use it.
(ROARS SOFTLY)
Now here is a monster
who looks like a Scarer.
You want a hope of passing
this class, you better eat,
breathe, and sleep Scaring.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
(RATTLING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL CHEERING)
Yeah!
MIKE: Give me another one.
Fear of spiders.
Arachnophobia.
Fear of thunder.
Keraunophobia.
Fear of chopsticks!
Consecotaleophobia.
What is this, kindergarten?
Give me a hard one.
(DRUM ROLL)
(CROWD CHEERING)
CHEERLEADERS: Go Monsters University!
You know what to do!
(PANTING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(ALL CHEERING)
The answer is C, fangs.
Well done, Mr. Wazowski.
A bowl of spiders!
Correct!
A clown running in the dark!
Right again.
Warts, boils, and moles,
in that order.
KNIGHT: Outstanding!
(SIGHS)
Ah! Whoa!
(LAUGHING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
(YELPING)
(ROARING)
Ah!
(WHIMPERS)
(CONTINUES ROARING)
Ogre slump.
(ROARS SOFTLY)
Zombie snarl.
(SNARLS)
Dominant silverback gorilla.
(GROWLS)
That is some remarkable
improvement, Michael.
(ROARS SOFTLY)
One frightening face does not
a Scarer make, Mr. Sullivan.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
(MUTTERING)
A Tauntaun grimace
with extra slobber.
You got it!
That's what I'm saying.
I am going to wipe the floor
with that little know-it-all.
Yes, you are, big blue.
Hey, wait.
What are you guys...
It's just a precaution.
RORs are the best Scarers
on campus, Sullivan.
Can't have a member getting
shown up by a beach ball.
Whoo-hoo!
I am on a roll.
I'm going to destroy that guy.
Well, then you'll get
this back right away.
It's time to start delivering
on that Sullivan name.
Today's final will judge your
ability to assess a child's fear
and perform the appropriate
Scare in the Scare Simulator.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(THUD)
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
The Child Sensitivity
Level will be raised
from Bed-wetter
to Heavy Sleeper,
so give it
everything you've got.
Dean Hardscrabble is
with us this morning
to see who will be moving on
in the Scaring program
and who will not.
Let's get started.
I am a five-year-old girl afraid
of spiders and Santa Claus.
Which Scare do you use?
Uh...
That's a Seasonal
Creep and Crawl.
Demonstrate.
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
(BELL DINGS)
Results will be posted
outside my office. Next.
Focus. (EXHALES)
Johnson, Crackle and Howl.
Yes! (CHUCKLES)
(DOOR OPENS)
(MONSTER ROARS)
(DUMMY KID SCREAMS)
Hey. Do you mind?
Don't mind at all.
(ROARS SOFTLY)
Come on, Mike.
Let's just move.
Stay out of my way.
Unlike you, I had to work hard
to get into the Scare program.
(SCOFFS)
That's because
you don't belong here.
(ROARS)
(ROARS LOUDLY)
(LAUGHS) That's what I thought.
(ROARING SOFTLY)
(ROARING)
(WHISPERING)
(GASPS)
(BOTH ROARING)
Whoa! Whoa...
(CLANKS)
(ALL GASP)
(CLATTERING)
(ALL GASPING)
(SCREAMS ESCAPING)
(ALL SIGHING IN RELIEF)
(BOTH GASP)
I'm so sorry.
(STAMMERS) It was an accident.
What? This?
My one souvenir from
a lifetime of Scaring?
Accidents happen, don't they.
The important thing
is no one got hurt.
You're taking
this remarkably well.
Now, let's continue the exams.
Mr. Wazowski,
I'm a five-year-old girl
on a farm in Kansas
afraid of lightning.
Which Scare do you use?
Shouldn't I go up on the...
That is a Shadow Approach
with a Crackle Holler.
Demonstrate.
(INHALES)
Stop. Thank you.
But I didn't get to...
I've seen enough.
I'm a seven-year-old boy...
(ROARS LOUDLY)
I wasn't finished.
I don't need to know
any of that stuff to scare.
That "stuff"
would've informed you
that this particular child
is afraid of snakes.
So a roar wouldn't make him
scream, it would make him cry,
alerting his parents,
exposing the monster world,
destroying life as we know it,
and of course
we can't have that.
So I'm afraid I cannot
recommend that you continue
in the Scaring program.
Good day.
Wait, what?
But I'm a Sullivan.
Well then, I'm sure your family
will be very disappointed.
(FOOTSTEPS RETREATING)
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
(GRUNTS)
(MURMURING CONTINUES)
And, Mr. Wazowski,
what you lack is something
that cannot be taught.
You're not scary.
You will not be continuing
in the Scaring program.
Please. Let me try the simulator.
I'll surprise you.
Surprise me?
I doubt that very much.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
SCRE.M.CAN PROFESSOR: Welcome back.
I hope everyone had a pleasant break.
Some say that a career as a
scream-can designer is boring,
unchallenging, a waste
of a monster's potential.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Open your textbooks
to chapter three.
We will now plunge
into the rich history
of scream-can design.
(SQUEAKS)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(GRUNTS)
(CHUCKLES)
Out of my way!
Coming through!
Oh, sorry. Ha-ha!
Welcome to this year's
Greek Scare Games kickoff.
The Scare Game! Yeah!
(MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
(FEEDBACK)
We have a special guest,
the founder of the games,
Dean Hardscrabble.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Good afternoon.
As a student, I created these gas
as a friendly competition,
but be prepared.
To take home the trophy,
you must be the most
fearsome monsters on campus.
(RORS CHUCKLING)
So good luck, and may
the best monsters win.
We're closing down sign-up,
so we'll see you all...
MIKE: Wait!
I'm signing up!
(CROWD LAUGHING)
What?
Uh... You have to be in
a fraternity to compete.
Behold the next winning
fraternity of the Scare Games,
the brothers, my brothers,
of Oozma Kappa!
Hi.
(HISSING)
Mr. Wazowski,
what are you doing?
You just said the winners are the
most fearsome monsters on campus.
If I win, it means you
kicked out the best Scarer
in the whole school.
That won't happen.
How about a little wager?
If I win, you let me back
in the Scaring program.
(SCOFFS)
And what would that prove?
That you were wrong.
(ALL GASP)
Very well.
If you win, I will
let your entire team
into the Scare program.
But if you lose,
you will leave
Monsters University.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Deal.
Now all you need to do is find
enough members to compete.
We need six guys, right?
MALE ANNOUNCER: Sorry, chief.
We count bodies, not heads.
That dude counts as one.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Anybody else want to join our team?
Anyone at all?
Excuse me.
Sorry. I'm late.
Can I squeeze by you?
Randy!
Randy, thank goodness.
I need you on my team.
Oh. Sorry.
I'm already on a team.
Boggs.
I'm finally in with
the cool kids, Mike.
Don't blow this for me.
Do the thing.
Oh! Where did he go?
(ALL LAUGH)
Please, anybody.
I need one more monster.
Just one more!
Yeah, sorry. Doesn't look good.
We have to move on. Your
team doesn't qualify.
Yes, it does!
The star player
has just arrived.
No way! Someone else!
Please! Anyone else.
We're shutting down sign-ups, okay?
Is he on your team or not?
FEMALE MONSTER: Come on! Let's go!
(GRUNTING)
Fine! Yes,
he's on my team.
Good luck.
All right, Wazowski,
what's the plan?
This is a fraternity house?
Hey there, teammates!
Come on aboard!
As the president
of Oozma Kappa,
it is my honor to welcome
you to your new home.
We call this room
"Party Central."
Technically, we haven't
actually had a party here yet.
But when we do, we'll be ready!
Whoo!
The hot cocoa train
is coming through! Whoa!
Next stop... You!
(CUPS RATTLING)
I would like to
start us off first by...
So, you guys
are Scaring majors?
(CHUCKLES) We were! None
of us lasted very long.
I guess we just weren't what old
Hardscrabble was looking for.
Don Carlton, mature student.
Thirty years in
the textile industry
and then old dandy Don
got downsized.
Figured I could throw
myself a pity party,
or go back to school
and learn the computers.
Hello. I'm Terry
with a "Y"...
And I'm Terri with an "I"!
I'm a dance major!
(CHUCKLES) And I'm not.
Five, six, seven, eight!
(SCATTING)
Seven, eight, turn! And...
Why didn't you turn?
Because we never
agreed to do this!
You said this was
going to be cool!
No one said
this was gonna be cool.
Now I'm embarrassed.
Now you're embarrassed?
Yes, because
it's in front of people!
You should wake up embarrassed.
Hey, hey, hey!
I'm Art!
New Age philosophy major.
Excited to live with you
and laugh with you,
and cry with you.
Thought you might like
to keep a dream journal.
Guess that leaves me.
Ah!
My name's Scott Squibbles.
My friends call me Squishy.
I'm undeclared, unattached,
and unwelcome pretty much
everywhere but here.
Now that we've all been introduced,
as captain of our team...
So, basically, you guys have
no Scaring experience?
(CHUCKLES) Not a lot!
But now we've got you!
You're about the scariest
fella I've ever seen.
Even with them pink polka dots.
Aw, thanks.
Actually, I think I bring
the whole package.
Your hands are
as big as my face!
He's like a mountain with fur!
Oh, come on.
I don't even work out.
Yeah, me neither. I don't
want to get too big. (SNIFFS)
We thought our dreams were
over, but Mike said if we win,
they're letting us in
the Scaring program.
We're going to be real Scarers!
The best!
You betcha! (CHUCKLES)
Yeah! (CHUCKLES)
Right.
And here's what you've been
waiting for, fellas.
Your very own
Oozma Kappa bedroom.
Oh... Great!
We're sharing this room?
We'll let you guys get settled.
Anything you need, you just
give a big holler-oonie!
Okay, thanks, buddy.
Are you kidding me?
Look, they don't
need to be good.
I'm going to
carry the whole team.
Really? And who's
going to carry you?
Hey, if you want to
go back to can design,
you know where the door is.
(FLICKING LIGHT SWITCH)
Great.
Guys?
Anybody home?
(CREAKING)
Um...
(STAMMERS) Hello?
Fellas?
Do you pledge your souls
to the Oozma Kappa brotherhood?
Ow!
Do you swear to
keep secret...
...all that
you learn here?
No matter how horrifying?
Hey!
Will you take the sacred
oath of the... (GASPS)
For crying out loud.
Sweetie!
Turn the lights on
while you're down here!
You're going to ruin your eyes!
Mom!
We're doing an initiation!
Oh, scary.
Well, carry on.
Just pretend I'm not here.
This is my mom's house.
Do you promise to look out
for your brothers...
(DIAL CRANKING)
...no matter what the peril?
(WASHING MACHINE WHIRRING)
Will you defend Oozma Kappa
no matter how dangerous?
No matter how insurmountable
the odds may be?
From evils both
great and small?
In the face of
unending pain and...
Oh, forget it!
You're in.
Look, we know
we're no one's first choice
for a fraternity,
so it means a lot
to have you here with us.
Can't wait to start Scaring
with you, brothers.
(SIGHS)
(ALL CHEERING)
Time for a celebration!
Yeah!
Grab the couch cushions,
gentlemen,
because we're building a fort!
Mom, can we
stay up late tonight?
(MIKE AND SULLEY SNORING)
Mmm, I know you're a princess
and I'm just a stable boy.
(ALARM BUZZES)
(KISSES)
Yuck!
(GRUNTS)
Mom! What are you doing?
Your grubby paw was in my bed!
(STAMMERS)
Were you kissing my hand?
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
No. And what about you
with all your shedding?
I don't shed.
Really.
Uh...
Excuse me.
I just want to get my stuff.
Would you just...
Oh, hey. Come on!
...let me get my stuff!
(GRUNTS)
(MIKE YELPS)
SULLEY: My butt!
(BOTH GROANING)
(CAMERA CLICKS)
First morning in the house.
That's going in the album!
Guys!
We got a letter!
A letter?
TERRI: We never get mail.
Oh! Sorry.
It's stuck.
Would you...
Give me that!
Tentacles. (CHUCKLES)
They're sticky.
(GASPS) It's the first event
of the Scare Games.
(ALL GASPING)
"A child's room
is where you scare,
but avoid
the toxicity lurking there."
Wait a minute. Where do
they want us to meet?
Of all the sewers on campus, this
one has always been my favorite.
Art, you've been here before?
I have a life outside
of the house, you know.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Welcome to your
worst nightmare,
the Scare Games!
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
CROWD: (CHANTING)
Scare Games! Scare Games!
(CHUCKLES) Yes!
Yes, I love it!
I love this energy!
Okay. Okay, everybody.
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: Let's hear it
for the frats and sororities
competing in
this year's games...
Jaws Theta Chi!
(ALL CHEER)
MALE ANNOUNCER: Python Nu Kappa!
Slugma Slugma Kappa!
(ALL GRUNT)
MALE ANNOUNCER: Roar Omega Roar!
(ALL ROARING)
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: Eta Hiss Hiss!
(HISSES)
And finally, Oozma Kappa.
(SILENCE)
Yay! Whoo-hoo!
Hi, Mom!
Smile!
(CAMERA CLICKS)
(GROANS)
Let's begin
the first competition,
the Toxicity Challenge!
(ALL CHEERING)
Human children are toxic!
And anything
they touch is toxic.
MALE ANNOUNCER: We don't
have any human toys,
but thanks to MU's
biology department,
we found a close second,
the stinging glow urchin!
(ALL GASP)
(ALL MURMURING)
Trust me when I say,
you are not gonna want
to touch this bad boy!
I want to touch it.
And you certainly don't want
to touch any of its friends.
(ALL GASP)
Yeah, I want to touch them.
This is the starting line.
The light at the end of the
tunnel is the finish line.
And whoever comes in last is
eliminated from the games.
Mike...
(GASPS) What is it?
Does that mean if
we lose, we're out?
Don't worry, Smoothie.
Squishy!
Squishy.
We're not going to lose,
because we have everything
we need to win right here.
Heart.
No! Me. I'm going to
win the race for us.
SULLEY: All right, all right.
That's very cute,
It's an obstacle course. What are
you going to do? Roar at it?
I can get through faster
than you, little guy.
Take your place at
the starting line!
This is all about teamwork.
Everybody, stick together.
I'm going to beat you
over that finish line.
Get ready to eat my dust.
Hey, guys, should we huddle up?
Attention, teams.
One last thing.
Scarers work in the dark.
(CRACKLING)
I want to go home!
On your marks...
Hey, uh, good luck, ladies.
Thanks! We're going to
rip you to pieces!
What?
(ALL HISSING)
(BOTH GASP)
MALE ANNOUNCER: ...get set...
Go!
(ALL YELLING)
I'm going to touch them!
(CHUCKLING)
(SIGHS)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(ALL PANTING)
Ow!
Come on!
Uh, guys! We're falling
behind a little! Fellas!
(SCREAMS)
Cheese and
crackers! (GROANS)
Son of a moustache!
Salisbury steak, that hurts!
Is that as fast as you can go?
Just getting started!
What the...
(CROWD JEERING)
Whoa! Ah!
Oh... Ah!
(GASPS)
That's got to hurt!
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS) Ow, ow, ow...
Ooh!
Terry!
Don't worry, we'll be fi...
(BOTH SCREAM)
(BOTH GROAN)
(YELPING)
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH SNIGGER)
Ha-ha!
(GASPS) Oh...
Uh-oh. Yikes!
Ow! Ow, ow, ow...
(ROARS)
(BOTH PANTING)
MALE ANNOUNCER: Roar Omega Roar wins!
(BOTH GRUNT)
(BOTH ROARING)
(BOTH GROAN)
(BOTH PANTING)
Take that, Wazowski!
Are you delirious?
I beat you!
Get your eye checked!
Oh, way to blow it, Oozmas!
Hey! Second place
ain't bad.
MALE ANNOUNCER: Second
place, Jaws Theta Chi!
What?
Your whole team has to
cross the finish line.
MALE ANNOUNCER: Third place, EEKs!
Fourth place, PNKs!
MIKE: No.
Fifth place, HSS!
No, no, no!
MALE ANNOUNCER: And in last place,
Oozma Kappa.
I can't feel my anything.
Oh... Shocker! Oozma Kappa
has been eliminated!
No.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPS)
Don't look so surprised,
Mr. Wazowski.
It would have taken
a miracle for you to...
Attention, everyone.
We have an announcement.
Jaws Theta Chi has
been disqualified.
(ALL GASP)
The use of illegal protective
gel is cause for elimination.
What!
(GROANS)
Which means Oozma Kappa
is back in the games!
It's a miracle!
Your luck will
run out, eventually.
This is going to be
harder than I thought.
MIKE: Okay!
Listen up, Oozmas.
Now, we're going to have to start
winning these things together,
so that means I'm going to need
each of you guys
to pull your own weight.
Mike?
(GASPS) What is it?
We've made a list of our
strengths and weaknesses.
In high school, I was the
master of the silent scare.
I could sneak up
on a field mouse
in a pillow factory.
(SQUISHING)
Sorry! They get stickier
when I'm sweaty.
Oh, my gosh, that's terrible.
We're experts in the ancient
craft of close-up magic.
It's all about misdirection.
Uh...
I have an extra toe.
(LAUGHS)
Not with me, of course.
Guys, one slip-up on the next
event, and we're goners.
So for this to work,
I'm gonna need you to take
every instinct you have
and bury it deep, deep down.
Done.
From now on,
we are of one mind.
My mind.
Oh, please.
I will tell you exactly what
to do, and how to do it.
ALL: Uh... Okay, Mike.
Seems about right.
All right.
Give me scary steps.
Fifty up and down,
right now. Let's go!
You're wasting your time.
We need a new team.
(SCOFFS) We can't just
"get a new team"!
I checked this morning.
It's against the rules.
What if we disguised a new team
to look like the old team?
Oh, no, no.
We are not cheating.
It's not cheating.
I'm just, you know,
leveling the playing field.
Okay, so it's kind of cheating,
but what do you want me to do?
They're not exactly the
scariest group in the world.
Oh, a ladybug! Make a wish!
Make a wish!
(BLOWS)
(ALL CHUCKLING)
This is not going to work.
Where are you going?
We're training.
I'm a Sullivan.
That's not enough.
You're all over the place.
You're charging
ahead when you...
Bup, bup, bup!
You tell them what
to do but not me.
So long, Coach.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
(BOTH GIGGLING)
Okay, Oozmas... (GASPS)
Boy, we need to get you a bell.
Listen up."If a kid hears you
coming, they'll call Mom or Dad",
"then you'd better run fast
or things will get bad."
Huh?
In the next event, if even
one of us gets caught,
we're all out.
So remember,
do exactly what I do.
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: We are at the
halfway point of the second event,
and things are
getting interesting.
(SOFTLY) Got it.
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: Only two teams left.
Who will make it
out with their flag,
and who will be eliminated?
You do not want to get
caught by a kid's parent.
And in this event, you do
not want to get caught by
the librarian.
(SHUSHING)
Quiet.
(SCOFFS) What's so scary about
a little old librarian?
(CHAIR CREAKS)
(GASPS)
I said, "Quiet."
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(GASPING)
(WHIMPERS)
Faster.
Slow and steady.
BOTH: Slow and steady.
(GRUNTS IN ANNOYANCE)
(GASPS)
Sullivan!
(ALL SHUSHING)
(ALL GROANING)
(FLOORBOARD CREAKS)
(GASPS)
Hmm.
Whew! (GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
(STRAINING) Ooh!
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLS)
(GASPS)
No!
(POPPING)
(GROWLING)
TERRI: Five, six,
seven, eight! (SCATTING)
BOTH: Look over here!
(TERRY CHUCKLING)
(TERRI SINGING)
(LAUGHING)
(PLATES SHATTERING)
Is that legal? You better
believe it, mop top!
The only rule is
don't get caught.
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
Who!
(LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
Ooh!
BOTH: Hey! Over here!
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMS)
Come and get me! Come and get me!
Whoo-hoo!
Guys, what are you doing?
They said don't
let her catch you.
But they didn't say how!
Move it! Move it!
Move it! Come on!
(GROWLS)
(ALL SCREAM)
ALL: Whoa!
(ALL GRUNT)
Whew! (CHUCKLES)
We did it!
No, we didn't.
We forgot the flag!
SQUISHY: Mike?
(GASPS)
Way to go, Squishy!
How?
Misdirection.
(LIBRARIAN GROWLS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL CHEERING)
The EEKs have been eliminated
and Oozma Kappa live
to scare another day!
ALL: (CHANTING) We're OK!
We're OK! We're OK!
SQUISHY: I've never
felt so alive!
TERRI: We were awesome!
Okay, look.
That wasn't real Scaring.
It was better
than what you did.
You should've
stuck to my strategy.
Whatever.
Talk to me when we start
the real Scaring.
(CAR HORN HONKS)
Hey! You guys
going to the party?
Oh, I think you've
got the wrong guys.
We don't get invited to...
(SHUSHES) Party?
The mid-games mixer
at the RORs'.
It's for the top Scare Teams.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
See you there!
(ALL GIGGLING)
Did you hear that?
I can't believe it!
Uh-uh. Bad idea.
This is great.
They're finally seeing us as real Scarers.
We're going!
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
DON: Do young people
still dance?
Because my moves
are a little rusty.
Oh, we forgot to
bring a hostess gift.
We can't go in there without
some scented candles.
Calm down.
We earned this.
(STAMMERS) What if there's a
lull in the conversation?
I never know what
to... You know...
Say?
How are you so good at this?
You just took on
an angry 50-foot librarian,
and you're afraid
of a little party?
Take a deep breath...
(ALL INHALING DEEPLY)
...and in you go!
(MUSIC STOPS)
Hello.
It's Oozma Kappa!
These guys are crazy!
What you did today was insane!
MONSTER: That was awesome!
(ALL CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
Oozma Kappa, tonight
we party like Scarers!
(ALL CHEER)
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
I've never stayed up
this late in my life!
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(DANCE MUSIC FADES)
(ROARS SOFTLY)
(WHISTLES)
Hey, quiet! Quiet!
Quiet down,
you can-wranglers.
All right.
On behalf of the RORs,
we'd like to congratulate all the
teams that have made it this far.
(ALL CHEERING)
All, right, let's
hear it for the PNKs!
(ALL HISSING)
I love that trick!
Never gets old. HSS!
(HISSES)
(CHUCKLES) Very creepy.
And finally, the surprise
team of the Scare Games,
Oozma Kappa!
(ALL CHEERING)
Now, I got to admit, fellas,
I thought you were
a bunch of nobodies.
But, boy, was I wrong.
Let's hear it for Oozma Kappa!
CROWD: Oozma Kappa!
Oh!
What?
The most adorable
monsters on campus.
CROWD: Ooh! Oh!
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Release the stuffed animals.
(CHET CHUCKLES)
Faced!
Don't worry. (GRUMBLES) Nobody
reads the school paper.
Yeah, but I'm pretty
sure they read the quad.
(MONSTERS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL LAUGHING)
MONSTER: Whoo-hoo!
CHET: Thank you
very much.
Okay. Would you like that
with two sleeves or four?
Thanks.
Tell your friends.
Hey! What do you
think you're doing?
Raising a little
money for charity.
Yeah? Well, stop it.
You want us to stop raising money for charity?
That's not cool.
This guy hates charity!
I want you to stop
making us look like fools.
Hey, you're making yourselves
look like fools.
Let's be honest, boys.
You're never going
to be real Scarers,
because real Scarers
look like us.
(LAUGHS MOCKINGLY)
But, hey, if you really want
to work for a Scare company
they're always
hiring in the mailroom.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Guys, hold on!
Hey, hey, hey! Wait a second.
Don't listen to him.
We just need to keep trying.
No, you need to stop trying!
You can train monsters
like this all you want,
but you can't
change who they are.
(SIGHS)
DON: Mike...
We appreciate everything
you've done, but he's right.
No matter how much we train,
we'll never look like them.
We're built
for other things.
(SLURPS)
Sorry, squirt!
Some monsters just aren't
cut out for the big leagues.
(LAUGHING)
The big leagues.
Guys.
We're going on
a little field trip.
(ALL CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
TERRY: My tentacle
fell asleep.
Thanks, Mom.
Have fun, kids!
I'll just be here
listening to my tunes.
(THRASH METAL BLARING
ON STEREO)
Hey, uh, where are we?
The big leagues.
Holy roly-poly.
Wow.
Nice fence.
This is amazing, Mike.
We're not stopping here.
(PANTING)
(WHIMPERING)
SQUISHY: This is crazy.
We're going to get arrested!
(MIKE SHUSHING)
Oh, wow.
Whoa...
Oh! (CHUCKLES)
FEMALE MONSTER ON PA: All Scare Floors
now active.
West coast coming online.
Scarers coming out.
SQUISHY: Look at them.
They're going
into the human world,
and they don't
even look scared!
(CHILD SCREAMS)
(BEEPS) Wow.
Take a good look, fellas.
See what they
all have in common?
Uh... No, not really.
Exactly. There's no
one type of Scarer.
The best Scarers use their
differences to their advantage.
(SNARLS) Wow.
Terri? Look.
DON: (CHUCKLES) Hey!
Look at that old feller
racking up the big numbers!
Don, that old fella is
Earl "The Terror" Thompson!
What? Where?
That's really him?
MIKE: He held the Scare
Record for three years!
Oh! Third door from the end!
MIKE: Carla
"Killer Claws" Benitez!
SULLEY: Look! It's
"Screaming" Bob Gunderson!
I still have his rookie card.
Me, too!
Doesn't have the speed
anymore, but his
technique is flawless.
Technique is flawless.
You collected Scare Cards, huh?
Yep. 450 of them.
Impressive. I have 6,000
still in mint condition,
but, you know,
450 is pretty good, too.
Hey, look at me! I'm Earl
"The Terror" Thompson!
(ROARS)
Whoa! (CHUCKLES)
Oh, that's great!
DON: That's
a pretty good one, Squish.
I've been a real jerk.
So have I.
But it's not too late.
We could be a great team.
We just need to
start working together.
SECURITY GUARD: Hey!
(GASPS)
What are you doing up there?
I can't go back to jail!
(YELPS)
(ALARM BLARING)
Come on!
DON: They're right behind us!
(ALL PANTING)
Get back here!
(GASPS)
Up there! Get them!
(ALL GRUNTING)
ART: Whoo-hoo-hoo!
(WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTS)
Thanks, brother!
Don't mention it.
(COUGHING)
I'm fine, really! It's just
a little heart attack.
Aw... I want
a piece of that action!
(GRUNTING)
(ALARM RINGING)
(ALL PANTING)
SQUISHY: Mom! Start the car!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
What?
Start the car!
Stop the bar?
The car! Start the car!
Oh! Okay.
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
Come on, come on,
come on, come on!
Get in! Get in!
Mom, go!
Seatbelts.
Okay, go!
Does anyone want gum?
Just drive!
Okay. Here we go!
(ALL SCREAMING)
ART: Oh, yeah!
Let's break in somewhere else!
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALARM BUZZING)
(SULLEY SNORING)
Rise and shine!
(GASPING)
Scary feet, scary feet...
The kid is in the bathroom!
Oh, he's back!
(ALL ROAR)
(ALARM BUZZING)
Wake up!
(GASPING)
(ROARING)
Thirty-seven! Thirty-eight!
Do I hear thirty-nine?
MIKE: Come on!
(SULLEY CONTINUES ROARING)
MIKE: Yes! Okay, Oozma Kappa,
you're looking good.
"To frighten a child
is the point of a Scare."
"If you frighten a teen,
then Scarer beware."
Okay, scare the little kid.
(ROARS)
Avoid the teenager!
(GASPS)
FEMALE TEENAGER 1: I'm on the phone!
(BUZZING)
(GROANS)
MALE TEENAGER 1: No one understands me!
(ROARS)
(BUZZES)
MALE TEENAGER 2: Whatever.
(ROARS)
(BUZZES)
(GROANS)
FEMALE TEENAGER 2: But, Daddy, I love him!
(BELL DINGS)
(ROARS)
(CHILD SCREAMS)
MALE ANNOUNCER: First
place, Roar Omega Roar!
Second place, Oozma Kappa!
Whoo!
MALE ANNOUNCER: Third place, HSS.
(CROWD CHEERING)
MALE TEENAGER 3: You're lame.
"Someone is coming, this
could ruin your night."
"Stay hidden, take cover,
and stay out of sight!"
You got 10 seconds.
Go!
Kiosk! Pile of leaves!
Standing out in the open.
And there should be one more.
(WHISTLES) How did I do?
Oh! Not too
shabby, Don!
Thanks!
I cannot get down.
Zombie snarl!
(SNARLING)
Angry poodle.
Jazz clown.
My Aunt Phyllis.
(GROANING)
In the morning.
That's what I'm talking about!
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(ALARM BUZZES)
Time to go to work.
(GASPS) You're out!
You're out.
(SIGHS)
Hey, tough luck, Kris Kringle.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(WHOOPING)
Thank you.
(CROWD CHEERING LOUDLY)
Yeah!
(WHOOPING) Yeah!
We're down to two remaining team,
Roar Omega Roar and Oozma Ka!
Which leads us to
the final event!
"Every one of your skills
will be put to the test."
"The Scare Simulator will
prove who's the best!"
Tomorrow night
you finally get to Scare
in front of the whole school!
Enjoy the attention
while it lasts, boys.
After you lose,
no one will remember you.
Maybe. But when you lose, no
one will let you forget it.
Oh, boy. That is
a good point.
Hey, Oozmas,
you guys are awesome!
You've got to
teach us your moves.
Well, then you're gonna
want to talk to this guy.
Oh... (CHUCKLES)
Sure, I can teach you.
All right. You want to
hide behind the chair?
You have to become the chair.
MALE ANNOUNCER: Thanks for coming, Dean.
Dean Hardscrabble!
If we get back into
the Scaring program,
I hope there's
no hard feelings.
Tomorrow,
each of you must prove
that you are undeniably scary.
And I know for a fact
that one of you is not.
(INDISTINCT)
No. He works
harder than anyone.
Do you think he's scary?
He's the heart and
soul of the team!
Do you think he's scary?
(ROARS)
We're going to win this thing
tomorrow, Sull, I can feel it!
We'll finally have
our lives back on track.
Hey, Mike?
You know, you've given me
a lot of really great tips.
I'd love to return
the favor sometime.
Oh. Yeah, sure.
Anytime.
(SULLEY GRUNTS)
We're doing this now?
Okay.
You've memorized
every textbook,
every Scare Theory,
and that is great.
Hey!
(CAT YOWLS)
But now it's time
to forget all that.
Just reach deep down
and let the scary out!
Huh. Just feel it.
Exactly. Go wild.
I don't know. I've kind of
got my own technique.
Give it a try.
(ROARS) Good, but bigger!
(ROARS)
Nope. You're thinking again.
From the gut!
(GRUNTING)
Let the animal out!
(ROARING)
Come on! Dig deep!
(ROARING LOUDLY)
SHERRIE: Boys!
It's a school night!
So, how was that?
Up top.
Ha-ha!
You know,
it did feel different!
I feel like it's
all coming together.
Yup, this time tomorrow the whole
school is finally going to see
what Mike Wazowski can do.
(CHUCKLES) You're darn right.
♪ Monsters University ♪
♪ We give our heart to you ♪
♪ Wherever children are dreaming ♪
♪ We'll bring them nightmares, too ♪
♪ Oh, Monsters University ♪
♪ Alma Mater hail to you ♪
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: Welcome
to the final competition
of the Scare Games.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
Whoo! Yeah!
All right!
MALE ANNOUNCER: It's time
to see how terrifying
you really are,
in the Scare Simulators!
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: But be warne.
Each simulated Scare has been set
to the highest difficulty level.
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: First
Scarers to the starting line.
Okay, just like we planned. I'll go first.
Then, Don...
Hold on. Mike's the one
who started all this
and I think it's only right if
he's the one who finishes it.
I think you should go last.
ALL: Yes!
Yeah, Mike. Finish strong!
All right. Don,
you okay going first?
I guess I'm as ready
as I'll ever be.
ALL: Oozma Kappa!
(CROWD CHEERING)
MONSTER: Go Oozmas!
I'm gonna do it. I'm
going to beat this guy.
Hey, Bruiser! You take
it easy on grandpa.
(LAUGHS EVILLY)
Unleash the beast, Don!
Okay, then.
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
(PANTING)
(CROWD GASPING)
(GASPS)
(SQUEAKING)
(ROARS)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
(DINGS)
(ALL CHEERING)
Huh? Huh?
Thanks for taking
it easy on grandpa.
(ALL GASPING)
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: Next group
to the starting line.
BOTH: Let's do this.
(ROARS)
(DINGS)
(CHEERING)
Yes! Yeah!
(BOTH ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
(DINGS)
(CHEERING)
(SCREAMING)
(DINGS)
(CHEERING ENTHUSIASTICALLY)
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
Come on, Art.
Come on, buddy.
You can do it.
(ALL ENCOURAGING)
Yes!
(CHEERING)
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
CROWD: Aw!
(ALL GROANING)
MALE ANNOUNCER: Next up,
Sullivan and Boggs!
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
You got this, Sull.
(ROARS)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
(DINGING)
MALE ANNOUNCER: And it's all tied up!
(LAUGHING)
(ALL CHEERING)
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: Ah!
Tough break for the RORs.
Huh?
Hearts?
Way to go, Boggs!
(OOZMAS CHEERING)
Yay!
That's the last time
I lose to you, Sullivan.
Worthington and Wazowski,
to the starting line.
(EXHALES)
Hey.
Don't worry about Hardscrabble.
Don't worry about anyone else.
Just go out there and show them
what Mike Wazowski can do.
Thanks.
(CHEERING)
(MIKE EXHALING)
Don't take the loss too hard.
You never belonged here anyway.
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
(MIKE PANTING)
(SCRATCHING)
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
MALE ANNOUNCER: Amazing
performance by Worthington!
Johnny, you're my hero!
CROWD: (CHANTING) ROR! ROR!
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: The Oozmas
will need a record-breaking
Scare to win this.
LITTLE MONSTER: You don't
belong on a Scare Floor.
HARDSCRABBLE: You're not scary.
SULLEY: Come on! Dig deep!
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
(DINGS)
Yeah!
(CROWD CHEERING)
They did it!
(CHEERING)
(YELPING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Yeah! Hey!
(LAUGHING)
We're in the Scare
program! Yeah!
(ALL CHEERING)
Come here, you son of a gun!
Way to go!
Yeah!
Oh! A little stuck.
Pardon me there,
Ms. Squibbles.
(GIGGLES) It's Sherrie.
We did it!
Way to go, Oozma Kappa!
Thank you!
Thanks a lot.
You rule!
I have never ruled before.
(LAUGHING) You guys
killed it out there!
Awesome!
Hey, Wazowski!
Come on, let's go, you maniac!
We're celebrating.
Mike?
I did it.
I can't believe it.
I'm going to be a Scarer!
(LAUGHS) Yeah, yes, you are.
You hear that? Get
plenty of rest, kiddo.
You haven't seen the last
of Mike Wazowski. Boo!
(SCREAMING)
(BEEPING)
I knew I was scary. I didn't
know I was that scary.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah, we're so
scary I guess we broke it.
Come on.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
MIKE: It's been tampered with.
Uh, I don't think you should
be messing with that.
MIKE: Why are
my settings different?
Mike, we should leave.
Did you do this?
Mike.
(SIGHS) I...
Yes, I did.
But you don't understand.
Why? Why did you do this?
(SIGHS) You know, just in case.
In case of what?
You don't think I'm scary.
Mike...
You said you believed in me.
But you're just
like Hardscrabble.
You're just like everyone else!
Look, you'll get
better and better...
I'm as scary as you!
I'm as scary as anyone!
I just wanted to help.
No.
You just wanted
to help yourself.
Let the whole team fail
because you don't have it?
(BUZZES)
MALE DOOR TECHNICIAN: So your
calculations were a little off.
That door took me all semester.
It's too dangerous. The professor's
just going to shred it.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(LAUGHS) There he is,
the big guy.
The first of many
trophies, I am sure.
KNIGHT: Sullivan.
Nice work out there.
I look forward to
having you back in class.
CHET: Hey, there he is!
Looks like I was
wrong about you.
You're one of us after all.
CHET: Way to go, Sulley!
Welcome back, broham!
You are one of us now, okay?
Anytime you want
to come hang out
and do whatever,
you got a crew.
You're a ROR, buddy!
Hey!
Where are you going?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(BUZZES)
You did what?
My team had
nothing to do with it.
It was all me. I cheated.
I expect you off
campus by tomorrow.
Yes, ma'am.
You're a disgrace
to this university
and your family name.
(ALARM BLARING)
What's going on?
Someone broke
into the door lab!
What?
Oh, no.
(CROWD CLAMORING)
Open the door!
Don't go in there!
(EXHALES)
(ROARS)
(GASPS)
You look funny.
What?
(GIRL YAWNING)
GIRL 1: I'm so tired.
What's going on?
GIRL 2: It's the
middle of the night.
GIRL 3: A little
funny green guy.
(WHIMPERING)
(ROARS)
(GASPS)
(GIRLS CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
GIRL 4: I want to touch it!
It's so cute!
(PANTING)
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
James!
No one goes near that door
until the authorities arrive.
You don't think
that could be...
It's Mike.
But he could die out there!
James, wait!
We can help.
Leave it to
the old master of sales.
We got a call in, but
that's the best we can do.
Ahem!
Don Carlton, sales. Folks,
today is your lucky day.
How many times have you asked
yourself the following question...
Arrest him.
Pardon?
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Spread them, pops!
DON: Do you mind?
Don't move!
What? Sullivan!
(GASPS) Don't you dare!
Sullivan! Don't go in there!
(GASPS)
Mike?
Mike! (GASPS)
(SIREN WAILS)
WOMAN: The kids said they
saw something in the cabin.
They're calling it an alien.
GIRL: It was!
I saw a little green guy!
What's the problem, ma'am?
(GASPS)
(WIND WHOOSHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHISPERS) Mike?
(GRUNTS)
(CROWD GASP)
(GASPS)
MALE CAMP COUNSELOR: Bear!
A bear in the camp!
RANGER 1: Call this in
to headquarters.
(PANTING)
(GASPS LOUDLY)
RANGER 2: Down this way.
All right?
(RANGERS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
I heard something over here!
(SPLASH)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS) Mike!
Come on, buddy.
Let's get you out of here.
This is all my fault.
I'm sorry.
You were right. They
weren't scared of me.
I did everything right.
I wanted it more than anyone.
And I thought... I thought
if I wanted it enough,
That Mike Wazowski
is something special.
And I'm just
not.
Look, Mike,
I know how you feel.
Don't do that!
Please, don't do that!
You do not know how I feel.
Mike, calm down.
Monsters like you have everything.
You don't have to be good.
You can mess up
over and over again
and the whole world loves you.
Mike...
You'll never know
what it's like to fail
because you were
born a Sullivan!
Yeah, I'm a Sullivan.
I'm the Sullivan
who flunked every test.
The one who got kicked out
of the program,
the one who was so afraid
to let everyone down
that I cheated.
And I lied.
(SIGHS)
Mike, I'll never know
how you feel,
but you're not
the only failure here.
I act scary, Mike,
but most of the time
I'm terrified.
How come you never
told me that before?
Because
we weren't friends before.
RANGER 3: Check the lake!
(GASPS)
RANGER 4: I heard something here!
RANGER 5: This way!
(PANTING)
(RANGERS SHOUTING)
RANGER 6: I saw movement!
Over there!
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
MIKE: Sulley!
(PANTING IN RELIEF)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
RANGER 5: He's cornered!
(BOTH GASP)
No!
They're still in there!
Until the authorities arrive,
this door stays off!
No! You can't
do that! No!
Enough! I want
this room cleared now!
You can't do this!
(ALL CLAMORING)
(GASPS)
(SIREN WAILS)
We got to get out of here!
Let them come.
What?
If we scare them,
I mean really scare them,
we could generate enough scream
to power the door
from this side!
What are you talking about?
I have read every book
about Scaring ever written.
This could work!
They're adults.
I can't do this.
Yes, you can.
Just follow my lead.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(CREAKING)
(LOUD THUDDING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(MOUTHING)
(SLAMS)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
Mama!
(DISTORTING) Mama...
(RANGERS GASP)
(SCRATCHING)
(GASPING)
(CREAKING)
(LOUD SCRATCH)
What the...
(FOREST RANGERS MURMURING)
Now what?
Phase two.
(CLATTERING)
(RANGERS GASPING)
(RANGER WHIMPERS)
Keep together.
(RANGERS SCREAMING)
(RANGERS MURMURING)
(WHISPERING) Are you ready?
Mike, I can't.
Yes, you can.
Stop being a Sullivan
and start being you.
MALE RANGER: Call for backup.
FOREST RANGER: Assistance
on the north side.
Repeat, we need assistance
DISPATCH ON RADIO: Ranger,
answer me, what's your 20?
We need assistance on the north side.
We have a...
(ALL GASPING)
Look! What was it?
Let's go.
(RANGERS CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(RANGERS GASPING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS ECHOING)
(CANISTERS DINGING)
(ROARING)
(RANGERS WHIMPERING)
(RANGERS SCREAMING)
Sulley, come on!
(GASPS)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(BOTH PANTING)
HARDSCRABBLE: How?
(STAMMERS) How did you do this?
Don't ask me.
(SPARKS CRACKLING)
(GASPS)
Move, move, move! This
is a 54-23 in progress.
All right,
everybody, clear out.
Secure the perimeter.
No child breach.
Repeat: no child breach.
You ruined our doors!
I've been working on
my door all semester!
Let's go, you two.
You're alive!
We are so glad you're safe.
Hey, wait!
CDA AGENT: That's for the
university president to decide.
But you can be sure we'll
be watching these two.
Always watching.
Expelled?
So, you're leaving?
Yeah, buddy. We have to go.
Harsh, man.
I'm sorry, guys. You'd be
in the Scaring program
right now if it wasn't for us.
What?
Well, (CHUCKLES) it is
the gosh-darnedest thing.
Hardscrabble's letting us
into the Scare program.
What?
She was impressed with our
performance in the games.
She invited us to
join next semester!
(CHUCKLES)
Congratulations, guys!
And that's not the
only piece of good news.
Sherrie and I are engaged!
Oh. Who is Sherrie?
(SIGHING) She's my mom.
Well, if it isn't my
two favorite fellas!
Come here.
Give me some sugar.
Oh!
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Ugh! So uncomfortable.
Oh, come on, Scott.
I don't want you to think
of me as your new dad.
After all, we're
fraternity brothers first.
This is so weird.
DON: Just think of me
as your big brother
that's marrying your mother.
Wait. Hold on.
We're brothers who share
the same mom slash wife.
That's worse.
Well, I guess
we should be going now.
Promise me
you'll keep in touch.
You're the scariest bunch
of monsters I have ever met.
Don't let anyone
tell you different.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
So, what now?
You know, for the first time in my
life, I don't really have a plan.
You're the great Mike Wazowski.
You'll come up with something.
I think it's time I leave the
greatness to other monsters.
I'm okay just being okay.
So long, Sull.
So long.
Wazowski!
(SCREAMS)
Whoa!
Stop the bus!
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Are you crazy?
(PANTING) Mike,
I don't know a single Scarer
who can do what you do.
I know,
everyone sees us together,
they think I'm the one running
the show, but the truth is,
I've been riding your
coattails since day one!
You made the deal
with Hardscrabble.
You took a hopeless team
and made them champions.
All I did was catch a pig!
Technically, I caught the pig.
Exactly! And you
think you're just okay?
You pulled off the biggest Scare
this school has ever seen!
That wasn't me!
That was you!
You think I could have
done that without you?
I didn't even bring a pencil
on the first day of school.
Mike, you're not scary.
Not even a little.
But you are fearless.
And if Hardscrabble can't see
that, then she can just...
I can just what?
Careful, Mr. Sullivan.
I was just warming up to you.
Sorry.
Well, gentlemen,
it seems you made
the front page again.
The two of you did
something together
that no one has
ever done before.
You surprised me.
Perhaps I should keep an
eye out for more surprises
like you in my program.
But as far as the two
of you are concerned
there is nothing
I can do for you now.
Except, perhaps, wish you luck.
And, Mr. Wazowski,
keep surprising people.
You know,
there is still one way
we can work at a Scare company.
They're always
hiring in the mailroom.
This is better
than I ever imagined!
I bet we break the all-time
record in our first year.
Mike, we're mail guys.
I know. I'm talking about the
record for letters delivered!
(GASPS)
All right, newbies,
quit goofing around.
I'll have you know tampering
with the mail is a crime
punishable by banishment!
Yes, sir.
We're right on it,
Mr. Snowman.
The team of
Wazowski and Sullivan
are going to change
the world starting today!
Say scream!
Scream!
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Wazowski, good luck
on your first day!
Thanks, Merv.
Good luck, Mike!
(ALL CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
You coming, Coach?
You better believe it.
(EXHALES)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(PANTING RAPIDLY)
(SIGHING LOUDLY)
I made it!
My first day of class!
Uh, the school year's over, son.
You missed it.
Great.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(PANTING RAPIDLY)