If I feel that I could be certain then
I would say the things, I want to say, to--
*upbeat music*
Hold it right there!
Go! Go! Go!
You were supposed to be keeping a lookout!
Sorry dad
My theater has been going through some pretty rough times, lately..!
So.. What do I do?
Quit?
No!
My next show is gonna be...
Drumroll please!
A singing competition!
Just think!
Your neighbor!
The-the grocery store manager!
That-that chicken!
Right there!
Real talent, from real life!
Norman, would you please tell them what a good singer I am?
Oh yeah, you're great honey
By the way, the bathroom sink is blocked again.
Im here to win...
That prize? It's mine!
Everyone in the city
Gets a shot at being a star
On my stage!
Ra-ra-ra-a-a
Roma roma-ma
Come-come my lady
Your my butterfly
Sugar baby
Ride...
Like the wind...
Ride like the
Oh..My..Gosh
Look at her..butt
Yeahhhh!!! Yea-yeaahh!
Are you okay?
Oh yes, I'm fine, thank you
How are you?
People say, yo humpty
Your really funny lookin'
Darling, stay... with me...
Wow!
This show is not gonna save your theater!
Maybe it's time to just.. move on
Come on! You know how much this means to us!
You can't just sing it!
You've got to show the fire on desire!
The fire went out a long time ago...
You are not going to believe what I did today!
*snoring*
*I am lost..*
*I am vain*
Dad, I just don't wanna be in your gang...
I wanna be a singer...
How did I end up with a son like you...
I'll get you out! Dad! Wait! I'll get the money! I promise!
I could really use some extra piano lessons
Yes... that was.. very bad
A defying moment in all of our lives!
We're going to be spicy, no?
Ya!
Yeah! Woohoo!
Don't let fear stop you from doing the thing you love
*cheering*
You know what's great about hitting rock bottom?
There's only one way left to go!
And that's.. up!
This store will close in 15 minutes
*yawning*
*upbeat music*
The lady in aisle 6...
That... was awesome
*cheering and clapping*
Sing!