(FOX FANFARE)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Lock on to em, R2.
ANAKIN: Master,
General Grievous's ship
is directly ahead...
the one crawling
with vulture droids.
Oh, I see it.
Oh, this is going be easy.
(DROID FIGHTERS
BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Oddball, do you copy?
MAN: (ON RADIO)
Copy, Red Leader.
Mark my position.
Form your squad up behind me.
We're on your tail,
General Kenobi.
Set S-foils in attack position.
This is where
the fun begins.
Let's them pass
between us.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
They're all over me.
Get them off my...(STATIC)
I'm gonna go help them out.
OBI-WAN: No! No.
They are doing their
job so we can do ours.
(SCREAMING)
(DROID BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Missiles! Pull up!
They overshot us!
They're coming around.
(R4 BEEPING NERVOUSLY)
All right, R4.
No, no, no, no.
No, nothing to fancy.
Search all power units, R2.
Stand by, reverse thrusters.
(ENGINE ACCLERATING LOUDLY)
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
- (LOUD BOOM)
- (LAUGHS)
We got em, R2.
(R2-D2 BEEPING HAPPILY)
Flying is for droids.
I'm hit! Anakin?
ANAKIN: I see them.
Buzz droids.
(BUZZ DROID LAUGHS
MANIACALLY)
(R4 WAILING HYSTERCALLY)
(SQUAWKING)
(CHIRPING SADLY)
R4, be careful!
You have a...
(R4 SCREAMING)
Oh, dear.
They're shutting down
all the controls.
Move to the right so I can
get a clear shot at them.
OBI-WAN: The mission!
Get to the command ship.
Get the chancellor.
OBI-WAN: I'm running
out of tricks here.
Oh! In the name of...
Hold your fire! You're
not helping here!
I agree. Bad idea.
(SCREAMING)
I can't see a thing.
My cockpit's fogging.
They're all over me! Anakin!
Move to the right.
Hold on, Anakin!
Your gonna get
us both killed!
Get out of here! There
nothing more you can do!
I'm not leaving
without you, Master.
(BUZZING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
- Get him, R2!
- (BUZZ DROID SQUAWKS)
- Watch out.
- (R2-D2 EXCLAIMING)
R2, hit the buzz
droid's center eye.
(BEEPS)
(R2-D2 BEEPING HAPPILY)
Yeah! You got him!
Great, R2!
The general's command
ship is dead ahead.
(R2-D2 SHRIEKING)
Well, have you noticed
the shields are still up?!
Sorry, Master!
Oh, I have a bad
feeling about this.
(DOOR CREAKING RAPIDLY)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
There they are! Get them!
(SCREAMS)
(ALL GROANING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
R2! Locate the chancellor!
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(GROANING CONTINUES)
- (LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
OBI-WAN: The
chancellor's signal...
is coming from right there.
The observation platform...
at the top of that spire.
ANAKIN: I sense Count Dooku.
- I sense a trap.
- Next move?
Spring the trap.
(R2-D2 WHISTLING RAPIDLY)
R2, go back.
I need you to stay
with the ship.
Here. Take this,
and wait for orders.
(BEEPING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
(COUGHING)
(COUGHING CONTINUES)
GRIEVOUS: What's
the situation...
Captain?
Two Jedi have landed...
in main hangar bay.
We're tracking them.
Just as Count Dooku
predicted.
(COUGHS)
(GRIEVOUS LAUGHING
MANIACALLY)
- (DROIDEKAS CLATTERING)
- Destroyers!
(WEAPONS COCKING)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
BATTLE DROID: Drop
your weapons.
I said drop 'em.
Roger, roger, roger
roger, roger.
- (LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
- (ALL GROANING)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
Those are Jedi
fighters all right.
(R2-D2 BEEPS SOFTLY)
- Did you press the stop button? No.
- No. Did you?
Well, there's more than
one way out of here.
OBI-WAN: We don't
want to get out.
We want to get moving. R2!
Activate elevator....
31174.
OBI-WAN: Come on, R2!
What's that?
- R2, do you copy?
- (R2-D2 WHIMPERS SOFTLY)
OBI-WAN: R2, activate
the elevator number...
- (MUFFLED) 31174.
- (CHIRPS SOFTLY)
Get back to work.
That nothin'.
OBI-WAN: (MUFFLED)
Activate the elevator... 31174.
R2, We...
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
(SIGHS) Always on the move.
OBI-WAN: R2, switch
on the comlink.
R2, can you hear me?
- R2!
- (BEEPING)
Whoa!
R2! R2!
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Stop! Stop!
R2, we need to be going up.
Hands up, Jedi.
OBI-WAN: R2, do you copy?
R2, do you hear me?
R2, we need to be going up.
Not down.
(GROANS)
(R2-D2 CHIRPS)
Hey, you!
(BEEPING)
Now, that's better.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
You stupid little...
astro droid.
- Uh, oh.
- (GRUNTS)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
- (LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
- Oh, It's you.
- (BEEPING)
- (GROANS)
My eyes!
What was that all about?
Well, R2 has been...
Uh, no loose wire jokes.
- Did I say anything?
- He's trying.
I didn't say anything.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
- Chancellor.
- Are you all right?
Count Dooku.
This time we'll do it together.
I was about to say that.
Get help. You're
no match for him.
He's a Sith lord.
Chancellor Palpatine.
Sith lords...
are our speciality.
DOOKU: Your swords, please.
We don't want to make
a mess of things...
in front of the chancellor.
You don't get away
this time, Dooku.
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(LIGHTSABERS CRACKLING)
I been looking forward to this.
My powers have
doubled since...
the last time we met, Count.
Good.
Twice the pride,
double the fall.
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(GROANS)
(WHOOSHES)
Get!
- (CHOKING)
- (ANAKIN EXCLAIMS)
(EXCLAIMS)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
- (YELLING)
- (GRUNTS)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
I sense great...
fear you, Skywalker.
You have hate.
You have anger.
(ANAKIN STRAINING SOFTLY)
But you don't use them.
(GRUNTS)
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(GROANS)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
Good, Anakin!
Good! (LAUGHING)
Kill him.
Kill him now.
I shouldn't.
Do it!
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
(SIGHS)
You did well, Anakin.
PALPATINE: He was
too dangerous...
to be kept alive.
Yes, but he was a
unarmed prisoner.
I shouldn't have done that.
It's not the Jedi way.
It is only natural.
He cut off your arm.
And you wanted revenge.
It wasn't the first
time, Anakin.
Remember you told
me about your mother...
and the sand people.
(TUSKEN RAIDERS
SCREAMING FAINTLY)
Now we must leave,
before more security
droids arrive.
Anakin.
There's no time.
We must get off the ship
before it's too late.
(SIGHS) He seems
to be all right.
Leave him, or we'll
never make it.
His fate will be
the same as ours.
GRIEVOUS: Prepare for attack!
All batteries!
Fire, fire!
(SCREAMING)
Elevator's not working.
R2, activate elevator...
3224.
(R2-D2 BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(GROANS)
- (R2-D2 WHISTLES)
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Reverse stabilizers.
Reversing stabilizers.
(R2-D2 BEEPING NERVOUSLY)
(R2-D2 SHRIEKING)
Magnetize! Magnetize!
(SHRIEKING)
(BEEPING)
Fire the emergency...
booster engines!
(ENGINES FIRING)
We're leveling out, sir.
(EXCLAIMS, GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMING)
ANAKIN: Easy!
We're in a bit of situation.
Did I miss something?
Hold on.
What is that?
Uh, oops. R2!
ANAKIN: R2, shut
down the elevator.
Too late! Jump!
(ELEVATOR ROARING)
(SHOUTS)
(ROARING CONTINUES)
(ALL GROANING)
Let's see if we can
find something...
in the hangar bay
that's still flyable.
- R2, get down here.
- (GRUNTS)
ANAKIN: R2, do you copy?
(R2-D2 CHIRPING FAINTLY)
- (COUGHING)
- General, we found the Jedi.
They're in hallway 328.
Activate...
ray shields.
- ANAKIN: Ray shields.
- OBI-WAN: Wait a minute.
How did this happen?
We're smarter than this.
Apparently not.
I say patience.
Patience.
Yes.
R2 we'll be out in a few
moments and then...
He'll release the ray shields.
(R2-D2 SCREAMING)
(SPUTTERS)
(SQUEAKS)
See? No problem.
(DROID BEEPING)
(WEAPON COCKING)
- Don't move. Ow!
- (BEEPS)
Do you have a plan B?
GRIEVOUS: Ah, yes.
The negotiator.
GRIEVOUS: General Kenobi.
We been waiting for you.
Excuse me.
That wasn't much...
a rescue.
Your welcome.
And...(COUGHS)
Anakin Skywalker.
I was expecting someone with
your reputation
to be a little...
older. (WHEEZES)
General Grievous.
Your shorter than I expected.
(COUGHS)
Jedi scum.
We have a job to do, Anakin.
Try not to upset him.
(R2-D2 BEEPS THEN CHIRPS)
(COUGHS)
Your lightsabers...
will make a fine addition...
to my collection.
- OBI-WAN: Not this time.
- (R2-D2 BEEPS)
And this time, you
won't escape.
R2!
(R2-D2 SCREAMING)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
- Crush them!
- (ALARM SOUNDING)
- (LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
- Make them suffer!
Come! Now!
- Stay at your stations!
- Whoa! Whoa!
(R2-D2 RAPIDLY BEEPING)
Get him! Get him!
BATTLE DROID: Ow!
(SCREAMS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Run!
(GROANING)
(SIGHING)
Don't bother with them.
- Keep the ship in orbit.
- Yes, sir.
(EXCLAIMING)
(YELLING)
(R2-D2 SQUEAKS THEN BEEPS)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
You lose,
General Kenobi.
- (LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATES)
- (GLASS BREAKING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(BOTH GASPING)
(CRUMPLING EXPLOSIONS)
- Get out of here! Run!
- (SCREAMING)
(LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
R2-D2: Eh-oh!
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
Time to abandon ship.
(BEEPS)
(LAUGHS, COUGHS)
(ALARM BLARING)
All the escape pods
have been launched.
- OBI-WAN: Grievous.
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
Can you fly a cruiser like this?
You mean, do I know how to land
what's left of this thing?
Well.
Well, under the circumstances,
I'd say the ability to pilot
this thing is irrelevant.
Strap yourselves in.
Open all hatches. Extend
all flaps and drag fins.
(SQUEAKING, WHISTLING)
(LOUD BOOMING)
(BANGING)
R2-D2: Uh-oh!
We lost something.
Not to worry.
We are still flying
half a ship.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Now, we're really
picking up speed.
OBI-WAN: 8 plus 60.
We're in the atmosphere.
Grab that. Keep us level.
(CHIRPING, BEEPING)
Steady.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
Easy, R2!
OBI-WAN: 5000.
Fire ships on the
left and the right.
We'll take you in.
OBI-WAN: Copy that.
Landing strip,
straight ahead.
We're coming in too hot.
(CHIRPING, WHISTLING)
(R2-D2 SHRIEKING)
(SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
(R2-D2 CHIRPS SOFTLY)
(ANAKIN SIGHING HEAVILY)
Another happy landing.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(R2-D2 CHIRPING)
ANAKIN: Are you
coming, Master?
Oh, no. I'm not brave
enough for politics.
I have to report
to the council.
Besides, someone needs
to be the poster boy.
Hold on.
This whole operation
was your idea.
Let us not forget, Anakin,
that you rescued me
from the buzz droids.
And you killed Count Dooku,
and you rescued
the chancellor.
Carry me unconscious
on your back.
All because of your training.
Anakin.
Let's be fair. Today
you were the hero.
And you deserve
your glorious...
day with the politicians.
All right. But you owe me one.
and not for saving your
skin for the 10th time.
9th time.
That business on Cato
Neimoidia doesn't...
doesn't count.
I'll see you in briefing.
WINDU: Chancellor Palpatine.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Thanks to your two
Jedi knights.
They killed Count Dooku.
But, General Grievous...
has escaped once again.
General Grievous
will run and hide,
as he always does.
He's a coward.
But with Count Dooku dead,
he is the leader
of the droid army.
And I assure you,
the senate will vote to...
continue the war
as long as Grievous is alive.
Then the Jedi
Council will make
finding Grievous our
highest priority.
- Watch it.
- JAR JAR: Excuse me.
C-3PO: Come along, R2.
ORGANA: The Republic
cannot praise you enough.
Thank you, Sentor Organa.
(BEEPING)
Well, it couldn't possibly
be as bad as all that.
(BEEPING)
Now there I agree with you.
In fact, I could do
with a tune-up myself.
But the fighting
will continue until
General Grievous is...
spare parts.
ORGANA: Well, I
will do everything...
I can in the senate.
- Excuse me.
- Certainly.
(R2-D2 CHIRPS)
(ANAKIN SIGHS)
PADME: Oh, Anakin.
(SIGHS)
I've missed you, Padme.
There were whispers...
that you'd been killed.
I'm all right.
It feels like we've been
apart for a lifetime.
And it might have been,
if the chancellor...
hadn't been kidnapped.
I don't think they would
have ever brought us back...
from the outer rim sieges.
- Wait. Not here.
- Yes, here.
(STAMMERS) I'm tired
of all this deception.
I don't care if they
know we're married.
Anakin, don't say things like that.
(SIGHS)
Are you all right?
You're trembling.
What's going on?
Something wonderful
has happened.
Ani.
I'm pregnant.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
That's...
(SIGHS)
Well, (STAMMERS)
That's wonderful.
What are we gonna do?
We're not gonna worry
about anything right now.
All right?
This is a happy moment.
A happiest moment of my life.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHROUS VOCALIZING)
(GRIEVOUS WHEEZES)
(COUGHING)
(BEEPING)
GRIEVOUS: Yes,
Lord Sidious?
SIDIOUS: General Grievous.
I suggest you move...
the separatist leaders...
to Mustafar.
It will be done,
my lord.
The end of the war
is near, General.
But the loss of...
Count Dooku.
His death...
was a...
necessary loss.
Soon I will have a...
new apprentice...
one far...
younger...
and more...
powerful.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Ani, I want to
have our baby...
back home on Naboo.
We can go to the
lake country...
where no one will know,
or we can be safe.
I can go early and fix
up the baby's room.
I know the perfect spot.
Right by the gardens.
You're so...
beautiful.
It's only because
I'm so in love.
No. (LAUGHS)
No, It's because I'm
so in love with you.
So love has blinded you?
(ANAKIN LAUGHS SOFTLY)
Well, that's not
extactly what I meant.
That's probably true.
(SLOW-TUNE PLAYING)
(BABY CRYING HYSTERCALLY)
(GROANS)
(SOBBING) Anakin! Help me!
(SCREAMING)
(BABY'S CRY FADES)
(PANTING HEAVILY)
What's bothering you?
(SIGHS) Nothing.
I remember when
I gave this to you.
How long is it
gonna take for us
to be honest with each other?
It was a dream.
Bad?
Like the ones I used to
have about my mother.
Just before she died.
And?
And, it was about you.
Tell me.
(SIGHS) It was only a dream.
You died in childbirth.
And the baby.
I don't know.
It was only a dream.
I won't let this one become real.
This baby will change our lives.
I doubt the queen
will continue to...
allow me to serve
in the senate.
And if the council discovers
you're the father,
you'll be expelled-
I know, I know.
Do you think...
Obi-Wan might be
able to help us?
We don't need his help.
Our baby...
is a blessing.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYS)
YODA: Premonitions?
Premonitions. Hmm.
These visions you have.
They're of pain...
suffering.
Death.
Yourself you speak of,
or someone you know?
Someone.
Close to you?
Yes.
Careful you must be...
when sensing the
future, Anakin.
The fear of loss...
is a path to the dark side.
I won't let these visions...
come true, Master Yoda.
YODA: Death is a natural...
part of life.
Rejoice for those
around you...
who transform into the Force.
Mourn them, do not.
Miss them, do not.
Attachment...
leads to jealousy.
The shadow of greed,
that is.
What must I do, Master Yoda?
Train yourself
to let go...
of everything you...
fear to lose.
OBI-WAN: You've missed the
report on the outer rim sieges.
ANAKIN: I'm sorry,
I was held up.
I have no excuse.
OBI-WAN: In short.
They are going very well.
Saleucami has fallen,
and Master Vos has
moved his troops...
to Boz Pity.
What's wrong, then?
The senate is expected...
to vote more
executive powers...
to the chancellor today.
Well, that can only mean
less deliberating...
and more action.
Is that bad?
It'll make it easier for
us to end this war.
Be cafeful for you
friend, Palpatine.
Be careful of what?
He has requested your presence.
- ANAKIN: What for?
- OBI-WAN: He would not say.
He didn't inform the council?
That's unusual, isn't it?
All of this is unusual.
And it's making me feel uneasy.
I hope you trust me, Anakin.
Of course.
I need your help, son.
What do you mean?
I'm depending on you.
For what? I don't understand.
To be the eyes,
ears and
voice of the Republic.
Anakin.
I'm appointing you
to be my personal
representative on
the Jedi Council.
Me?
A master?
I'm overwhelmed, sir.
But the council elects
its own members.
They'll never accept this.
I think they will.
They need you.
More than you know.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
YODA: Allow this
appointment lightly...
The council does not.
Disturbing is this move...
by Chancellor Palpatine.
I understand.
Your on this council.
But we do not grant you
the rank of master.
What?
How can you do this?
This is outrageous.
It's unfair.
How can you be on
the council...
and not be a master?
Take a seat...
Young Skywalker.
Forgive me, Master.
KI-ADI-MUNDI: We have
surveyed all systems...
in the Republic,
but have found no sign...
of General Grievous.
Hiding in the outer rim...
Grievous is.
The outlying systems...
you must sweep.
We do not have
many ships to spare.
What about the droid
attack on the Wookiees?
WINDU: It is critical we
send an attack group...
there immediately.
He's right.
It's a system we
cannot afford to lose.
Go, I will.
Good relations with...
the Wookiees I have.
It's settled in.
Yoda will take a battalion...
of clones to reinforce
the Wookiees...
on Kashyyyk.
May the Force be with us all.
ANAKIN: What kind of
nonsense this is?
Put me on the council and
not make me a master?
It's never been done in
the history of the Jedi.
- It's insulting.
- Oh, calm down, Anakin.
You have been given
a great honor.
To be on the council
at your age-
it's never happened before.
The fact of the
matter is you are
too close to the chancellor.
The council doesn't like it...
when he interferes
in Jedi affairs.
I swear to you,
I didn't ask to be
put on the council.
But it's what you wanted.
Your friendship with
Chancellor Palpatine...
seems to have paid off.
That has nothing to do with this.
The only reason
the council...
has approved your
appointment...
is because the
chancellor trusts you.
And?
Anakin, I am on your side.
I didn't want to put
you in this situation.
What situation?
The council wants
you to report
on all the
chancellor's dealings.
They want to know
what he's up to.
ANAKIN: They want me to
spy on the chancellor.
But that's treason.
OBI-WAN: We are
at war, Anakin.
Why didn't the council
give me this...
assignment when we
were in session?
This assignment does
not to be on record.
The chancellor is not
a bad man, Obi-Wan.
He befriended me.
He's watched out for me
ever since I arrived here.
That is why you must help us.
Anakin.
Our allegiance is
to the senate,
not to its leader,
who has managed
to stay in office...
long after his
term has expired.
The senate demanded
that he stay longer.
Yes, but use your
feelings, Anakin.
Something is out of place.
(SIGHS)
You're asking me
to do something...
against the Jedi code,
against the Republic,
against a mentor
and a friend.
That was out of place here.
Why are you asking
this of me?
The council is asking you.
Anakin did not
take to his new...
assignment with
much enthusiasm.
WINDU: It's very dangerous,
putting them together.
I don't think the boy
could handle it.
I don't trust him.
With all due respect, Master...
is he not the chosen one?
Is he not to destroy the Sith...
and bring balance
to the Force?
So the prophecy says.
YODA: A prophecy...
that misread...
could have been.
He will not let me down.
He never has.
I hope right you are.
(SIGHS)
Sometimes I wonder what's...
happening to the Jedi order.
I think this war
is destroying...
the principles
of the Republic.
Have you ever
considered that...
we may be on the wrong side?
What do you mean?
What if the democracy
we thought
we were serving
no longer exists,
and the Republic has
become the very...
evil we've been
fighting to destroy?
I don't believe that.
And you're sounding
like a separatist.
This war represents a
failure to listen.
Now you're closer to the
chancellor than anyone.
Please, ask him to
stop the fighting...
and let diplomacy resume.
Don't ask me to do that.
Make a motion in the senate,
where that kind of
a request belongs.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
Don't do this.
Don't shut me out.
Let me help you.
Hold me.
Like you did by the lake on Naboo.
So long ago, when there...
was nothing but our love.
No politics,
no plotting, no war.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(DRONING)
(APPLAUSE)
(DRONING CONTINUES)
You wanted to see
me, Chancellor.
Yes, Anakin.
Come closer.
I have good news.
Our clone intelligence...
units have...
discovered the location...
of General Grievous.
He's hiding...
in the Utapau system.
ANAKIN: At last.
We'll be able to
capture that...
monster and end this war.
I would worry about
the collective...
wisdom of the council...
if it didn't select you...
for this assignment.
You're the best choice...
by far.
Mmm.
Sit down.
(SOFTLY) Leave us.
(APPLAUSE)
Anakin.
You know I'm not able...
to rely on...
the Jedi Council.
If they haven't
included you...
in their plot,
they soon will.
I'm not sure I understand.
You must sense...
what I have come to suspect.
The Jedi Council...
want control of the Republic.
They're planing to betray me.
- I don't think...
- Anakin.
Search your feelings.
You know?
Don't you?
I know they don't trust you.
Hmm. Or the senate.
Or the Republic.
Or democracy, for
that matter.
I have to admit...
my trust in them
has been shaken.
Why?
They asked you
to do something...
that made you feel
dishonest, didn't they?
They asked you to spy
on me, didn't they?
I don't, uh...
I don't know what to say.
Remember back to...
your early teachings.
All who gain power...
are afraid to lose it.
Even the Jedi.
The Jedi use their
power for good.
Good is a point of view, Anakin.
The Sith and the Jedi...
are similar in almost...
every way,
including their quest...
for greater power.
The Sith rely on their...
passion for their strength.
They think inwards only...
about themselves.
And the Jedi don't.
The Jedi are selfless.
They only care about others.
(APPLAUSE)
Did you ever hear...
the tragedy of...
Darth Plagueis the Wise?
- No.
- I thought not.
It's not a story the
Jedi would tell you.
It's a Sith legend.
Darth Plagueis...
was a dark lord of the Sith
so powerful and...
so wise,
he could use the Force...
to influence the
midi-chlorians...
to create...
life.
He had such a knowledge...
of the dark side,
he could even...
keep the ones...
he cared about...
from dying.
He could actually...
save people from death?
The dark side of the Force...
is the path way...
to many abilities...
some consider...
to be...
unnatural.
(STAMMERS)
What happened to him?
He became so powerful,
the only thing he was
afraid of was...
losing his power.
Which eventually,
of course, he did.
Unfortunately...
he taught his apprentice...
everything he knew.
Then his apprentice...
killed him in his sleep.
It's ironic.
He could save others
from death...
but not himself.
Is it possible...
to learn this power?
Not from a Jedi.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN: All Red units, over here!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
KI: Palpatine thinks
General Grievous...
is on Utapau?
ANAKIN: A partial
message was...
intercepted in a
diplomatic packet...
from the chairman of Utapau.
Hmm.
YODA: Act on this we must.
The capture...
of General Grievous...
will end this war.
Quickly and decisively...
we should proceed.
The chancellor
has requested...
that I lead the campaign.
WINDU: The council
will make up
its own mind who is to go,
not the chancellor.
A master is needed,
with more experience.
I concur.
Master Kenobi should go.
YODA: I agree.
- KI: Aye.
- WINDU: Aye.
WINDU: Very well.
- Council adjourned.
- (CHEWIE GRUNTS)
(WOOKIES GROWLING SOFTLY)
(CHEWIE ROARS)
The droids have
started up their...
main power generators.
Then now...
the time is...
Commander.
Yes, sir.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL WOOKIES ROARING
INDISTINCTLY)
BATTLE DROID: Charge!
(WEAPONS FIRING)
(SCREAMS)
MAN: Head for cover!
(EXCLAIMS)
(TARZAN YELL)
(ROARS)
Your gonna need
me on this one, Master.
Oh, I agree.
However, it may
turn out just...
to be a wild bantha chase.
Master.
I disappointed you.
Uh, I haven't been very...
appreciative ofyour training.
I've been arrogant,
and I apologize.
I've just been so frustrated
with the council.
You are strong and
wise, Anakin,
and I am very proud of you.
I have trained you since...
you were a small boy.
I have taught you everything I know.
And you have become
a far greater
Jedi than I could
ever hope to be.
But be patient, Anakin.
It will not be
long before the...
council makes you
a Jedi master.
Obi-Wan.
May the Force be with you.
Goodbye, old friend.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
CODY: Fortunately,
most of the cities are...
concentrated on this
small continent here.
On the far side.
I'll keep them distracted
until you get there.
Just don't take too long.
Come on. When have I
ever let you down?
(LAUGHS) Very well.
The burden is on
me not to destroy...
all the droids
until you arrive.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Save your energy.
(SIGHS) I can't.
Don't give up, Padme.
(SIGHS)
Obi-Wan's been here, hasn't he?
He came by this morning.
What did he want?
He's worried about you.
He says you've been
under a lot of stress.
(SIGHS)
I feel lost.
Lost?
What do you mean?
Obi-Wan and the council
don't trust me.
They trust you with their lives.
Something's happening.
I'm not the Jedi I should be.
I want more.
That I know I shouldn't.
You expect too much of yourself.
I found a way to save you.
Save me?
From my nightmares.
Is that what's bothering you?
I won't lose you, Padme.
I'm not gonna die in childbirth, Ani.
- I promise you.
- No, I promise you.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SQUAWKING INSTANTLY)
Greetings, young Jedi.
What brings you...
to our remote sanctuary?
Unfortunately, the war.
There's no war here.
Unless you brought it with you.
With your kind permission,
I should like some fuel...
and to use your city as...
a base as I search
nearby systems...
for General Grievous.
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
He is here.
We are being held hostage.
They are watching us.
I understand.
Tenth level...
thousands of...
battle droids.
Tell your people to take shelter.
If you have warriors,
now is the time.
Take the fighter
back to the ship.
Tell Cody...
I've made contact.
(DROID BEEPING)
Is he bringing
additional warriors?
He didn't say.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SQUAWKING)
(YIPPING)
(SNARLS)
(YIPPING CONTINUES)
(GROWLS)
(YIPS)
(SNARLS)
GRIEVOUS: It won't be long...
before the armies of...
the Republic...
track us here.
(WHEEZING QUIETLY)
I am sending you
to the Mustafar system...
in the outer rim.
(YIPPING)
It is the volcanic planet.
You will be safe there.
Safe?
VICEROY: Hmph!
Chancellor Palpatine
managed...
to escape your grip, General.
Without Count Dooku...
I have doubts about your...
ability to keep us safe.
GRIEVOUS: Be thankful, Viceroy.
you have not found
yourself...
in my grip.
GRIEVOUS: Your ship...
is waiting.
(GRIEVOUS COUGHS FAINTLY)
(HISSES)
(SNORTS SOFTLY)
Hello there.
(WEAPON ACTIVATING)
General Kenobi.
(LAUGHING EXCITEDLY)
You are a bold one.
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
Kill him.
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(WHIMPERING)
(WEAPONS COCKING)
Back away!
I will deal with this
Jedi slime...
myself.
Your move.
You fool!
I been trained...
in you Jedi arts...
by Count...
Dooku.
(COUGHING RAPIDLY)
(LIGHTSABERS ACTIVATING)
Attack..
Kenobi!
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
(CRACKLING)
(GRUNTING)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
MAN #1: Go, go, go, go!
Move it! Move it!
Everybody out.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
MAN #2: Cover yourself. Come on.
- (LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
- MAN #1: Move it! Move it!
(ALL GROANING INDISTINCTLY)
MAN #1: Come on, move!
Come on, everybody!
Army or not.
You must realize.
You are...
doomed.
Oh, I don't think so.
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTS)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTS)
(WHISTLES)
Uh-oh!
(YIPPING)
Hyah!
(EXCLAIMS)
(SCREAMING)
(OBI-WAN EXCLAIMING)
(SCREAMS)
MAN: Cover that corner.
CODY: Master Windu,
may I interrupt?
General Kenobi
has made contact
with General Grievous,
and we have begun our attack.
WINDU: Thank you, Commander.
Anakin,
deliver this report
to the chancellor.
His reaction will give us...
a clue to his intentions.
Yes, Master.
I sense a plot...
to destroy the Jedi.
The dark side of the Force...
surrounds the chancellor.
If he does not give up his...
emergency powers after the...
destruction of Grievous...
then he should be...
removed from office.
The Jedi Council
would have to
take control of the senate...
in order to secure a peaceful transition.
To a dark place...
this line of thought
will carry us.
Hmm.
Great care...
we must take.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Chancellor.
We've just received a report...
from Master Kenobi.
He has engaged General Grievous.
We can only hope
that Master Kenobi...
is up to the challenge.
I should be there with him.
It's upsetting to me...
to see that the council...
doesn't seem to fully...
appreciate your talents.
Don't you wonder...
why they won't make...
you a Jedi master?
I wish I knew.
More and more I get
the feeling that...
I'm being excluded
from the council.
I know there are
things about...
the Force that they're
not telling me.
They don't trust you, Anakin.
They see your future.
They know your power...
will be too strong...
to control.
You must break through...
the fog of lies...
the Jedi have
created around you.
Let me help you to know...
the subtleties of the Force.
How do you know the
ways of the Force?
My mentor taught
me everything...
about the Force.
Even the nature of...
the dark side.
You know the dark side?
Anakin.
If one is to understand...
the great mystery,
one must study...
all its aspects,
not just the dogmatic...
narrow view of the Jedi.
If you wish to
become a complete...
and wise leader,
you must embrace...
a larger view of the Force.
Be careful of the Jedi, Anakin.
Only through me...
can you achieve a power...
greater than any Jedi.
Learn to know the...
dark side of the force...
and you'll be able...
to save your wife...
from certain death.
What did you say?
Use my knowledge,
I beg you.
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
Your the Sith lord.
I know what's been
troubling you.
Listen to me.
Don't continue to be a...
pawn of the Jedi Council.
Ever since I've known you...
you've been searching
for a life...
greater than that of
an ordinary Jedi.
A life of significance...
of conscience.
(LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
Are you going to kill me?
I would certainly like to.
(WHISPERS SOFTLY) I know you would.
I can...
feel your...
anger.
It gives you focus...
makes you stronger.
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATES)
I'm going to turn you...
over to the Jedi Council.
Of course. You should.
But you're not sure of...
their intentions, are you?
I will quickly discover
the truth of all this.
You have...
great wisdom, Anakin.
Know the power...
of the dark side.
Power to save...
Padme.
(YIPPING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(YIPS)
- (SHOUTS)
- (GROWLS)
(YIPPING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROWLING ANGRILLY)
(CLANGING)
(WEAPON ACTIVATES)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(ROARING)
(GROWLS)
(GROANS)
(GROWLING)
(GASPS)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMS, GROANS)
- (SCREAMS)
- (LAUGHS)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING IN PAIN)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
- (GROANS)
- (GRUNTS)
(GROWLS)
(GROANING SOFTLY)
(GROANING CONTINUES)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
So uncivilized.
(CLANGS)
(SIZZLING)
ANAKIN: Master Windu.
I must talk to you.
WINDU: Skywalker.
We just received word
that Obi-Wan has...
destroyed General Grievous.
We're on our way to make
sure the chancellor returns
emergency power
back to the senate.
(SIGHS) He won't
give up his power.
I've just learned
a terrible truth.
I think Chancellor
Palpatine is a Sith lord.
A Sith lord?
Yes. The one we've
been looking for.
How do you know this?
He knows the ways
of the Force.
He's been trained to
use the dark side.
Are you sure?
Absolutely.
Then our worst fears
have been realized.
We must move quickly if the...
Jedi order is to survive.
Master, the chancellor
is very powerful.
You'll need my help if
you're going to arrest him.
For your own good,
stay out of this affair.
I sense a great
deal of confusion...
in you, young Skywalker.
There is much fear that
clouds your judgment.
I must go, Master.
No.
If what you've told me is true,
you will have gained my trust.
But for now, remain here.
Wait in the council
chambers...
until we return.
- (WHIRRING)
- Yes, Master.
PALPATINE: You do know...
don't you,
if the Jedi...
destroy me,
any chance of saving...
her will be lost.
(VOCALIZING)
(VOCALIZING CONTINUES)
(VOCALIZING ENDS)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Master Windu.
I take it General Grievous...
is been destroyed then.
I must say you're here...
sooner than expected.
In the name of the Galactic...
Senate of the Republic.
- (LIGHTSABERS ACTIVATING)
- Your under arrest, Chancellor.
Are you threatening
me, Master Jedi?
The senate will
decide your fate.
I am...
the senate.
Not yet.
It's treason...
then.
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(PALPATINE ROARING ANGRILLY)
(ROARS)
(SCREAMING)
(LIGHTSABERS CRACKLING)
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTING)
(CRACKLES)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SNARLS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(EXCLAIMING)
(LIGHTSABER HUMS)
WINDU: You are
under arrest...
my lord.
Anakin.
I told you it would
come to this.
PALPATINE: I was right.
The Jedi are taking over!
The impression of the Sith...
will never return.
You have lost.
No.
No, no!
You will die!
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
He's a traitor!
He is the traitor!
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
I have the power...
to save the ones you love.
EMPEROR: You must choose!
Don't listen to him, Anakin!
(SCREAMS)
Don't let it kill me.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
I can't hold on any longer!
(STAMMERING)
I can't.
I'm weak.
I'm—
I'm too weak.
- Anakin!
- (GRUNTS)
Help me!
(GROANS)
(STAMMERING)
I can't hold on any longer.
I am going to end this
once and for all.
ANAKIN: You can't.
He must stand trial.
WINDU: He has control
of the senate...
and the courts!
He's too dangerous...
to be left alive!
I'm too weak.
Oh, don't kill me.
Please.
ANAKIN: It's not
the Jedi way!
He must live!
Please don't!
I need him!
- No!
- (LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(WINDU SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(YELLING) Power!
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
(YELLING) Unlimited...
power!
(WINDU GROANS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SIGHING)
What have I done?
(MOANS SOFTLY)
EMPEROR: You're fulfilling...
your destiny...
Anakin.
Become...
my apprentice.
Learn to use...
the dark side...
of the Force.
I will do whatever you...
ask.
Good.
Just help me save
Padme's life.
I can't live without her.
(BREATHING SOFTLY)
To cheat death...
is a power only
one has achieved,
but if we...
work together...
I know we can...
discover the secret.
I pledge myself...
to your teachings.
(MURMURS SOFTLY)
Good.
(SOFTLY) Good.
(RASPY BREATHING)
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
The force...
is strong...
with you.
A powerful Sith...
you will become.
Henceforth.
you should be...
known has...
Darth...
Vader.
(DARTH VADER THEME PLAYING)
Thank you...
my master.
Rise.
(MURMURS SOFTLY)
Because the council...
did not trust you,
my young apprentice,
I believe...
you are the only Jedi
with no knowledge
of this plot.
When the Jedi learn what
has transpired here,
they will kill us,
along with all the senators.
I agree.
The council's next move...
will be against the senate.
Every...
single Jedi...
including your friend
Obi-Wan Kenobi,
is now an enemy...
of the Republic.
I understand, Master.
We must move quickly.
The Jedi are relentless.
If they are not
all destroyed,
it will be...
civil war...
without end.
First...
I want you to go
to the Jedi temple.
We will catch them off-balance.
Do what...
must be done...
Lord Vader.
Do not hesitate.
Show no mercy.
Only then,
when you'll be
strong enough...
with the dark side...
to save Padme.
What about the other Jedi...
spread across the galaxy?
Their betrayal...
will be dealt with.
After you have killed
all the Jedi in the temple,
go the...
Mustafar system.
Wipeout...
Viceroy...
Gunray...
and the other...
separatist leaders.
Once more...
the Sith will...
rule the galaxy!
And...
we shall...
have...
peace.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Sergeant, over here!
Hurry! Follow them!
(SCREAMING)
All Red units, let's move it!
(SCREECHES)
(YIPPING)
OBI-WAN: Commander,
contact your troops.
Tell them to move to
the higher levels.
Very good, sir.
Oh, by the way...
I think you'll be
needing this.
Thank you, Cody.
Now let's get a move on.
We've got a battle
to win here.
- Hyah!
- Yes, sir.
(BEEPING)
EMPEROR: Commander Cody.
The time...
has come.
Execute...
order...
66.
- Yes, my lord.
- (BEEPS)
(YIPPING)
Blast him!
(SHRIEKING)
(WATER SPLASHING)
Come on!
(WEAPONS COCKING)
(GROANS)
- (CHORUS VOCALIZING)
- (SQUAWKING RAPIDLY)
(WEAPONS COCKS)
(VOCALIZING ENDS)
Execute order...
66.
It will be done, my lord.
(SQUAWKING)
- It will be done, my lord.
- (BEEPS)
(WEAPONS COCKS)
(GRUNTS)
(WOOKIES ROARING LOUDLY)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
(ROARING CONTINUES)
(BOTH MURMURING)
(CHEWIE ROARING)
Master Skywalker.
There too many of them.
What are we going to do?
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
C-3PO: The chancellor's
office indicated....
Master Anakin returned...
to the Jedi temple.
Don't worry.
I'm sure he'll be all right.
(SOBBING SOFTLY)
(CHORUS VOCALIZING)
What's going on here?
There's been a
rebellion, sir.
Don't worry. The situation
is under control.
- (BLASTER COCKS)
- I'm sorry, sir.
It's time for you to leave.
And so it is.
- (LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
- Get him!
(GROANING)
No!
Don't worry about him.
Let him go.
(BREATHER BUBBLES)
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTING)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
All these Wookies are dead.
Move to the east.
Yes, sir.
(MURMURS SOFTLY)
Good-bye, Tarfful.
Good-bye, Chewbacca.
(CHEWIE ROARING)
Miss you, I will.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
(BOTH MURMURING)
(GROWLS)
(MURMURS)
(CHEWIE EXCLAIMING)
Hopefully we'll be
able to intercept
a few Jedi...
before they walk into
this catastrophe.
CODY: Did you find Kenobi?
Sir, no one could have
survived that fall.
CODY: Start loading
your men on the ships.
Move it!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(HISSES)
(BEEPING)
Emergency code 913.
I have no contact
on any frequency.
(DISTORED) Master Kenobi.
- Repeat.
- ORGANA: Master Kenobi.
Senator Organa.
My clone troops turned on me.
I need help.
We have just rescued
Master Yoda.
It appears this ambush
has happened everywhere.
We're sending you
our coordinates.
(R2-D2 BEEPING NERVOUSLY)
Hush! Not so loud.
Are you all right?
I heard there was an
attack on the Jedi temple.
You could see the
smoke from here.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
I came to see ifyou
and the baby are safe.
What's happening?
The Jedi have tried to
overthrow the Republic.
I can't believe that.
I saw Master Windu
attempt to...
assassinate the
chancellor myself.
Oh, Anakin.
What are you gonna do?
I will not betray the Republic.
My loyalties lie with
the chancellor...
and with the senate...
and with you.
What about Obi-Wan?
I don't know.
Many Jedi have been killed.
We can only hope
that he's remained...
loyal to the chancellor.
Anakin, I'm afraid.
Have faith in my love.
Everything will
soon be set right.
The chancellor has
given me a...
very important mission.
The separatists
have gathered...
on the Mustafar system.
I'm going there to end this war.
Wait for me until I return.
Things will be different.
I promise.
Please, wait for me.
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
Well, he is under a
lot of stress, R2.
(BEEPING)
Take care, my little friend.
Oh, my lady,
is there anything I might do?
No, thank you, 3PO.
Oh,
(STAMMERS) I feel so...
helpless.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
How many other Jedi have
managed to survive?
Hmm.
Heard from no one have we.
I saw thousands of troops...
attack the Jedi temple.
That's why I went
looking for Yoda.
Have we had any contact
from the temple?
Received a coded retreat...
message we have.
It requests all Jedi...
to return to the temple.
It says the war is over.
Well, then we must go back.
If there are any
stragglers, they will...
fall into the trap
and be killed.
Hmm.
Suggest dismantling...
the coded signal, do you?
Yes, Master. There is
too much at stake.
I agree.
And a little more
knowledge...
might light our way.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
The plan has gone as you...
had promised, my lord.
You have done well...
Viceroy.
When my new apprentice
Darth Vader arrives,
he will take...
care of you.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
We're receiving a message...
from the chancellor's office, sir.
- Send it through.
- Yes, sir.
Senator Organa.
The supreme chancellor...
requests your presence...
at a special session of Congress.
I will be there.
He'll be expecting you.
Could be a trap.
I don't think so.
The chancellor will not
be able to control...
the thousands of
star systems...
without keeping the
senate intact.
If a special session...
of Congress there is,
easier for us to enter...
the Jedi temple it will be.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(R2-D2 EXCLAIMS)
(R2-D2 WHISTLES)
R2, stay with the ship.
(BEEPING)
(R2-D2 WHISTLING DEJECTEDLY)
(ALL CLAMORING IN
ALIEN DIALECT)
(BEEPING, SQUEAKING)
Welcome, Lord Vader.
We've been expecting you.
(DARTH VADER THEME PLAYING)
- (SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
EMPEROR: And the Jedi...
rebellion has...
been foiled.
What's happened?
The chancellor's
been elaborating...
on a plot by the Jedi...
to overthrow the senate.
The remaining Jedi...
will be hunted...
down and defeated!
(APPLAUSE)
Not even the
younglings survived.
Killed not by clones...
this...
Padawan.
By a lightsaber...
he was.
Who?
Who could have done this?
(GROANS)
The attempt on my life...
has left me scarred...
and deformed.
But I assure you.
My resolve...
has never...
been stronger!
(APPLAUSE)
Stop!
No!
(SCREAMS)
(CHORUS VOCALIZING)
In order to ensure...
the security...
and continuing...
stability,
the Republic...
will be reorganized...
into the first...
Galactic...
Empire!
For a safe...
and secure...
society!
- (APPLAUSE)
- (VOCALIZING CONTINUES)
So, this is how liberty dies.
With thunderous applause.
The war is over.
Lord Sidious...
promised us peace.
We only want-(SCREAMS)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATES)
(VOCALIZING ENDS)
I have recalibrated the code,
warning all surviving...
Jedi to stay away.
For the clones...
to discover the
recalibration...
a long time it will take.
Wait. Master.
OBI-WAN: There is
something I must know.
If into the security...
recordings you go,
only pain will you find.
I must know the truth, Master.
(LIGHTSABER WHOOSHING FAINTLY)
(MURMURS SOFTLY)
It can't be.
EMPEROR: You have
done well...
my new apprentice.
Now...
Lord Vader.
Go and bring...
peace to the empire.
- (CLICKS)
- I can't watch anymore.
Destory the Sith...
we must.
Send me to kill the emperor.
I will not kill Anakin.
To fight this Lord Sidious...
strong enough...
you are not.
He is like my brother.
I cannot do it.
Twisted...
by the dark side...
young Skywalker has become.
The boy you trained...
gone he is.
Consumed...
by Darth Vader.
I do not know where the
emperor has sent him.
I don't know where to look.
Use your feelings, Obi-Wan.
And find him you will.
OBI-WAN: When was the
last time you saw him?
Yesterday.
And do you know
where he is now?
No.
Padme.
I need your help.
He's in grave danger.
From the Sith?
From himself.
Padme...
Anakin has turned
to the dark side.
You're wrong.
How could you even say that?
I've seen a...
secruity hologram...
of him...
killing younglings.
Not Anakin.
He couldn't.
He was deceived by a lie.
We all were.
OBI-WAN: It appears
that the chancellor
is behind everything,
including the war.
Palpatine is the Sith lord
we've been looking for.
After the death
of Count Dooku,
Anakin became his
new apprentice.
I don't believe you!
I can't.
Padme.
I must find him.
You're going to kill
him, aren't you?
He has become a...
very great threat.
I can't.
Anakin is the father, isn't he?
I'm so sorry.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
TYPHO: Milady, let
me come with you.
PADME: There's no danger.
The fighting's over.
And this is personal.
As you wish, milady,
but I strongly disagree.
I'll be all right, Captain.
This is something
I must do myself.
Besides, 3PO will
look after me.
C-3PO: Oh, dear.
(BEEPS)
Do you know? I think
I'm beginning...
to get the hang of
this flying business.
Hmm.
(ENGINES REVVING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
ANAKIN: The
separatists have been....
taken care of, my master.
EMPEROR: It is...
finished, then.
You have restored...
peace and justice...
to the galaxy.
Send a message...
to the ships of the...
Trade Federation.
All droid units...
must shut down...
immediately.
Very good, my lord.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(HATCH OPENS)
ANAKIN: I saw your ship.
What are you doing out here?
I was so worried about you.
Obi-Wan...
told me terrible things.
What things?
He said...
you've turned to
the dark side.
That you...
killed younglings.
Obi-Wan is trying to...
turn you against me.
He cares about us.
Us?
He knows.
He wants to help you.
Anakin...
all I want is your love.
Love won't save you, Padme.
Only my new powers can do that.
At what cost?
You're a good person.
Don't do this.
I won't lose you the
way I lost my mother.
I am becoming
more powerful...
than any Jedi has
ever dreamed of.
And I'm doing it for you.
To protect you.
Come away with me.
Help me raise our child.
Leave everything else...
behind while we still can.
Don't you see?
We don't have to
run away anymore.
I brought peace
to the Republic.
I am more powerful
than the chancellor.
I— I can overthrow him.
And together, you and I
can rule the galaxy,
make things the way
we want them to be.
I don't believe what I'm hearing.
Obi-Wan was right.
You've changed.
I don't want to
hear any more...
about Obi-Wan.
The Jedi turned against me.
Don't you turn against me.
I don't know anymore.
Anakin!
You're breaking my heart!
You're going down a path...
I can't follow.
Because of Obi-Wan?
Because of what you've done.
What you plan to do.
PADME: Stop!
Stop now! Come back!
I love you.
(YELLING) Liar!
No!
You're with him!
You brought him
here to kill me.
No! (CHOKING)
Let her go, Anakin!
(CHOKING CONTINUES) Anakin.
Let her go!
(GASPS, GROANS)
You turn her againest me!
You have done that yourself.
(LAVA WAVES RUNNING)
(YELLING) You will not
take her from me!
OBI-WAN: Your anger
and your lust...
for power have
already done that.
You have allowed this...
dark lord to twist
your mind...
until now...
until now you have
become the...
very thing you
swore to destroy.
ANAKIN: Don't leture me, Obi-Wan.
I see through the
lies of the Jedi.
I do not fear the
dark side as you do.
I have brought peace,
freedom, justice...
and security to
my new empire!
Your new empire?
Don't make me kill you!
Anakin, my allegiance
is to the Republic...
to democracy!
If you're not with me...
then you're my enemy.
Only a Sith...
deals an absolutes.
I will do what I must.
You will try.
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(YELLING)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTS)
I hear...
a new apprentice you have...
Emperor.
Or should I...
call you Darth...
Sidious?
Master Yoda...
you survived.
Surprised?
Your arrogance...
blinds you...
Master Yoda.
Now you will...
experience the full
power of the...
dark side.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(GROANS)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(ANAKIN GRUNTS)
(OBI-WAN YELLS)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
I have...
waited a long...
time for this...
moment.
My little...
green friend.
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
At last, the Jedi...
are no more.
Not if...
anything to say about it.
- I have!
- (YELLING)
At an end...
your rule is.
And not short enough it was.
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMS)
If so powerful you are...
why leave?
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
You will not stop me.
Darth Vader will...
become more powerful...
- than either of us.
- (LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
Faith in your new
apprentice...
misplaced may be.
As is your faith...
in the dark side
of the Force.
(LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
- (GRUNTS)
(CHOKING)
(GROANING RAPIDLY)
(MOUTHING WORDS)
(CHOKING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATES)
- (YELLING)
- (GROANS)
(LIGHTSABERS ACTIVATING)
- (LIGHTSABERS CRACKLING)
- (CHORUS VOCALIZING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(WHOOSHING)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
- (DUEL OF THE FATES PLAYING)
- (EMPEROR LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(LOUD CRASHING)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(LAUGHS)
- (LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATES)
- (CRASH)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(GRUNTS)
- (LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATES)
- (GRUNTS)
(VOCALIZING CONTINUES)
(LAUGHING EXCITEDLY)
(LOUD CRASH)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS, GROANS)
(YODA GROANING)
(EMPEROR LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(EXCLAIMS, YELLING)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Hurry.
Careful timing we will need.
Activate your
homing beacon...
when you're ready.
There's no sign of his body, sir.
Then he's not dead.
Double your search.
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
Tell Captain Kagi...
to prepare my shuttle...
for immediate takeoff.
Yes, Master.
I sense Lord...
Vader is in danger.
(CRUMPLING EXPLOSIONS)
(CREAKING)
(PANTING)
(BEEPS)
(HATCH OPENS)
Into exile...
I must go.
Failed I have.
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CRUMPLING EXPLOSIONS)
(CHORUS VOCALIZING)
(VOCALIZING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(RUMBLING)
(VOCALIZING RESUMES)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
I have failed you, Anakin.
I have failed you.
I should have
know the Jedi...
were plotting to take over.
Anakin, Chancellor...
Palpatine is evil!
From my point of view, the...
Jedi are evil!
Well, then you are lost!
(BEEPING)
This is the end for you...
my master.
(CHORUS VOCALIZING)
(GRUNTING)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
It's over, Anakin!
I have the high ground!
You underestimate...
my power!
Don't try it.
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(GROANS)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(YELLING) You we're
the chosen one!
It was said that you would...
destroy the Sith...
not join them!
OBI-WAN: Bring balance
to the force!
Not leaving it in darkness!
(YELLING)
(YELLING CONTINUES)
(SCREAMING) I hate you!
You were my brother, Anakin.
I loved you.
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(GROANING)
(ANAKIN YELLING)
(YELLING CONTINUES)
(WHISTLES, BEEPS SADLY)
Oh, Master Kenobi.
Um, we have Miss...
Padmé on board.
Yes. Please...
please hurry.
We should leave this
dreadful place.
Obi-Wan.
Is Anakin all right?
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(R2-D2 CHIRPS SOFTLY)
(MOANS SOFTLY)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(SHIP REVVING)
MAN: Your Majesty, this way!
There he is.
He's still alive.
(CRUMPLING EXPLOSIONS)
Get a medical capsule
immediately.
Yes, sir. Right away.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Excuse me, Master Yoda.
Obi-Wan Kenobi has made contact.
ORGANA: We'll take her
to the medical center.
Quickly.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
Medically, she's completely healthy.
For reasons we
can't explain...
we are losing her.
She's dying?
We don't know why.
She has lost the will to live.
We need to operate quickly...
if we are to save the babies.
Babies?
She's carrying twins.
(HEARTBEAT THUMPING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(PADME SOBBING)
(BABY LUKE CRYING
HYSTERCALLY)
ROBOT: Ee-see-tah oy-doh.
Luke.
(BABY LUKE COOING)
- Oh, Luke.
- (COOING CONTINUES)
(PADME SCREAMING)
Boo-bah,
boo-bah.
Boo-bah.
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(BABY LEIA CRYING
HYSTERCALLY)
ROBOT: Ee-see-tah oy-doh.
OBI-WAN: It's a girl.
Leia.
(THUMPING CONTINUES)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(WHEEZING)
- (SOFT THUD)
- (HISSING)
(DARTH VADER BREATHING)
Obi-Wan?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
There's good in him.
I know.
I know there's...
Still...
(COOING)
(CRYING)
(STEAM HISSING)
(CHORUS VOCALIZING)
(VADER BREATHING)
(LOUD THUD)
(BREATHING CONTINUES)
Lord Vader.
Can you hear me?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
DARTH VADER: Yes, Master.
Where is Padme?
Is she safe?
Is she all right?
It seems...
in your anger...
you killed her.
I?
I couldn't have.
She was alive!
I felt it!
(VADER GROANING)
(CHORUS VOCALIZING)
(GROANING CONTINUES)
Nooooooo!
Hidden, safe...
the children must be kept.
We must take them...
somewhere where the Sith...
will not sense
their presence.
Hmm.
Split up they should be.
My wife and I will take the girl.
We've always talked of...
adopting a baby girl.
She will be loved with us.
And what of the boy?
To Tatooine.
To his family sent him.
I will take the child
and watch over him.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Until the time is right...
disappear we will.
Master Kenobi.
Wait a moment.
In your solitude...
on Tatooine...
training I have for you.
Training?
An old friend...
has learned the path...
to immortality.
One who has returned...
from the netherworld...
of the Force.
Your old master.
Qui-Gon?
How to commune with him
I will teach you.
Captain Antilles.
Yes, Your Highness?
I'm placing these
droids in your care.
Treat them well. Clean them up.
Have the protocol
droid's mind wiped.
- What?
- (R2-D2 BEEPS)
(CHUCKLING BEEPS)
Oh, no.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHROUS VOCALIZING)
(TIE FIGHTERS ROARING LOUDLY)
(VADER BREATHING)
(BREATHING CONTINUES)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING)
(BREATHING CONTINUES)
(SHIP ROARING)
(BLEATS)
(SNORTS SOFTLY)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHORUS VOCALIZING)
(VOCALIZING CONTINUES)
(VOCALIZING ENDS)
(ENGLISH - SDH)