People will say I'm a monster
for what I've done
maybe they're right .
I always thought that I'd have more time.
Dad.
I'm sorry
Peter?
- He likes to sleep with the light on.
- Mary, let's go.
Dad.
Be good
I have found a safe place for us to spend the night at Lake Geneva.
- Are you uploading it?
- To Roosevelt, all of it.
Just in case we...
We're going to be fine, Mary.
Did you see his face?
He is never going to understand.
Mary, we've been through this.
Our life as we know it is over.
We will spend every day from now on
looking over our shoulders...
never feeling safe.
We can't do that to him.
- He's just a little boy.
- I know, I know, It's going to be OK.
It's gonna be alright.
No rest for the weary, huh?
No, I'm afraid not.
Occupational hazard I guess.
What is it you're working on?
Er...just planning ahead.
Do you think I can speak with the pilot?
Something you need?
Perhaps, I can help.
I'd just like to radio ahead and make sure
everything's in order for when we land.
I think we both know that's not an option,
Dr. Parker.
They say you're a genius.
Not if you think you can escape.
It's okay. It's okay.
I got you. Are you okay? Okay?
I'm going to make you safe.
It's done. Breathe...Mary.
- Roosevelt.
- What? Roosevelt.
It's back up, back up.
It'll be alright okay.
Listen...to me.
Upload complete
What you got for me today,
New York?
Reporting live from New
York born chopper.
An Oscorp truck carrying plutonium
has been hijacked.
- A Police chase is in progress
- Alright, let's get to work.
Say hello to Aleksei Sytsevich.
- Spider-Man!
- Hello, pedestrians.
Knock, knock.
Mr. Criminal?
Hey! My name is Spider-Man, you can call me
webhead, you can call me amazing,
just don't call me late for
dinner, you get it? Okay!
- Not a shaker? Are you a hugger?
- I'm a killer.
Warning! Plutonium-238 is a radioactive
material and is highly explosive.
Excuse me.
There's more room on the sidewalk.
Dodge, please, dodge!
A little help? A little help, please.
You're having problem with your gun?
Let me help you out with that.
Too much work.
Er...this is bad,
I'm gonna be right back.
Heads, up, watch out. Wooo!
Okay, okay, there you go. You okay?
- You alright?
- You're Spider-Man!
Costume gives it away, huh? Look,
this looks pretty important, Max.
- Max? How do you know my name?
- It's written on your badge.
- I'm a nobody.
- Hey! You're not a nobody, you're somebody.
Lick that. Alright, listen to me.
The world needs you. You're
my eyes and ears out here.
- Alright? Alright!
- See you out there!
Warning: Violation of protocol
Hands up...
Gotcha, gotcha,
no, got you, too.
No, you're not going anywhere.
Come here, come to daddy.
Get out of the way.
OK, OK, got it, got it. Woo.
Oh, come on.
Hey wait, come back here.
Gotcha.
Hey I'm sorry, I'm running a bit
late, I got stuck in some traffic.
Your timing is terrible. It started already,
I know I'm sorry where are you?
First on Broadway, second on Broadway, third
on Broadway, Ah, 5 minutes, 10 tops.
- Are those sirens?
- No.
- Peter, No!, Peter!
- No sirens.
Peter, what's happening?
Peter, Peter!
Hello?
- And now I would like to introduce you an extraordinary young woman,
- I'll be right there, promise.
this years' Valedictorian, please
welcome...Gwen Stacy.
Good morning, esteemed faculty
and families of my fellow graduates.
It's an honor to be standing up
here today.
Hello...I told you,
I'm running a bit late.
I saw that, Spider.
Really?
I know that we all think we're immortal.
We're supposed to feel
that way, we're graduating
but like our brief
4 years in high school...
what makes life valuable, is
that it doesn't last forever.
What makes it precious is that it ends.
We know that now more than ever.
And I say it...
today of all days
is to remind us that time is luck.
So don't waste it living someone elses' life.
Make yours count for something.
Fight for what matters to you,
no matter what.
'cause even if we fall short...
what better way is there to live?
Alright
I'll take that, that's my rule.
This is not end, Spider
Peter Parker
I think I know that guy.
Peter Parker.
Sorry.
Wait, do that again, do that again.
Oh, Pete...Lord says...I almost
stole my car up again over myself.
- I'd like to have seen that too.
- No, no, no, this is for you.
- Oh, I am so proud of you.
- You earned it. Sweetheart I'm so proud of you.
- I know the first thing your Uncle Ben would say...
- Yea, I know too.
"You gotta hurry up, the party's over.
You gotta get a job."
Alright, then the second thing he would say:
"Don't just follow the path. Make your own trail."
- Ralph Waldo Emerson...?
- No...
- What do you mean no?
- Ben told me he made it up.
You really did learn something here.
I wish your uncle could have been here.
Yea, me too...and my folks.
Yea, yea.
Alright, you can go.
Come on, and be right back.
OK, guys, get together,
get together right now.
- A quick one alright, Cheese...
- Cheese...
OK, just gimme 2 seconds.
Don't go too far.
Good to see you. Alright.
Did your traffic jam have anything
to do with the Russian mob...
and machine guns by any chance?
- Why don't you just tell me? what I gonna do?
- I was about to...right after you speech.
- Gwen, honey, family photo.
- Okay.
- You coming to dim sum?
- You can't keep me away.
- It's at 8 o'clock. Don't be late.
- I will be OK.
And I am going to do my speech for you.
- All night, I want to hear it all night long.
- Over and over again, all night long.
- That was pretty good.
- Peter, join us.
I got to find my aunt, I gotta find my
aunt but I'm going to catch up later. Thank you.
You're going to make enemies.
People will get hurt.
So will you please promise me something, OK ?
Leave Gwen out of it.
Promise me that.
Peter's outside.
Peter.
What is it?
What's wrong? Are you alright?
I don't know what I'm doing.
It's my father, isn't it?
Yea, I see him everywhere I go.
I can't...I don't know what to do.
I can't get him out of my head.
- Yea but we'd talked about this.
- I know...Gwen
It's not his choice.
Gwen, I promised him that
I would keep away from you
and now I'm gonna come
eat dinner with your family.
How can I do this?
What does this make me?
I don't know, what does that make you?
It makes me not able
to live with myself.
- I thought that it made you love me.
- I do love you.
I love you.
Then why isn't that enough, huh?
Because what if something happens to you,
just like it happened to him because of me.
No, wait, wait, wait.
I cannot let that happen.
Listen to me, you're Spider-Man...
and I love that
but I love Peter Parker more.
That's worth it to me.
I can't lose you too.
Is it because you can't lose me,
we can't be together?
Who's there to work out for, Peter?
I can't. I'm sorry, Gwen.
Wow, you have done this to me...
again and again, Peter.
I can't live like this.
I break up with you.
Good morning, New Yorkers.
Looking for another beautiful day here in the city.
The steady increase in sightings of
Spider-Man has sparked a national debate...
over the role of vigilantes
in America's crime fighting .
- How about that Spider-Man...
-  Last night on Manhattan bridge he saved a dozen lives.
We want to hear your calls.
I think without Spider-Man,
there'll be no hope for this city..
Who do you think paid the bill for all the
damages he caused, huh? It's you and me, taxpayer!
Did you make this?
Yea
This is a wind turbine.
You made this? No way!
This is amazing.
It's good as new, right? I'll walk you home.
- What's your name?
- Jorge.
Jorge, I'm Spider-Man.
I don't feel like my kids are
safe with him out there,
get out of the way and
let the police do their job.
Some folks think that there
might be more than one Spider-man.
What do you think,
one guy or many?
I'd love to know who's behind that mask.
- Hey, nice outfit.
- Thanks.
We have a caller on the line named
Max, he said he knows Spider-Man.
Listen, I'm upset...Spider-Man
to me is being misunderstood.
He's a very, very good person,
He's protecting us.
Not only that, he saved my life, one time,
and we sort of became best friends.
- How much?
- You're that Spider guy!
I'm Spider-Bad.
This Spider-Man guy, he's not
the police, he's not a fireman.
What gives him the right,
to get involved in other people's business
Peter, honey, can I come in?
No!
Peter, the final starts at 9, honey.
And you said you'd take my car
into the shop b'coz it keeps dying, remember?
Gimme a second Aunt May, I'm gonna
get the door, just gimme a second.
Please just let me in, alright?
The final is at 9, are you going
to take my car to the shop?
No, you can't come in. Stay outside,
I'm so naked.
You said you're gonna take my car
into the shop because...
- Are you alright?
- Yea. I'm okay.
I'm just...I'm very naked right now.
- What happened to your face, it's filthy!
- It is? Yes.
Oh yea, yea, I was cleaning
the chimney.
- We have no chimney.
- What?
- You're late.
- I know, I'm late.
Downstairs...Now!
- Alright, I'm leaving!
- I'm naked here.
Morning. I love you.
I love you too. Hurry up.
Ho ho ho, look who's here?
Spidey!
How was your morning?
Aces, Max, aces.
I've been out saving the world,
protecting everybody.
Listen, isn't it somebody's birthday today?
That's why you're here.
You remembered my birthday.
All the crime fighting you've been doing
and you still take time to come visit little old me, Max.
That's...it's amazing.
But...of course you would,
why won't you visit me?
We're best friend.
What are you doing?
You made me a cake?
People don't get the chance to see
these all small kind things you do for people.
I know what they say about you in the
press but it doesn't matter to me
because I know the real you,
because you're amazing.
Wow, that's what the press needs.
They should call you "The
Amazing Spider-Man."
You like that, Spidey?
I like it a lot, Max.
Good...because today is going
to be amazing.
Circuit 39.
I'm not late, Harvey,
I'll be there in 15 minutes.
I just wanna know if you can find another
waitress to replace me
because I start my training
rounds at the hospital.
Don't mention this to Peter,
I don't want him to know because he worries.
Yea, yea, okay, you got it.
Double shift on Thursday. Okay bye.
- Who was that?
- Harvey.
- Another double shift, huh?
- Sometimes.
I got nothing else to do,
I like the girls,
I miss Ben gives me a little
extra in the cookie jar.
I sold another, another couple of photos
to the Bugle so that outa help.
Yea, what really help if that guy
would pay you a fair wage.
Oh, James? James would pay me some fair wages,
if it was 1961, he would pay me a fair wage.
Hey, Hey, wait. What are you doing?
What are you doing?
- I'm doing my laundry.
- No, I do the laundry.
It's my job, I've been doing your
laundry since you were 6 years old.
I understand that, I'm in college now,
it's time that I took care of my own dirty underwear.
The last time you did the laundry,
you turned everything blue and red.
That was a mistake, cause'
I was washing...the...the American flag, my...can you just please...
No one washes the flag.
I do and I wont anymore, forget it, fine,
can I just do my...it's just underwear!
This is my laundry, my home,
my machine. Back off, eat your breakfast.
Alright laundry sheriff.
I'll do it later.
- I'll do it.
- No, forget it. No, I'll do it some other time, forget it.
- Excuse me.
- Idiot.
I do not get it.
A lot of jam. Come on, come on.
- Watch it, buddy.
- Hey, let's go!
Oscorp Industries is proud to announce...
the world's first electromagnetic
power grid.
by converting aging power stations
into a field of hydro electric towers...
we're generating clean,
green, sustainable energy...
to power Manhattan...
and finally the rest of the world...
- Dillon, you're late.
- "D" line trains were so slow, sir.
Don't you realise that Oscorp is now
responsible for the entire city energy supply?
The designs for the power grid
and they use a lot of them
and I noticed that in those power grids were the designs by me.
You designed them? Sure you did
and I'm Spider-Man.
You're no Spider-Man. He's the ...?
You ever speak about him again,
I'm goint to rip your raccoon head off.
Now get to work.
- Which floor please
- 74.
Thank you
Oh, hold that!
- I got it.
- Thank you, you're a real gentleman.
- Most people would just let that close.
- Well, most people don't notice other people.
- Which floor please
- 63
- Hold on. What's it?
- Er...63
- 63, please
- Thank you
Thank you, very much.
Er...my name is Max, Max Dillon.
- I'm Gwen. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Is it your birthday?
Oh yea, well, I...er, they...
fortunately leave this flyer in my room...
birthday party, big club...
a lot of celebrities....
Wow. I would like to invite you,
it's just that the guest list is closed.
Oh, got it, got it but well thank you anyway.
This's exciting. This guy dress like spiderman.
It must be cool, huh, to have the
whole world look at you like that.
You know Spider-Man saved my life one time.
Of all the people in the whole
city, he saved me.
He said he needed me.
That must be really...
Floor 63.
It's nice to meet you, Max.
Wait, she remembered my name.
Welcome home.
It's dark in there.
Your eyes will adjust.
It's better this way.
Dad.
This is not how I imagined
I will die.
Looking at my son and,
seeing a stranger.
You had such potential, Harry.
Such fierce intelligence
and yet you thrown it all away.
You threw me away.
You kicked me off to boarding
school when I was 11.
On my 16th birthday...
you sent me Scotch
or one of your assistants did.
I'm pretty sure because the card read:
With compliments, Norman Osborn.
I don't expect forgiveness from you anymore
and you know what? I don't believe in miracles.
How could you possibly understand...
that your childhood had to be sacrificed
for something greater?
Not just for me, for you!
Have your hands started to twitch yet?
When you lay awake...
and you feel it coming...
hiding under the skin...
waiting to show itself...
to show you who you really are...
Retroviral Hyperplasia.
I never told you...
that's genetic.
Our disease,
the Osborn curse
and it began at your age.
Let me see it.
Your hand, give it to me.
The greatest inheritance
I can give you
is not nearly money.
is this...a solemn total volume of my work
everything I did to stay alive.
Maybe you can succeed where I failed.
Mr. Norman Osborn, the
legendary founder and CEO of Oscorp Industries has died.
The Osborn estate has confirmed
he is survived by his only son, Harry
Osborn, who is the sole heir
of the Oscorp corporate empire
Harry
Osborn fundamentaly changed the medical
profession's approach to human healing...
and affected the lives of millions.
I started Oscorp because I looked at
the world around me and I thought.
"We can do better.
We should do better."
Einstein said the world cannot be changed
without changing our thinking
but change isn't just a slogan.
It begins with hard work. Change begins
with persistence and commitment.
Mr. Osborn changed the world
and now it's up to each of us to ensure that
his hopes and dreams remain alive
but not today.
- Today...
- Hello?
- Is this Gwen Stacy?
- Yes, it's, who's calling?
I'm calling from the Oxford scholar
program. We've some exciting news.
Oh, Dillon, you stay here.
There's a current flow problem in genomics
lab. Why don't you stay and take a look at that.
It's my birthday. Everybody else
is leaving, why do I have to stay?
- Because you're special,
- Smythe, I mean Mr. Smythe...
Happy birthday.
Bio electrogenesis.
The generation of electricity by
living organisms...
Hey guys.
Someone loves a party.
You're just a little sick.
I got your medicine.
And on my birthday.
After all I put together for this company.
Warning.
- Error in sector 5A
- I know, maybe it's just the...
Did you know it's my birthday, Kari? Could
you sing "Happy Birthday" for me?
I'll just have to sing for myself.
Gilbert! What? It's Max. Can you shut
down power in sector 32, please?
- Forget it I'm out the door.
- What do you mean, Listen I'm up here, it's dangerous.
- Sorry, Max
- Hello?
I'll do it myself
and I'll sing to myself.
Happy Birthday...to me.
Happy Birthday...dear Max...
Happy Birthday...
to me.
System restored.
Have a nice day.
Harry, Oscorps has been under intense public scrutiny
in the wake of Dr. Connors' recent breach of trust.
You mean, people are pisssed off because he
tried to turn everyone in N.Y city into giant lizards?
Given that...
all the animal hybrid program he
was involved in were destroyed...
to restore investor confidence.
That is the Osborn way.
Whoever's inconvenient around
here, just get rid of it, right?
Much of that scrutiny may fall on
you now.
- We felt that plausible deniability was your best option...
- Sure, sure, I get it.
20-year-old kid.
200 billion dollar company.
What was dad thinking?
I mean you're all lawyers...right?
Surely someone must have questioned his
sanity in the end.
Someone must have thought about having
him declared legally incompetent.
would have made this conversation
a lot easier.
- Harry...
- It's Mr. Osborn.
We're not friends.
Hi.
You were his assistant, right?
- What is your name?
- Felicia. Felicia.
From now on, everybody at this table
will explore? Felicia
because Felicia works for me.
Would anybody like to speak up?
Well good then, you can all
keep your job for a little longer.
Sir... There's a Peter Parker...
Felicia, I want to see every
file on this list.
Every single one.
Peter Parker.
It's like seeing a ghost.
Hey, Harry.
Random.
- 10 years.
- It's 8.
Close.
- What's up?
- It's on the news, man.
I heard about your dad and I wanted
to come and...
see you, check it out, see how you're doing.
I'm...umm...I'm with some people.
I'm in the middle of a meeting.
I'm sorry, I don't want to intrude,
I know it has been a long time and
I kind of know exactly what
you're going through right now.
You were so there for me when my
parents...
That's why I'm here for you.
Thank you.
It's good to see you man.
Good to see you.
Sorry about your dad.
You've got your braces off.
and now there's nothing to distract from your...?
There it is.
Does someone dry your
hair every morning?
Umm...you know...one of my main
servants hold the hair dryer
but I work the comb.
Okay, so at least I'm not completely
helpless.
After graduation I went
to Brazil and Singapore.
- That's right...and then Europe, you know, I went to Europe.
- I saw you.
What do you mean you saw me.
I saw you in some magazine with some French
supermodel, you know what I'm talking about?
- Yea, yea, dude, the whole model thing is so exhausting.
- I know.
What?
You got a lady?
Er...that's the question.
That's the question.
- Nobody?
- No, I don't.
Yea, I don't know...
it's a, er...I don't know, it's complicated.
Yea, I don't do complicated.
So what's her name? Who is she?
Her name is Gwen, Gwen Stacy.
- Gwen Stacy?
- She works for you.
Really? She works for me?
- She's an intern at Oscorp.
- Is she a model employee?
You know, when my father sent away me I tried to
forget everything about this place.
I guess that kind of includes you.
You don't have to explain anything to me, man.
We both got dumped.
Did you ever figure out why your parents bailed?
My dad left a briefcase.
Thats all I got, a briefcase full of junk.
- Whatever, I don't know. I try not to think about it.
- How's that working out for you?
Perfectly.
Dude, that's horrible.
It's just the wrist. It's
just all in the wrist, buddy.
You can do it with some strength.
Yea, right you got to admit though,
things have gotten a little crazy around here man.
Giant lizards, and...
Spider-Guy.
Just one guy,
just one Spider-Man,
or woman.
We don't know...for sure.
Whatever dude. What's with Spandex
rescuing kittens from trees?
So impressed.
- The guy like to give people hope.
- For what?
Maybe eventually everything's gonna
be alright.
I wish I had time for eventually.
- Who was it?
- Maxwell Dillon, electrical engineer.
No associates or friends to speak of.
He submitted specs for the grid,
that we...appropriated...
caused it invisible.
Wall Street is nervous enough of
that child, Harry, taking over.
We got to find a way to get him out.
In the meantime if the press gets hold of this
accident, our stock will cradle.
So make sure that this Mr. Dillon
stays invisible.
This could prove useful for us
in the future.
Hey.
Move!
Hey!
You look amazing.
I'm sorry for this spontaneous...?
it's kind of...
No, I...spontaneous is alright,
you know.
Well, I just figured it was time,
you know...time we try to be friends.
Friends, yea, that's...
great.
Just don't want this to be complicated.
- I just said that to someone I hate complicated.
- Keep it simple.
Okay great, great, yea, yea, alright
but I mean...
if we were to be friends, I think
we gotta establish some ground rules.
- Some ground rules?
- Yes, some ground rules,
- Like that.
- Like what?
Look...look, that laugh, that laugh.
That's off the table.
- My laugh's off the table?
- You gotta figure out a more annoying laugh.
That's still adorable.
That was not adorable.
What're you doing...
- Okay, I've got a ground rule.
- Oh, you, what? What's it.
Er...don't tell me that I look amazing
with your big brown doe eyes, OK?
I'm really serious about that one.
- Oh no...
- What?
- I've just figured out the next ground rule.
No more of this.
- No more...no more this nose rub that you do.
- This? Don't think I've to?
What am I supposed to do?
It's allergy season.
This is killing me, I gotta...you just
stay in my face with my ground rules, I'm out.
Come on!
First we get ice cream, then I'm out.
Umm, yea, I did that...
and I got completely addicted to this
place that has Korean meatballs.
- Yea... Have you been there?
- No, no... It's mind-blowing.
That place is at 6th, I know,
you love it there.
How do you know that?
How do you know I love it there?
Cos' umm...
Cos' you told me.
It just opened last month.
Have you been following me?
I knew it. How often?
Just once a day, sometimes.
Sometimes more.
Oh boy, why?
- You trying to keep me safe?
- Yea.
No, that's the closest
I can get still being with you.
I'm moving to England.
- What?
- Yea.
I have a, um...a first scholarship to Oxford
in molecular medicine
and it's between me and this other kid and
there's this oral exam we've to do
and he's like a freshman
in college but he's 14
and it could be him
but might be me, I hope it's me
and then I, I gotta move to England
and I'm really excited.
That's...er...
England?
Station, I need a 10-85.
Send out the units to the
southend corner of Duffy Square.
Everybody get out of the way, please.
Get out of the way!
Sir, get your hands away
from the cable, right now!
Sir, get your hands away from the cables!
Let me see your hands, please!
You stay right where you are.
Do not move.
Freeze! Get down, on the ground!
Get down on the ground, now!
- Stop.
- Get down on the ground, now!
It's not my fault. Stop.
Please...
My goodness.
They see me...they see me...
They see me...they see me..
- On the ground, now!
- No...stop. Don't do that.
Please.
- It's over, freak.
- Wait, it's not my fault.
It's not my fault.
I said, stop!
I'm glad you're not one of those
cops that ride a horse.
All team members...hold your fire and wait for
my call.
All unit Hold your fire, I repeat, hold
your fire and stay down.
- Stop, stop it!
- Yo, Sparkle!
Hey...how are you doing?
- It's you?
- Yea, I know it's me, who are you?
- You don't remember me?
- No, should I?
I walked into the street, the car
almost hit me. You swung me up.
You saved me.
You said you needed me.
- The guy, you're the guy with the blue prints...
- Yes, blue prints.
Yes, I remember you, of course I remember
you, you're my eyes and ears.
- Er...what's your name again?
- How could you forget me?
- Oh, I do, I know it, I know it, don't tell me...
- It's Max. Is it Max?
Yes.
I'm sorry, I didn't recognize you with the...you look different.
How are you?
- I don't know what's going on with me.
- I can see, I...I believe you.
It's strange...the power that
I got so much.
I got so much anger.
Excuse me. I can see that, I can see you
don't want to be here, I can see you're scared
cos' you don't know what's happening to you.
I can see that you don't want to hurt anybody.
- It's going to be alright.
- I got a clear shot, standing by.
- I don't want them shooting me anymore.
- They're not going to shoot you.
You guys, this is my buddy Max.
I told you about Max.
No one shoots at Max!
You and me, fancy you and me talking. Whoa...
Stay right there, stay right there.
Just be careful with the grid,
it's the electricity.
I just...I just wanted them to see me.
If he makes a move, you take that shot.
How about you come with me, go somewhere we can talk,
away from all these people...okay?
No, no...stop!
Spidey...Spidey...
You stupid freak!
dummy!
He lied to me, he shot me...
Shut up.
You're so selfish.
Stay with me Max.
- You set me up.
- No...I didn't set you up.
- You lied to me.
- No, I'm trying to help you, let me help you.
It's my birthday.
Now it's time for me to light my
candles.
Do we have visual on Spider-Man?
Does anyone...have visual on Spider-Man?
That's enough.
- Mike. Big John.
- Nice job!
Nice work fellas. It's a
pleasure doing business with you.
Spider-Man...
England?
Really?
Good talk.
Our coverage of this breaking story begins
with Jessica Abo at the scene.
That's right. We're standing here with two eyewitnesses
who are going to tell us what they just saw.
So tell us. How do you think Spider-Man did it.
How do you think he beat this creature.
Yea, it got to be rubberised, Spideys suit
that's, that's why he didn't get electrocuted.
Probably some kind of neoprene.
That's what I'll use, honestly...
Thank you very much for the two of you, as you you can tell
so many questions remain unanswered..
Online polls show a sudden uptake in public
sentiment in favour of the web-crawler.
Tonight it would seem New York city owes him a debt of gratitude.
Next generation military body armor.
Features include enhanced
mobility, battlefield injury repair.
Direct nervous system interface.
So the common household spider,
umm..unlike human cells,
they contain the power to self-heal
from severe infection, tissue damage.
and so we used radioactive isotope
with compatible human DNA...
Welcome...to Dr. Jallings science
investigator.
Today we're going to be talking about
electricity.
Batteries, insulators,
electromagnetic current.
Batteries can withstand
a lot of incoming charges.
The more powerful the battery, the
bigger the charge it can withstand.
But if the incoming charge
exceeds the outgoing charge,
the battery might explode!
Explode!
Conducting experiments like this,
always wear protective gear.
- You're not invincible.
- I think I need a bigger battery!
- Hello?
- Pete, its me.
Hey, Harry, what time is it?
Late, early, I don't know.
I've been up all night.
- I need to see you.
- You alright...?
Not really Pete.
I'm dying...but I think you can help
save my life.
You're looking at the world's first
Human-Spider hybrids.
The hope is to extract the venom
from their glands
and turn that into a cure, an agent
that heals diseased cells.
And if I can be cured...
Imagine what this could do for other
diseases like Alzheimer's even cancer.
They never made it to
human trials.
14 years of research and nothing
to show for it.
Except maybe this.
- Spider-Man.
- What about him?
He was bitten by one of
those things that worked.
I don't know how and I
don't know why...but
he can do everything else a spider can,
including self-heal.
I need to find him.
I need his blood.
You need Spider-Man's blood?
- It will save my life.
- It may not, Harry.
It may not be that simple.
- You saw what happened to Curt Connors, right?
- Connors was weak.
This is me, Peter.
I don't think you can just set up a
van and have him donate it.
I mean, I'm sure he's sensitive about people shoving needles...and
Probably sensitive?
Okay, well then, maybe you can just sensitively tell me where he is
- and I will just go ask him myself.
- What?
- You took his picture.
- So? You know him.
Harry, I took a picture from a long way,
I use a long lens, I don't know him.
- When we were together, you said at the river
- About...?
about how he gives people hope.
Come on.
Central Server accessed
Just say yes.
Don't turn your back on me.
I don't want to end up like my father, Peter.
Please.
- Peter, please.
- I can't.
I'm going to try and find Spider-Man.
- Hey, what's the security doing here?
- That's so weird.
Hey, Miss Stacy.
What are you doing here?
She's not here.
Check another floor.
- Are you in trouble?
- Yea. Who's that guy?
There was an accident,
I need you to know Oscorp, they're covering it up
and I found out. That guy
from Times Square last night,
I met him. He was an
electrical engineer in the building
and he loves Spider-Man by the way, otherwise...
I didn't get that last night because I got the feeling
that he wanted to kill me with his electrical devise.
That's exactly kind of how it feels like to love you.
I was searching for him in the computer and all files were erased .
- It's completely erased.
- That's Oscorp.
- What about you, why are you here?
- Harry, Osborn? he's dying.
- What do you mean he's dying?
- He's dying.
And he thinks the only thing going to save
his life is my blood, Spider-Man's blood.
As far as I know, if I gave it to
him, it could kill him.
I'm saying worse.
This is the maintenance closet,
Gwen.
This is the most cliche hiding place
you could have chosen.
I'm...sorry.
- This is the stupidest hiding place.
- Take us to the Bahamas hiding place.
I don't want to talk to you about
England I guess is because...I don't...
- You just kissed me.
- I'm sorry, I couldn't help it.
How do you like it?
- It felt a little rush.
- I know, I know.
This is the plan. You get to the elevator,
I'm going to distract them, okay? Okay
I'm sorry...I'm all thumbs today.
- Gwen Stacy.
- Oh my God!
- Er...umm...I'm Harry.
- Yea...
- I'm an old friend of Peter's.
- Yea, I know who you are. Sorry.
I was kind of rushing...
No, I'm sorry he never introduced us.
I thought you two had broken up.
Oh...yea, yes, we had, it's...
Complicated.
- Complicated.
- He's Peter. Everything is always complicated with Peter.
- Yea, yea, it's...you're right.
- But that's why I need you.
Right?
To help him make his choices
clear.
- Nice to meet you, Harry.
- Yea, it' such a pleasure, Gwen.
Ravenscroft Institute
You had been in a terrible accident.
I'm Dr. Kafka.
I'm here to help you.
Of course you are, Doc'.
That's why you prepared a
military grade, Biostimulate electrode.
High intensity capacitors.
The kind they make at Oscorp.
All of this because you're trying to help me.
You are correct.
I'm here to study you,
to understand what you are, why you are
and I'll get results.
I always do.
You do realize you locked me in a
prison...an advance cell...
all the electricity...
I can feel it in the walls,
I can feel it in my veins.
No matter what you do, Doc' ,
you can't contain it.
It's a force of nature, like me.
- You want to know how powerful I am?
- Yea.
Oh, so do I!
I'm dying...to know.
Doc' , but you better make damn sure you
kill me this time because if you don't...
I'm gonnna kill the light.
Everyone in this city will know
how it feels to live in my world.
A world without power.
A world without mercy.
A world without Spider-Man.
And everyone will be able to see me
for what I truly am.
And who are you?
Don't you know? I am Electro.
Warning: Electrical capacity reaching limit.
Initiate lockdown procedure immmediately.
Very impressive, Electro.
Lockdown began.
Aunt May?
- What are you doing?
- When did you do this?
There's something you're not
telling me, Aunt May.
Every time I mention my parents,
your eyes go down.
I know you're not telling me something. You lie to me.
- I know you love me... I don't.
- I know you love me but you do.
Aunt May, Aunt May, you've to tell me,
Aunt May, it's my father.
Yes, he was your father...
that didn't seem to stop him
from leaving you here.
I need the truth.
The truth is that your parents left you here, on our door-step.
And you're this little boy whose wholeworld was
turned upside down with no explanation.
We did the best, we could.
Your Uncle Ben, he and I.
Who else was going to care for you and
protect you and worries about you?
Your father? No.
I was the one who wiped your nose
and made you brush your teeth
and do your homework and washed
your dirty underwear. Me!
Your stupid, nonscientific aunt, who
doesn't know how to make ends meet...
who has to take nursing classes, with 22 year old
kids, so I can pay for you to go to college
and I don't know how to do
this without Ben. I don't know how
and you're dreaming about your perfect father
who was never here? No!
No, I wont tell you.
You're my boy.
As far as I'm concerned, you're my boy.
And I won't hurt you.
I'm your boy.
You're my everything.
You're enough. You're more than enough.
That's not what this is about. Don't get that twisted.
- I love you so much.
- I know.
It's okay. It's okay.
Aunt May...
I need to know.
Alright.
I'll tell you everything I know.
- But It will hurt you.
- Okay.
A few days after the funeral...
Two government men came to see us.
They said, the genetic research
that your father was doing with
Norman Osborn was very valuable
and that people would pay a lot for it
and thats why he ran off with it.
They said he was a traitor.
I couldn't believe it, Peter.
They told us he betrayed his best
friend, all of us, for the money.
I don't...I don't get it.
No...this doesn't make sense.
Yes, I know.
I didn't believe it either. I didn't believe it.
- This doesn't make any sense..
- Peter... I don't know.
For so long, I would play it over and over in
my head what had I missed, what had I missed.
He was just a normal unassuming guy. He wore
the same ratty lab coat for 20 years...
He took the D train to work,
at 7 every morning...
came home at 6 every night.
I don't know.
Maybe everyone has a part of
himself they hide...
even from the people they love.
Mr. Osborn.
Look up.
I think you're looking for me.
I cannot believe my eyes.
Spider-Man.
Just the man I wanted to see.
- You...err...talked to Peter?
- Yeap.
I want to help you, Mr. Osborn.
I really, really do.
I can't give you my blood.
Not right now.
- Excuse me?
- It's too dangerous.
If our blood isn't compatible,
you could die.
I'm already dying.
- Your blood can't make me die more.
- But it could do something worse.
Okay.
Alright, how much?
- How much what?
- How much do you want?
Maybe a boat, a plane or
money? How much do you want?
- I don't want your money.
- Come on! Everybody wants my money!
I don't.
I thought...I thought you're suppose to save people.
I thought that's what you do,
is you save peoples' lives.
You just gonna let me die.
I'm trying to protect you, right now.
You're trying to protect yourself.
Look...we just need a bit more time
I do not have time! Get out!
I'm sorry.
You're a fraud, Spider-Man!
- Hey, can I talk to you for a second?
- Hi, I'm running late right now.
No, no...it's just  going to take a second.
Give me a minute, just give me one minute,
I'm just going to say one thing then I'm gone.
Everything is a mess!
My dad, my mum,
everything my father do...lies!
Lies, lies, lies.
Nothing make any sense anymore.
So here we are. I got to figure what I'm going to
do with Harry. Of course I want to save him, you know.
How hard is it to save him...cos' he's my best pal.
What if my blood works? But what if it
doesn't? I don't know. I got no idea.
I got nothing.
The only thing I keep coming back to...
Gwen is...
Miss Stacy, shall I take you
upstairs?
Yes, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry..I'm already late...
Can I have just one more minute?
Thank you, I'm sorry.
- Where are we?
- I've to be...er...I'm at...my last interview for Oxford, right now.
- Oxford? I didn't know.
- Yea.
OK, well, I'm sorry to bother you,
er...umm...my fair lady...
but madame, madame but er...who am I?
I mean, who am I? I am John Hopkins.
I'm one of the young professors at Harvard
and I'm trying to get her to be in my...
to be part of my team, for a while now
and she is the best person I know
and a scientific genius
- and...anyway, "God save the Queen" I'm sorry that I made things...
- Excuse me, Peter!
Peter, what do you want to say to me?
What's the one thing?
I have to go to England for a year.
It's important to me.
I know, I know we're on different path right now.
You know...I don't know.
We were just going different ways.
I gotta go. I gotta go.
Gwen.
Good luck.
"Roosevelt's secret  station:
Track 61, a secret subterranean extension of New York's
"D" line train under Pershing Square
was originally built to transport President Franklin Roosevelt
away from the public eye...
to keep his polio hidden
from the American people."
Mr. Osborn.
You alright? Is there anything I can
get you or...?
No, not unless you can bring
those spiders back to life.
- Spiders?
- The ones that they destroyed.
"To restore investors' confidence."
Go home, Felicia.
Take the day off.
Harry!
I think there may be another way,
to get what you're looking for...
I overheard Menken talking
with one of our security's head.
Before they destroyed the spiders,
they had the venom extracted.
What are you saying?
That way they could comply with the lawsuits but
still keep the data in case whenever it became useful.
- Where is it?
- Somewhere in the building.
Somewhere off the books
called "Special Projects".
Special Projects.
Last received entry: 1 hour ago
Approved by Harry Osborn...
Accessing Ravenscroft archive.
...and then I'm going to kill the light,
so everyone in this city will discover
how it feels to live in my world.
A world without power.
A world without Spider-Man.
Warning. Your user
access has been revoked.
He's busy. You can't go in there. He's busy.
- What did you do?
- A more relevant question is what did you do?
An employee is killed and your
first action as CEO, you covered it up!
No, you covered it up and then you
buried him in the bug house using my name.
Ravenscroft is a time warning institution
devoted to mental improvement.
- You're experimenting on people in there.
- Progress has its stepping stones.
Now, in light of your deceptive
criminal actions, you have been...
how do I put this gently...
fired.
You're not going to bury me too.
Looks to me like you're
halfway in the ground already.
It's only a matter of time.
You're going to die a horrible death,
like your father.
The difference is,
no one is going to miss you.
- Get him out.
- Wait, wait!
I know my way out.
My name is Richard Parker.
Whatever lies will be told about me,
I would like the world to know the truth.
Oscorp was already a leader
in genetic research
when Norman Osborn made a deal with
a foreign military organization
to continue funding my research.
And I discovered what they were going to use it for.
Weapons, biological weapons of course. So I refused.
And now to eliminate me from the picture,
Norman Osborn has
falsified evidence against me
in order to take control of my work.
Can I help you?
Yea, you can open the gate.
I'm Harry Osborn.
There's a patient that I specially would like to see.
Joe, this is Mr. Osborn, Oscorp.
Sorry sir, without a yellow badge,
you can't even pass this point.
Well, it doesn't matter because there is
something else that Norman doesn't know.
The human DNA that I implanted in
the spiders
was my own.
Which means that without me,
without my bloodline,
Oscorp can never replicate or
continue my experiments.
Keep Electro incubated,
400 milligrams of sodium
and phenobarbital,
I've...I've destroyed as much as possible from the archives
but I didn't have time
to kill all the spiders.
So as a scientist, my choice is very clear now.
I have to disappear. I have to get
as far away from here as I can
but as a father
it means, I may not see my boy
again.
and nothing is as
important to me as my son, Peter.
Nothing in this world.
But I have a responsibility to protect
the world from what I've created
and protect him from what
I know Osborn is capable of.
People will say I'm a monster
for what I've done.
Maybe they're right.
I always thought that I'd have more time.
- Dad...Dad!...
- I'm sorry.
Sedation...off...
I'm gonna get you out.
Alright but we don't have much time.
- Who are you?
- I'm Harry Osborn. I want to make you a deal.
- I should kill you.
- Come on.
Think big, Max.
I'm not the one you want.
You want Spider-Man
and I can give him to you.
But...I need something first.
I need you to get me to Oscorp.
Get you in? You own it.
Not anymore.
Oscorp betrayed us both.
So I can't get in there without you and
you can't get out of here without me.
- What've you done?
- Someone pulled an alarm in the ISO unit...
Get a containment team in there now!
You can't possibly know what I want.
You submitted the design for the grid
and they stole it and now you want it back.
You just wanna take back what's yours!
- How?
- All the power is in the city, Max, and its right at your fingertips.
Once you shut down the grid...
Spider-Man will come to you and I want you to make him bleed!
Break it! Break it!
Max, we don't have much time.
Go... go... go.
- Give me one reason why I should trust you?
- Because I need you!
- You need me?
- Yes, I need you.
You are my only chance that
I have at surviving.
- You need me?
- Yes, I need you.
I need you...please, please!
- I know what its like to be thrown away..
- Please...Max!
I need you! I need you!
You want to be my friend?
I thought we were already friends?
I had a friend once.
It didn't work out.
Yea, me too.
Then let's go catch a spider.
You have one new voice message.
Hi, Peter, it's me.
I...I got into Oxford. Woo-hoo.
It's very exciting.
I came by your house a little bit
ago and I..you weren't there and so
I'm on my way to the airport
right now
because there's this early summer
class I found out about
and I thought that it would
somehow
be easier, I guess, this way.
I think that maybe it's time to
let this go...
and that's not because I don't love you,
it's actually because I do.
So, umm...goodbye.
- We have to move now!
- Why? What's happening?
Remember me?
Oh my oh my, how the tables have
turned.
I know it's hard to admit but how
spectacular
- remove this desk, am I right?
- Right, that's right.
OK, so , Fairy Godmother,
it's time to create me a wish.
- I want in...to special...
- How dare you come back in here?
You recalcitrant, unworthy, defective, urchin, freak!
Oh...God I'm sorry, that's just not the answer we were looking for.
"Clear."
Welome back to the bonus round.
Let's take a walk, shall we?
The grid is all yours.
Spider-Man, give it to me.
- What is all these stuff?
- The future.
Load one up.
It won't work.
We're in heavy diagnostic test.
- Apart from human trials...
- I thought that should be already on human trials...
you're just too stupid to know it.
Do it. Now.
You had it all this time!
Critical Injury Detected
Healing Protocol Activated
It's Spider-Man!
- Stop the cab.
- Wait, I aint even moving!
- Did you get my message?
- What's the message?
- The message over there.
- Oh that! It was you?
- Don't do that.
- I couldn't make it up.
I tell you what it says, it says 'I love you'
because I love you.
No offense but you're wrong.
What would that be? You're wrong about us being
on different path.  We're not on different path, you're my path!
I know I'm not always going to be my best
and I know there's so many reasons
why we shouldn't be together, I know that.
Well, I'm tired of them all.
I'm tired of every single one of it.
If I'm gonna to make a choice,
then I choose you.
So...
here's my thought.
England.
Both of us.
I'm following you now.
I'm just going to follow you everywhere.
I'm just going to follow you
the rest of my life.
I mean...they got crime there...in England.
They got tons of crime, it seems.
- Tons...
- Yea, they got...Jack the Ripper.
They haven't caught Jack the Ripper yet, can you believe that?
What the hell is that?
Is that Max?
He must have cut the power to the whole city.
- Totally black!
- Hey, I need tech-ops up here right now!
Phones are down. Somebody
go down and grab tech-ops...
Hey... write down what you remember,
people.
There's gotta be some kind
of a "blackout plan", right?
- Some kind of backup?
- There's an emergency resides at the power plant.
If he got the transmission lines,
- they never gonna get this back up.
- How am I going to stop him?
Every time I get close to him,
he fries my web-shooter.
- Okay, have you tried him
- Yes, I tried everything, rubber, plastic...
- Did you try magnetizing him?
- I didn't...try magnetizing him.
Okay, well, remember eighth grade
Science class?
If you magnetize a nail with a battery...
- You cause an electric charge.
- Yes...
New York approach...this is Pan National 273 on approach...
How do you hear?
- Approach, do you copy?
- Radio is working, it's not us.
Do not panic, everyone, please return to vehicle!
Go back to your car, remain calm!
Do not panic!
Everyone return to your vehicle! Go to your home!
- Officer!
- Spider-Man!
- My father was Captain George Stacy at your precinct,
- Yea, I know who he was. What can we do for you?
- Jumper cables! Jumper cables?
- Yes and...copper wire.
- Am I talking louder than I usually talk right now?
- Yes.
- You're still doing fine.
- Alright, do it!
Did you get it?
Try...try...Hurry...hurry...
- Okay, it works , good.
- And that, is why you were number two in Midtown. Rubbing in Okay.
- I gotta go.
- I'm coming with you.
- Gwen, you're not coming with me.
- Yes I am. Come on...it's too dangerous.
I'm coming with you I see the specs
and I know how to reset the entire system.
Gwen I'm coming with you.
You know that you need me.
Then come with me.
Shut that thing.
Sorry, I love you.
Don't hate me.
We gotta work with this. They're still not back with the generator.
Get me engineering!
- I need a respirator right now!
- I'll get the battery operated. I get hang on!
Can you see me now, Spider-Man?
It's time to meet our destiny.
Tower, we're experiencing some kind of electrical disturbance.
Instruments are going haywire, radar is down.
We're flying blind out here,
do you copy?
Tower, repeat, we're "standby" only,
what is happening?
Sir, there're two inbound flights on intersecting path!
Time to impact?
4 and a half minutes.
Clock it... Clock it right now.
You're too late, Spider-Man.
I designed this power grid.
Now I'm gonna take back
what is rightfully mine.
I want control of everything.
- And I will be like a God to them.
- A God named "Sparkles?"
Not this time. Is that all you got?
Come on!
You ready to give up?
Oh, thank you, Gwen Stacy.
Shake it off. This is your bones,
muscles and your organs.
Oh boy!
I hate this song!
Spider-Man, bet you never
saw this coming...
Really?
You wired me to a car,
what are you, a little caveman?
You tie me up to go off to war?
I know how to help you!
- What're you doing here?
- I know the grid best. I can reset the system.
You can't be here right now. I'm not messing
around. You can't be here right now. this is insane!
Guess what
Nobody makes my decisions for me, alright? Nobody!
This is my choice, okay?
- My choice...
- Go! Mine!
Now how do we stop him?
Okay, so he uses electric. He's like a battery.
So what happens when you overcharge a battery?
- It explodes. Right!
- So we use his power against him, perfect!
Okay, I think I can reconnect the power line
but what I need you to do, I need you to reset the system.
- Okay when I say you turn that power on, you turn it on.
- No matter what. Peter... No matter what.
Go! Go!
60 seconds to impact.
Now, Gwen, do it now...!
Overload
Unit 687.
This is La Guardia tower. Turn
immediately to heading 280.
Incoming traffic, I repeat 280.
Okay people, back to work, let's
land these planes.
I'll be back.
Thank God, alright! Alright,
we're back, everyone, lets go.
Are you still able to make it to your fight?
Gwen, stay there.
Peter.
When you said Spider-Man said no,
you meant "you" said "no"
Harry, what did you do?
What you made me do.
You were my friend and you betrayed me!
No, I was trying to protect you.
- Look at me!
- Hey. it's gonna be okay. This is gonna be alright.
You give people no hope.
You take it away.
- No, Harry.
- I'm going to take away yours!
No, Gwen...run...
Harry, Harry put her down!
Harry, stop this right now.
This isn't you, Harry, this is
not you. Harry, put her down!
- Harry!
- Harry's dead!
Harry, this is between you and me.
You wanna fight?
Fight me, let her go!
You okay?
I got you, I'm going to put you down right now.
Breathe!
You okay?
Stay with me, stay with me,
stay with me, you stay with me.
Gwen!
Gwen...no, please!
Please!
I can't do...
Leave us.
You made progress?
I laid down and find several worthy candidates.
Now that Spider-Man's gone...
the city will never be the same.
Oh...I'm counting on that.
Speaking of progress,
you're looking better.
It comes and goes.
Tell me more.
- How many men did you have in mind?
- I want to keep it small.
Everything you need is already at Oscorp.
Access granted.
Welcome, Mr. Fiers.
- Who is our first volunteer?
- Aleksei Sytsevich.
Apparently serving a
life sentence.
He is most eager to join us.
Good.
Start with him.
Russian ganster Aleksei Sytsevich was broken out of a
classified penetentiary known simply as 'The Vault'
by an unknown team of men.
It's yet another example of
increased criminal activity
since the disappearance of Spider-Man
5 months ago.
The webslingers absence has
left a hole in the heart of the city.
Believe it or not even the New York city Police
Department has joined the chorus of New Yorkers
in hoping for the return of the webslinger.
The entire world seems to be asking
the same question:
Where is Spider-Man?
Too bad without that spider-guy.
Too bad he disappeared, seems like
everybody really needs him.
Where you going?
- I'm not sure.
- Peter...
Where are you going?
I don't know.
You know what? It's so funny...
I've been trying to clean up
around here, get organised and
been putting some of Ben's stuff...in boxes
It's funny that the heavier the box gets,
the lighter I feel.
You throwing his stuff away?
No, no, God no. I couldn't do that.
It's a part of me.
I'm just...finding...
a better place for it.
I'm gonna take one last look...
and then I'm gonna put it where it belongs.
Gwen's speech.
It is easy to feel hopeful
on a beautiful day like today.
But there will be dark days ahead of us too.
There will be days when you
feel all alone
and that's when hope is needed
most.
No matter how bad it gets
or how lost you feel, you must promise me
that you will hold on to hope.
Keep it alive.
We have to be greater
than what we suffer.
My wish for you is to become hope.
People need that.
And even if we fail, what better way
is there to live.
As we look around here today,
that all of the people who help
make us who we are,
I know it feels like we're
saying 'goodbye'
But we'll carry a piece of each other into
everything that we do next
to remind us of who we are
and if we were meant to be,
you had a great 4 years with
you. I'll miss you all very much.
Let's go! Move it!
I'm here live on Park Avenue 56th
Street where it's complete chaos.
A man in some sort of weaponised
armored suit is wreaking havoc on midtown
I'm Rhino.
I told you I would be back.
Hold your fire.
Everybody hold your fire.
Kid, you got to get...
Look, New York.
Spider-Man is back.
That's my baby.
Brave boy, huh.
Does Aleksei scares you, little
boy?
Hey, Spider-Man.
- I knew you'd come back.
- Yea, thanks for stepping up for me.
You are the bravest kid
I've ever seen.
I'm gonna take care of this jerk, you go take care of your mom...okay?
Alright, get out of here, go, go.
Will you fight me,
will you fight me now?
On behalf of the fine people of New
York city and real rhinos everywhere...
I ask you to turn your mechanised
paws in the air!
Never! I can crush you!
I can destroy you!
- You're gonna have me come down there so that you can kill me?
- Yes!
I'll be right there. Ah...there's
no place like home.