Every human being
has a basic instinct.
This work done by:
|| killer_sub ||
To help each other out.
If a hiker gets lost in the mountains,
people coordinate a search.
If an earthquake levels the city,
people all over the world
send emergency supplies.
This instinct is found
in every culture.
Without exception.
At around 4:30am our satellites
detected a storm approaching
the ARES 3 mission side on Mars.
The storm had escalated to severe
and we had no choice
but to abort the mission.
But, during the evacuation,
astronaut Marc Watney was killed.
---
I'm entering this log for the record.
This is Marc Watney,
and I'm still alive,
obviously.
I have no way to contact NASA
or my crew mates.
But, even if I could,
it would take four years
four years
for another manned mission
to reach me,
and I'm in a Hab
designed to last 31 days.
So, in the face of overwhelming odds,
I'm left with only one option.
I'm gonna have to science
the shit out of this.
Okay,
let's do the math.
I got to figure out how to grow
four years worth of food, here,
on a planet where nothing grows.
But, if I can't figure out a way
to make contact with NASA,
none of this matters anyway.
NOUVEAU MESSAGE
Houston be advised, we've got a video
message.
It's directed to the crew.
Play it.
---
Mark Watney is still alive.
In your face, Neil Armstrong.
---
We left him behind.
Let's go get our boy.
This is something NASA rejected.
So, we're talking mutiny.
And if we mess up
the supply rendez-vous,
we die.
If we mess-up
the earth gravity assist,
we die.
It's space,
it doesn't cooperate.
I guarantee you,
that at some point,
everything is gonna go south on you.
And you're gonna say "this is it".
"This is how I end."
Is it possible
that he's still alive?
|| killer_sub ||
Its name.
---
|| killer_sub ||
----