Aragorn, something is out there!
What do you see?
Fast... quiet now.
Quiet... quiet... quiet.
A battle is stirred up, they heard.
What is your name?
Your name is kingly.
What troubles you, Brego?
What did you see?
You told me once...
...this day would come.
This is not the end...
it is the beginning.
You must go with Frodo.
That is your path.
My path is hidden from me.
It is already laid before your feet.
You cannot falter now.
Arwen...
If you trust nothing else...
...trust this...
Trust us.
Is this how you leave?
Did you think you could slip
away at first light unnoticed?
I will not be coming back.
You underestimate your skill in battle.
You will come back.
It is not of death in
battle that I speak.
What do you speak of?
You have a chance for another life...
...away from war...grief, despair.
It is time.
The ships are leaving for Valinor.
Go now...before it is too late.
Do I not also have your love?
You have my love, father.
The world is changed.
I feel it in the water.
I feel it in the earth,
and I smell it in the air.
Well done, Brego, my friend.
You're late.
Thank you.
And they should be...
300...against 10,000!
They have more hope of defending
themselves here than at Edoras...
Aragorn, they cannot win this fight.
They are all going to die!
There is nothing to forgive, Legolas.
Well met, Haldir!
Show them no mercy...
...for you shall receive none!
Hold!
Prepare to fire!
Their armour is weak at the
neck and beneath the arm.
Fire the arrows!
Keep firing!
Ladders!
Bring him down, Legolas!
Kill him! Kill him!
Hurl the arrows!
Charge!
To the Keep!
Pull back!
Haldir!