(BIRDS AND ANIMALS CHATTERING)
BAGHEERA: Many strange tales
are told of this Jungle...
but none so strange...
as the tale of the cub
we call Mowgli.
(GRUNTING AND PANTING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING AND
PANTING CONTINUES)
- (GROANS)
- (GROWLING)
You must be the very
worst wolf I've ever seen.
Yeah, but if that branch didn't break,
I would've made it.
Crossing upwind,
breaking from your numbers.
If you can't learn
to run with the Pack...
one of these days,
you'll be someone's dinner.
- How'd we do?
- Not Mowgli, again.
- He's never gonna make the Council.
- YOUNG MALE WOLF: Let's go!
YOUNG FEMALE WOLF:
Race you to the top! (LAUGHS)
It was higher ground.
Wolves don't hide in trees.
I can't keep up with them, Bagheera.
I tried. I just picked the wrong tree.
BAGHEERA:
It was a dead tree.
How was I supposed to know
it was dead?
It had a fig vine.
Any tree girdled by a creeper
is either dead or close to it.
- These are things a wolf must know.
- Yeah.
But if the branch didn't break,
I would've made it.
I realise you weren't
born a wolf...
but couldn't you at least
act like one?
BAGHEERA:
When I found him...
many years ago...
he was just an infant,
abandoned in the woods.
YOUNG MALE WOLF:
Get the deer!
BAGHEERA:
If he was going to survive...
I knew he needed a people.
A people to protect him.
That's why I entrusted him
to the wolves.
AKELA: Look well, wolves.
BAGHEERA: Akela was
a just and noble leader.
He allowed Mowgli to dwell
among them, all those years.
The trouble was,
wolves grew so fast...
and Mowgli well...
let's just say
he liked to take his time.
Mowgli, pick me up high!
- My turn! (LAUGHS)
- Stop. Not now.
BAGHEERA: It was Raksha
who raised him.
She was the only mother
he ever knew.
- Come on, let's play!
- MOWGLI: I don't feel like playing, Gray.
Come on, you're my brother.
You have to play with me.
Let's go chase some mice.
(LAUGHS)
How did it go?
Caught me again.
If it's meant to be...
it will be.
Let me hear the Law.
ALL: "This is the Law
of the Jungle...
"as old and as true
as the sky.
"The Wolf that keeps it
will prosper...
"but the Wolf that
breaks it will die.
"Like the creeper that girdles
the tree trunk...
"the Law runneth over
and back.
"For the strength of the Pack
is the Wolf...
"and the strength of the Wolf
is the Pack."
(ALL HOWLING)
(MOWGLI HOWLING)
BAGHEERA:
Soon, the rain ceased to fall
and the dry season arrived.
Heat crept through the Jungle...
turning it yellow...
then brown...
then black.
But that year...
was the driest season
that anyone could remember.
Even the mohwa didn't flower.
My leaf.
This is mine. Mine, mine, mine.
There's a rock.
That's mud. That's mud.
There's a rock. That's my rock.
That's my rock.
Nobody touches my rock.
There's another rock.
Two rocks. Three rocks.
Peace Rock? Peace Rock!
It's the Truce! The Water Truce!
- IKKI: It's the Water Truce!
- (SCREECHES)
BAGHEERA: It had been
many, many years
since the Peace Rock was revealed...
and the Water Truce was called.
(GROWLS)
(SNORTS)
BAGHEERA:
Hunting at the riverbank
- was now forbidden...
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
because, by Law of the Jungle,
drinking comes before eating.
So, you could come to the Peace Rock,
on a day like this...
and find all people side-by-side.
Don't forget.
No hunting.
Playing only.
Playing, only. I got it, ami.
RAKSHA: And remember...
not everyone here has seen
a man-cub in the Jungle before.
So, behave yourself.
Okay, can I go now?
Take the pups with you.
Wait for me!
MOWGLI: Come on, Gray!
Oh, take a look at this guy.
Excuse me.
MOWGLI: Sorry.
- He's walking on two legs.
- Don't stare.
MOWGLI:
Hey, look. A wild boar.
- GRAY: And a rhino.
- TAVI: And a mongoose.
- MOWGLI: Everybody's here.
- (LAUGHS)
Is that a peacock?
- Ooh, a stick!
- IKKI: Oh, that's my stick.
- I like this stick.
- Seriously, that's my stick.
- This is my stick.
- No, that's my stick!
- Let go of my stick!
- It's a Water Truce!
- (BOTH GROANING)
- (GROANS)
- Sorry.
My bad! It's involuntary.
IKKI: I could pee on it.
Watch yourself, please.
Dad, what is that?
I think that's a man-cub.
What's a man-cub doing here?
- Whoa. Don't forget the Truce.
- (BLACKBUCKS GASPING)
I know the Law, bucks.
(ALL GASPING)
(SCATTERED CHUCKLING)
What is that?
(SLURPING)
(SNORTING)
- ALL: Weird.
- That's weird.
(HISSES)
AKELA: Mowgli.
What was the rule
about your tricks?
It's not the wolf way.
No more tricks.
Chin up, little one.
We'll make you a fine wolf, yet.
What about me?
Am I gonna be a fine wolf?
Look at me howl!
(HOWLING)
In some packs,
the runt gets eaten.
Oh...
(CHUCKLES)
(EAGLE SCREECHING)
Mowgli, behind me.
Don't leave my side.
(GROWLS SOFTLY AND SNORTS)
(SNARLING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Everyone comes to Peace Rock.
So many smells to catch up on.
(SNIFFING)
But, um...
SHERE KHAN:
I can't help but notice...
there's this strange
odour today.
What is it,
this scent that I'm on?
I almost...
I almost think
it was some kind of...
man-cub.
Mowgli belongs
to my Pack, Shere Khan.
Mowgli?
They've given it a name.
When was it we came to adopt
man into the Jungle?
He's just a cub.
Does my face not remind you
of what a grown man can do?
Shift your hunting ground
for a few years...
and everyone forgets
how the Law works.
Well, let me remind you.
A man-cub becomes man...
and man is forbidden!
(ROARING)
- What do you know about Law?
- Raksha.
Hunting for pleasure.
Killing for power.
RAKSHA: You've never known Law.
The cub is mine!
Mine to me.
So, go back to where you came from,
you burned beast!
(GROWLING)
The tiger knows who rules
this part of the Jungle.
I'm sure he doesn't mean to come here
and make threats.
Especially during a Water Truce.
No, I'm deeply respectful of these Laws
that keep us safe.
So, here's my promise.
Nothing lasts forever.
The rains will return
and the river will rise.
And when this rock disappears,
that Truce will end.
SHERE KHAN:
You want to protect him, fine.
But ask yourselves,
how many lives is a man-cub worth?
BAGHEERA:
How many lives?
Who could answer that question?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CROAKING)
- ALL: The rain!
- Rain!
- The rain!
Keep it dry, keep it dry, keep it dry.
(GRUNTS) These quills
get stuck on everything!
BAGHEERA:
When the rains returned...
it was a question
the Council had to face.
(WATER RUSHING)
(WOLVES ARGUING INDISTINCTLY)
They deliberated
and they argued...
for many days.
(ARGUING CONTINUES)
What do you think
they're talking about?
BAGHEERA: No one had ever
come between the Pack before.
But Shere Khan's threat...
was not to be ignored.
Mowgli, you're not supposed
to go up there!
RAMA: He's got to go.
Look at the skies.
Shere Khan may be heading here
as we speak.
(ARGUING CONTINUES)
RAKSHA: Please!
I'm leaving.
(ARGUING STOPS)
I don't want to see
anyone get hurt.
Mowgli, go back to the den!
A man-cub belongs with man.
We raised him
as one of our own!
- He'll have the boy, either way.
- BAGHEERA: Akela.
Maybe I can be of help.
The boy's right.
Maybe it's time
he found another people.
- No.
- I'm the one who brought him to you.
And now I'll return him
to where he belongs.
I won't let you.
He's my cub!
We knew this day would come.
We are the only family
he's ever known!
AKELA: Raksha.
It's the only place he'll be safe.
It's okay, ami.
I won't go far.
I'll come back and visit.
Never forget this...
You're mine.
Mine to me.
No matter where you go,
or what they may call you...
you will always be...
(VOICE BREAKING) my son.
BAGHEERA:
I wish I could tell you...
that the wolves
could've fought Shere Khan.
But this is not
that kind of a tale.
MOWGLI: The turtles like me.
Maybe the crocodiles.
What about the rhinos?
They always
let me hang around.
Of course, the rhinos sleep
standing up.
I don't think
I'd be very good at that.
It's either the turtles
or the crocodiles.
Which one do you think is better?
BAGHEERA: Neither.
What do you mean?
I'm bringing you to
the man village.
What?
Bagheera, I don't know man.
You will.
MOWGLI: You always said
we're not supposed
to go near a man village.
BAGHEERA:
That was different.
Why is it different?
You always said, "Stay away
from the man village...
"because you might fall in a trap...
"or get eaten,
or get hurt by flying rocks."
I know what I said.
Whoa. Elephants.
- Bow your head.
- Why?
Show them respect.
BAGHEERA: The elephants
created this Jungle.
Where they made furrows
with their tusks,
the rivers ran.
Where they blew with
their trunks, the leaves fell.
They made all that belongs.
The mountains, the trees...
the birds in the trees.
But they did not make you.
That is why you must go.
What if I live with the nilgai?
No.
Or the mongoose?
This is not a discussion.
But this is my home!
I don't even know
what man's like.
You'll learn.
But I wanna stay in the Jungle.
Why do I have to go there?
Because the Jungle
is no longer safe for you.
You're being hunted...
by a tiger.
Only man can protect you now.
- (SNORTS)
- MOWGLI: Whoa!
This isn't fair.
You're not giving me a choice.
There's a lot of stuff
you're not telling me, too.
Don't think I didn't notice.
You say you're taking me
where I came from...
but you found me in the Jungle.
Are you bringing me back
to the Jungle? No.
Why are you bringing me
to the man village
if you found me in the Jungle?
And why does the tiger
hate me so much?
Does he know me?
Sure seems like he knows me.
Down.
What? Now we have to bow
to the buffalo, too?
Listen to me.
This is not a game.
You're gonna run to that ravine.
What are you talking about?
Go to the north,
where the sky glows at night.
I'll find you on that path.
Bagheera, I'm not taking one
more step until you tell me...
- (ROARS)
- (MOWGLI SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
(SNARLING)
(BOTH ROARING)
BAGHEERA: Run, Mowgli!
Run!
(BELLOWING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(WATER BUFFALO BELLOWING)
(LOWING)
(MOWGLI GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
Gray, what's wrong?
Why don't you
come outside and play?
What is that?
Why did he have to leave?
Gray.
We could've protected him.
We shouldn't have let him go.
I miss him, too.
What's important is,
he's safe now.
(EAGLE SCREECHING)
Get inside.
I suppose you know
why I've come.
The man-cub
has left the Jungle.
I thought
I made myself clear.
I wanted him
turned over to me.
We no longer harbour him.
He has left the Pack.
And where, may I ask,
has he gone?
He's with his own kind now.
So, the man-cub has left the Jungle.
AKELA: That's right.
You and I no longer have a quarrel.
And, most importantly...
we have peace.
I guess it's done, then.
Unless I can draw him...
back out! (ROARS)
Akela!
(ROARS)
Have I got your attention now?
I didn't want it to be this way.
I made it so simple.
All I asked for was one thing,
and you denied me!
That ends now.
Spread the word.
Until I have the man-cub,
these hills are my hills.
You did not respond to reason!
So now, you will know fear.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(LOWING)
(RUMBLING)
(MOWGLI GRUNTING)
- (WATER BUFFALO LOWING)
- (GASPING)
(LOWING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
(ECHOING) Bagheera?
(SIGHING HAPPILY)
Hmm?
Hey, there.
(SQUEAKS)
Do you have a language?
You're kind of cute, I guess.
You want a bite?
Come on.
Come here. Come on,
it's all right.
Don't be afraid.
Come on.
Hey, those are mine!
(YOUNG CIVETS SQUEAKING)
Hey, come back!
(SQUEAKING)
Those are mine!
Drop it!
Hello?
Who's out there?
KAA: Hi, little cub.
Oh, no. Don't be scared.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I was just passing through.
I don't want any trouble.
KAA: There's no trouble.
Are you alone out here?
Mmm. That's not good.
We should never be alone.
I'm waiting for a friend.
He should be here soon.
KAA: I can stay with you,
until he gets here.
Would that be all right?
I'll keep you safe.
Just you and me, sweet thing.
Who are you?
Kaa.
Poor, sweet little cub.
What are you doing
so deep in the Jungle?
This is my home.
Don't you know what you are?
I know what you are.
I know where you came from.
You do?
(HISSING) Yes.
Would you like to see?
(ECHOING) Yeah.
KAA: Mostly,
men stay in their village...
far from the dark of the Jungle.
But sometimes...
they travel.
And when they do...
their caves breathe in the dark.
They call it...
the Red Flower.
Man's creation.
It brings warmth and light...
and destruction
to all that it touches.
MOWGLI: Who is that?
KAA: The traveller,
protecting his cub.
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARING)
KAA: Shere Khan ended
the man's life that night.
(ROARS)
But not before he was burned
by the Red Flower's touch.
He ran so fast, he didn't
notice the cub he left behind.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
And that cub...
was you.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
The panther found you.
Oh, you poor, sweet thing.
You want to stay in the Jungle?
You can be with me,
if you want.
I'll keep you close.
Let go of your fear, now.
(HISSING) Trust...
in me.
(HISSING)
(ANIMAL ROARING)
(KAA HISSES)
(LOUD SNIFFING)
(SCREAMING)
Relax, kid.
No need to get
worked up. Okay?
- Where am I?
- Uh...
This is a cave. It's my cave.
You don't remember
what happened, do you?
- No.
- I saved your life.
Yeah, I snatched you
from the jaws of death.
The coils of death,
if you will.
And lucky for you...
your new favourite hero,
old Baloo, here...
just happened
to be passing by.
Uh, no big deal.
Just tell me this.
Can you...
climb?
Yeah.
Then let's quit wasting time
and get on with it.
Get on with what?
Payback, kid. Payback.
What do you mean "payback"?
Payback for what?
You owe me, kid.
You owe me. You owe me.
Slow down.
- And you're gonna pay back.
- But, but...
Because that's right.
You're gonna do
the right thing.
That's the right thing to do.
You're gonna pay me back,
because you owe me.
You got it?
(SNIFFING)
BALOO:
Okay, here's our little task.
You see that golden stuff,
dripping down there?
That's called "honey."
All you need to do,
little one...
for payback purposes...
is to just shimmy on up there...
and get me that thing up there
that's making that funny noise...
- and bring it back down.
- (BUZZING)
You're kidding me, right?
No, not really.
(SCOFFS) I can get killed
going up there.
Kid!
Kid, kid, kid.
Try to understand this.
I'm a bear.
It means that
I have to eat my weight...
every day...
for hibernation purposes.
(STUTTERS)
I know I'm asking for a lot...
but I don't climb and you do.
Look, I really need your help.
Winter's coming.
You don't want me
to go to sleep...
and never wake up.
(SCRAPING)
(GRUNTS)
(BUZZING)
There are a lot of bees up here.
Yeah, some.
But don't worry.
These ones don't sting.
Attaboy!
Ow! I'm getting stung!
(SIGHS) Okay.
I would've done this myself,
but I'm afraid of heights.
Oh, boy. Here we go again.
Why don't you
mind your own business?
You can do it!
- He's just gonna run away.
- Not this one.
As soon as the monkeys get
stung, they always run away.
- He's not a monkey. A man-cub.
- What is he?
- A man-cub?
- Yeah! Could you keep your voice down?
I'm trying to concentrate.
- Everything going A-okay up there?
- MOWGLI: Ow!
Oh, boy. Looks like
you got another one.
- Buzz off.
- It's a man-cub.
- A man-cub?
- Yeah, it's a man-cub.
- It's not a monkey?
- No, it's a man-cub!
You have never been
a more endangered species...
than you are at this moment.
You're doing an amazing job!
I'm getting stung!
Oh, boy. Here we go again.
- It's not a monkey, Fred.
- It's a man-cub.
- A man-cub?
- Yeah, it's a man-cub.
- Can you believe it?
- Are you sure?
Would you please shut up?
Hey, up there!
(CHUCKLES) Everything is
going fantastically, I see.
Ow! (GRUNTS AND PANTS)
BALOO: You got it!
Believe in yourself!
(GRUNTING)
- There you go!
- Ow!
BALOO: Come on! Almost!
Yeah!
(CHUCKLES) Yeah!
Oh, yeah!
Uh-oh.
(MOANING)
Fred?
(GRUNTING)
(SQUEALING)
(MOANING)
Oh, yeah, exfoliate me.
You said they didn't sting.
What do you call this?
How the heck did you do that?
Oh, those must have been females!
(GROANS LOUDLY)
BALOO: They look like males
from down here.
Females do sting.
Just put some honey on those.
- Honey? Really?
- Yeah.
You put it on, you lick it off.
You feel much better.
It's nature's ointment.
(WHISPERS)
I put it everywhere.
Thanks.
Okay, so, we're even now!
Hold on a minute.
What's your name anyway?
We were never properly introduced.
- Mowgli.
- Mowgli?
Mowgli is a terrific name.
I bet you got that one
all to yourself, too.
Hey!
Mowgli, look...
I got a lot of gathering to do
these next couple of weeks...
on account of the hibernation.
I could really use your help.
You know, if you stuck around...
I can't. I have to go
to the man village.
(STUTTERS) Uh...
For what reason, man village?
I don't have a choice.
There's a tiger hunting me.
Really? Why a tiger?
Because I'm a man-cub, all right?
Just leave me alone.
Hey! Mowgli, my friend,
my buddy, my pal.
Slow down a second, handsome.
Bagheera said I have to go
to the man village.
Oh, Bagheera! I know him. Sure.
You know what his problem is?
He always plays by the rules.
And, sometimes rules
were meant to be...
well, not necessarily broken,
but certainly bent.
And definitely reinterpreted.
Don't you think?
He told me to go to the man village,
so, that's where I'm gonna go!
Okay, fine.
You wanna go to the man village,
have it your way.
In fact, I'll do you one better.
I'll take you there myself.
Come on, let's go. It's getting late.
(BALOO HUMMING)
♪ Bare necessities ♪
♪ Forget about ♪
♪ Your worries and your strife ♪
♪ I mean the bare necessities ♪
What's that?
That's a song about the good life.
What's a song?
(SCOFFS) You never
heard a song before?
Everyone's got a song.
Didn't the wolves ever sing?
I don't know.
Uh... Oh...
We recited the Law of the Jungle.
"This is the Law of the Jungle...
"as old and as true as the sky.
"The Wolf that keeps it may prosper...
"but the Wolf that breaks it will die."
Kid, that's not a song.
That's propaganda.
MOWGLI: What's propaganda?
(SIGHS)
Just a little farther.
That's the man village?
BALOO: Yep. You can always
tell by the Red Flower.
They do love their Red Flower.
The Red Flower
doesn't seem so bad.
Yeah.
Let it loose, and it destroys
everything it touches.
Don't ever play with it.
You got that?
Yeah, I got it.
Good.
Do you think
that's where I'm from?
Could be.
I don't know, kid.
Does it look familiar?
I don't remember it.
All I remember is
living with the wolves.
Why do you wanna go there?
- Bagheera said I need a people.
- (BALOO GROANS)
Again, with the listening
to Bagheera.
Hey, he's my friend, okay?
Now I don't even know
where he is.
I can't believe I'm leaving
the Jungle for good.
May I say just one thing?
What I saw you do today,
I've never seen anything like it.
I've been trying to get
that honey for years.
But I used my tricks.
What tricks?
You know...
Everything that I built.
It's not the wolf way.
Who cares? "The wolf way."
That's the Mowgli way.
That's the Baloo way.
That's our way.
That's how we get things done.
I can't even imagine what kind
of potential you'd have...
if you had somebody like me
helping you out.
You say you want to go
to the man village.
I say, you could be a man
right here.
I'll tell you what.
Now you know
where the man village is.
You can always go down there,
whenever you want.
But I would personally
appreciate it...
as a personal
favour to me, personally...
if we just worked together,
just us, tricks and all.
I think it would be
interesting to see...
just how much honey
we could accumulate...
before winter.
Whatever I could do to make
your trickiness happen...
I will do.
And if it turns out to
not be fun for you...
I will walk you right down
to that man village myself.
Is that a deal?
Just till winter.
(WHISPERING)
Ami, wake up.
Pups?
They're up there.
- (LAUGHING)
- (PUPS GIGGLING)
SHERE KHAN: The deer, of course,
take comfort in numbers.
They lack defences
most animals will have.
And if we're being honest...
they're not very smart either.
- (ANIMALS GRUNTING)
- Unlike the mother crocodile,
who is a good deal more clever.
(SHERE KHAN CHUCKLING)
But the one you have
to watch out for...
is the cuckoo bird.
Do you know
how the cuckoo bird survives?
By preying on a mother's weakness.
The cuckoo bird is too clever
to raise its young.
Instead, it sneaks...
its eggs into the nests
of simpler birds.
So, when they hatch...
the mother bird is fooled.
She feeds them, nurtures them.
And do you know what happens
to her own chicks?
They starve...
and die...
from neglect.
All because a mother loved a chick...
that wasn't her own.
Come now, time for sleep.
(PUP WHIMPERING)
I think they like me.
Why are you doing this?
He's gone.
Isn't that what you wanted?
I want him dead.
Once he gets word
of what happened here...
he'll come back.
And I'll be waiting.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(CUCKOO CALLING)
(YAWNING)
- That's the first mark.
- Got it.
- That's the first mark!
- Got it!
That's the first mark!
MOWGLI: Got it!
Whoo!
Yeah, I got it!
- Tell him to go to the second mark!
- Got it!
- (PANTING) Go to the second mark!
- Got it.
Got it.
BALOO: (SINGING)
♪ Look for the ♪
BALOO AND MOWGLI:
♪ Bare necessities ♪
♪ The simple bare necessities ♪
♪ Forget about your worries ♪
♪ And your strife ♪
♪ I mean the bare necessities ♪
♪ Old Mother Nature's recipes ♪
♪ That bring the bare
necessities of life ♪
♪ Wherever I wander
Wherever I roam ♪
♪ I couldn't be fonder ♪
♪ Of my big home ♪
♪ The bees are buzzing ♪
♪ In the tree ♪
♪ To make some honey just for me ♪
♪ When you look under
the rocks and plants ♪
♪ And take a glance
at them fancy ants ♪
♪ And then maybe try a few ♪
♪ The bare necessities of life ♪
♪ They'll come to you! ♪
- ♪ Wherever I wander ♪
- (LAUGHING)
♪ Wherever I roam ♪
♪ I couldn't be fonder ♪
♪ Of my big home ♪
♪ The bees are buzzing in the tree ♪
♪ To make some honey
just for me ♪
♪ When you look
under the rocks and plants ♪
♪ And then take a glance
At them fancy ants ♪
♪ And then maybe try a few ♪
♪ Mmm! Mmm! ♪
♪ The bare necessities of life
They'll come to you ♪
♪ They will come to you ♪
♪ Yeah, they'll come to you! ♪
♪ Come to you! ♪
Baloo, Baloo, Baloo... look.
- (RUSTLING)
- (TWIG BREAKS)
BALOO:
Stay low on my back.
Come on out and show yourself.
Bagheera! Ah!
BAGHEERA: Mowgli.
Oh, I was looking everywhere for you!
I thought you were gone!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah!
I can't believe you found me!
I was so worried about you.
I was lost, and I didn't know
what happened...
but then I met Baloo.
And then he saved me
from a giant snake!
And now we're working together!
(CHUCKLES) Really?
That's a new wrinkle.
I didn't know sloth bears worked.
Come on, Mowgli,
let's be on our way.
Wait!
Yeah, go on ahead.
I'll catch up.
Don't be mad, okay?
Why would I be mad?
Because you're always mad
when I do stuff.
You gotta promise
not to be mad this time.
Show me, then I'll decide.
MOWGLI:
Come on, check it out!
These are vines I use on the cliff.
I twirl them together to make
them longer and stronger.
See how strong they are?
You wanna see
the really cool part?
It's inside.
Come on, let's go!
Come on!
It's the honey stash
for winter!
Have you lost your mind?
You said you wouldn't get mad.
Did you listen to anything
Akela taught you?
There's no place...
in the Jungle for these...
tricks!
You want to do this,
you do this in the man village.
But I'm helping Baloo
get ready for hibernation.
Bears don't hibernate
in a jungle.
What are you teaching him?
Not full hibernation,
but I nap a lot.
Listen to me, you con artist!
He may not know
your game, but I do.
- BAGHEERA: He's leaving now.
- But I don't wanna leave!
You don't have a choice!
Why don't we all just
settle down for a minute.
Look, it's gotten late.
Too late to travel.
So, why don't we all
just have a little honey...
I don't eat honey.
No problem. I'll eat the honey.
Let's all get a good night's sleep...
and we can talk about this
in the morning.
Fine. But we're leaving,
first thing.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING
IN DISTANCE)
(SNORING)
(ROARING)
(ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING
CONTINUES)
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
(TRUMPETING)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING)
BAGHEERA: Mowgli.
Where is he?
- BAGHEERA: In the pit.
- In the what?
- Is this your teaching?
- Oh, come on!
You know I'd never teach him
to mess around with elephants.
(TRUMPETS SOFTLY)
Hey, guys.
What'd I tell you? He's special.
I know he's special.
I raised him.
Then don't make him leave,
Bagheera!
You gotta let him be
what he is.
You don't understand.
The boy's in danger.
I know, he told me.
He's being hunted by a tiger.
Not any tiger. Shere Khan.
Shere Khan's hunting him?
Oh.
But if you send him back
to the man village,
they'll ruin him.
They'll make a man out of him.
We should send him back
to the Wolf Pack.
Who's their alpha?
Akela, he can protect him.
Akela is dead.
- What?
- Shere Khan killed him.
He will stop at nothing
until he has this boy.
Nothing.
The only way we can save him...
is if he goes to that man village.
Please, Baloo.
You're the only one he'll listen to.
Hey, kid.
Hey.
That was pretty cool,
what you did back there.
Bagheera didn't think so.
Oh, no, I talked to him.
He was very impressed.
He was?
We both were. Yeah.
I've never seen anyone get
that close to an elephant before.
(SIGHS)
So, listen, kid.
I gotta talk to you about something.
What do you wanna talk about?
I've been thinking.
Now that your friend has shown up...
maybe it's time...
for you two to just mosey along.
Now it's winter...
and it's really time for you to go.
But I wanna stay here with you.
We're buddies, aren't we?
Huh? No, we were never friends.
I certainly never thought
of you as my friend.
You helped me get honey
and I don't really need you any more...
(STAMMERS)
Do I have to spell this out?
I don't want you around any more.
(SIGHS)
Well, I did it.
And that's about the hardest thing
I've ever done.
I know.
(HUFFS)
(MONKEY CHITTERING)
(CHITTERING)
(MOWGLI BREATHES DEEPLY)
Go away.
(CHITTERING)
Get away from me.
(IMITATES MOWGLI)
Stop it.
(SCREECHING)
Get away from me!
MOWGLI: (SCREAMS)
Bagheera!
- (SCREAMS)
- Mowgli!
(GRUNTS)
Mowgli, hold on!
MOWGLI: (GRUNTS)
Bagheera!
What was that?
Where are they taking him?
BAGHEERA: This way.
(MONKEYS CHITTERING
AND SCREECHING)
MOWGLI: Ahh! Ah!
Whoa!
(SCREAMING)
We see you! We see you!
Come on, jump!
And watch the claws.
(BALOO GROANS)
(MOWGLI GRUNTING
AND SCREAMING)
Gah! (GROANS)
(MONKEY GRUNTS)
Uh...
I'll take it from here.
No, I'm coming.
(STUTTERS) It's doable...
if I don't have to go too high.
Good. Let's get going.
All right.
(MONKEYS SHRIEKING)
(GRUNTING)
(BALOO GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(EAGLE SCREECHES)
(SOBS)
A bird. That can't be a good sign.
BAGHEERA: Baloo.
Look at me. Look at nothing but me.
- Hmm?
- You're doing fine.
Just keep your eyes up high.
All right. I'm coming. I'm coming.
(MONKEYS SHRIEKING)
(CLANKS)
(CLANKING)
(CHATTERING STOPS)
What part of the Jungle you from?
You, man-cub.
You come from the South,
the North?
(STUTTERS)
What part of the Jungle?
The South, I guess.
Southern Jungle, the Seeonee.
Beautiful, I hear.
I never been there myself.
So, tell me, you ever had
a taste of the pawpaw fruit...
down there in the Seeonee?
Some people call it the...
What's the word?
Papaya. Stolen words.
I say pawpaw.
Goes to the sound it makes
when it tumbles to the Jungle floor.
Try it.
Go ahead.
It's good.
You know who I am?
No.
I am the King of the Bandar-log.
Call me Louie.
(MONKEYS GASPING)
(PANTING AND GRUNTING)
I did it!
- (SIGHS)
- Well done, old chap.
(GROANING)
BAGHEERA: He must be in there.
Follow me.
No, no.
We're on level ground here.
I'm in charge.
And I've got a plan.
You are a man-cub
who wants to live in the Jungle.
How do you know that?
Kid...
I got ears. My ears got ears.
You wanna live here?
You need a people to protect you.
Only I can protect you...
and I will, for a price.
I don't have anything to give you.
I think you do.
What?
Look around, man-cub.
I got everything.
I have plentiful food...
endless treasure...
command vast legions.
But there's one thing I don't have...
and that's the one thing...
you can give me.
The Red Flower.
- (MONKEYS GIBBERING)
- I don't have that!
You're a man, aren't you?
That's what makes you a man.
You can summon the Red Flower...
and control it.
They told me not to go near
the Red Flower.
You know why they tell you that?
Because once you have it,
you rise to the top of the food chain.
Nothing in this Jungle can stand up...
to the Red Flower.
(ALL SCREECHING)
Please, I just wanna go.
(SINGING)
♪ Now, don't try to kid me, man-cub ♪
♪ I'll make a deal with you ♪
♪ What I desire is man's red fire ♪
♪ To make my dream come true ♪
♪ Now give me the secret, man-cub ♪
♪ Come on!
Clue me what to do ♪
♪ Give me the power
of man's Red Flower ♪
♪ So I can be like you ♪
♪ Oh, ooo-be do ♪
♪ I wanna be like you-oo-oo ♪
♪ I wanna walk like you,
talk like you too-oo-oo ♪
♪ You'll see it's true-oo-oo,
someone like me-ee-ee ♪
♪ Can learn to be
like someone like you-oo-oo ♪
♪ Now you might think
it's ridiculous that me ♪
♪ A Gigantopithecus,
would ever dream ♪
♪ I'd like to team with
the likes of you, man-cub ♪
♪ But together we 'd have powers ♪
♪ All the Jungle's treasures, ours ♪
♪ I got desire, you got the fire ♪
♪ But the dream I dream takes two ♪
♪ So, oo-oo-oo ♪
- ♪ I wanna be like you-oo-oo ♪
- (MONKEY HOOTING)
♪ I wanna use that flame ♪
♪ Just the same as you can do ♪
♪ Oh, how magnificus it would be ♪
♪ A Gigantopithecus like me ♪
♪ Could learn to do ♪
♪ Like you humans do-oo-oo ♪
Just one thing we need...
to reach our full potential.
Bring me that Red Flower...
and we will rule this Jungle.
I will protect you.
And you will want for nothing,
ever again.
- I can't!
- (MONKEYS CHITTERING)
You can't or you won't?
I can't!
You will!
BALOO: Excuse me!
Anybody?
(MONKEYS CHITTERING)
BALOO: Excuse me...
am I in the right monkey temple?
Oh, my gosh.
Is that King Louie?
(CHUCKLING) This is so exciting.
The legends do you no justice, sir.
You are truly enormous.
(CHUCKLES) In the best way.
Look at all of that flesh...
just squatting there...
on an ancient throne.
How majestic.
Seize him.
Hey, hang on.
Can you just hang on?
I climbed a mountain to see you,
and I'm not a climber.
Just to be in your presence.
For me, this is a dream
come true. Oh...
Throw him off the cliff.
Wait, wait, wait.
I have no problem with that.
I don't have
any problem with that.
I came up here
without an invitation.
It was extremely
presumptuous of me.
Let me interrupt myself.
- I just gotta say...
- (MONKEY SHRIEKING)
you guys are so much handsomer
in person than anyone knows.
No one ever gets up close to you.
Why?
Because of the smell.
The smell is rough.
But it's not just,
"Oh, look at me."
It's, "I got the brains."
You guys got the know-how.
You got the noggin.
You came up with this stuff,
with the thumb.
Come on, show me.
How do you do that? I can't do that.
Look, I scratch, I rub,
You know, I can grab a fish.
But I was hoping, and you may
not be open to this at all...
but I was hoping,
and once again, it's a dream...
but I was hoping
that I might become...
a Bandar-log myself.
Gosh, I wanna be like you.
I am hitching
my wagon to your star.
(SHRIEKING)
(PANTING)
No one leaves!
I can show myself out.
Thanks. Bye-bye!
(PANTING)
(KING LOUIE SCREAMS)
(ROARING)
We'll try to hold them off.
(GRUNTING)
Where you going, man-cub?
Stay away from me!
You don't have anyone now.
I'm your only hope.
I can make it real good for you here.
Where else you gonna go?
I'll go back to the Pack!
I'll go back to Akela!
Akela?
Oh.
You didn't hear?
Shere Khan killed him.
Must've been on account of you.
No! You're lying!
(GROANS)
Don't run away...
from who you are!
You hear me?
(MONKEYS SCREECHING)
(ROARING)
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
Think about it, man-cub.
We can rule this Jungle.
No...
Listen to reason.
- Gotcha!
- (MOWGLI SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
Mowgli!
If anything happens to that kid...
I'll never forgive myself.
- MOWGLI: Bagheera!
- Mowgli?
BAGHEERA: Stay there.
We'll come around to you.
Is it true?
What?
Is Akela dead?
We were going to tell you.
You knew!
You both knew!
And nobody did anything about it!
Kid, just hold on.
Someone's gotta do something!
- Mowgli!
- (GRUNTS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(CHATTERING)
There's no trace of him.
Where could he have gone?
(SCREECHING)
Come on!
(GRUNTS)
(EAGLE SCREECHING)
It's man.
He's come to the Jungle.
Ami, what's happening?
The Red Flower.
Everybody, get to the river!
(PANTING)
ALL: Red Flower.
Pups, come on. Stay close.
(SNORTS)
Is that Mowgli?
Shere Khan!
I'm not afraid of you!
No one has to be afraid
of you any more!
(SHERE KHAN GROWLING)
SHERE KHAN: No...
I think they're afraid
of something else now.
The man-cub is now a man.
Gray...
(WHIMPERS)
Always a proud day...
when they come of age.
You can fool them,
but you can't fool me.
I'm the one who saw
your future.
I saw what you'd become.
Come now,
use the Red Flower.
Use it on me
like your father did.
Show everyone
what you really are!
(GRUNTS) I'm Mowgli of the Seeonee
and this is my home!
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
That was the stupidest thing
you could've done.
Now you have nothing.
No claws, no fur, no teeth...
And no friends.
"This is the Law of the Jungle...
"as old and as true as the sky."
What is this?
"The Wolf that keeps it
may prosper...
(TOGETHER) "but the Wolf
that breaks it will die."
You fools.
ALL: "Like the creeper
that girdles the tree trunk...
"the Law runneth over and back."
Fine! Rise up, all of you!
You want to put yourselves
between me and the man-cub?
"...and the strength
of the Wolf is the Pack."
I will have you all
in my teeth! (GROWLS)
(ROARING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
- No!
- Wolves, attack!
(YELLING)
- (GRUNTS)
- Stay here!
But I wanna fight with the wolves!
- You can't fight him like a wolf.
- You're not a wolf!
Fight him like a man.
Now, go!
Okay.
We'll hold him off.
(GROWLS)
(GRUNTS)
SHERE KHAN: It's time
we put an end to this.
RAKSHA: No!
(SCREAMS)
Dead tree.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
It's just you and me now!
(GROWLS)
(GRUNTS)
Break, break! (GRUNTING)
(SNARLS)
(GRUNTS)
- (GROWLS)
- (YELLS)
You've got nowhere
to go, man-cub!
- Did you think I would let you grow old?
- (BRANCH CREAKS)
Either I'll devour you
or the Red Flower will.
It's just a matter of time.
How long did you really think
you'd survive against me?
Longer than your father did?
Longer than... Akela?
(GROWLS)
I'm not afraid of you!
- Do you hear me?
- (ROARS)
I'm done running from you!
- (BOTH GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
(CRACKLES)
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
You stood your ground, old boy.
You stood your ground.
(ELEPHANT TRUMPETING)
Ami, ami!
My son.
- ALL: Mowgli!
- It's Mowgli!
Mowgli.
Will you look at that?
BAGHEERA: And where they made
furrows in the ground with their tusks...
there the rivers ran.
(HOWLING)
(ALL WOLVES HOWLING)
In my years, I've seen
a lot in this Jungle.
But that night...
I saw something I'll never forget.
I saw a little boy...
without a people...
bring all the Jungle together
for the very first time.
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
BAGHEERA:
Just a few more turns.
I'm going high!
Stay low.
(SIGHS) He never listens.
Gotcha!
- Come on, Mowgli.
- You went in the tree.
- That wasn't fair.
- We almost made it.
BALOO: You guys...
are going too fast. (PANTS)
Anybody ever teach you how to jog?
You went high when everyone else
stayed on the trail.
- But that's what you do.
- Maybe, but I'm not a wolf.
Next time, stay together.
Come on, guys. (CLAPS)
"For the strength of the Pack is the..."
- Wolf.
- "Wolf...
"and the strength of the Wolf
is the Pack."
Mowgli's back!
WOLF CUB:
Hey, Mowgli! Wait for us.
Hurry up, guys.
- MOWGLI: Hi, Gray.
- (GIGGLING)
Look well, wolves.
(WOLF CUBS GIGGLING)
"This is the Law of the Jungle...
ALL: "as old and as true as the sky.
"The Wolf that keeps it may prosper...
"but the Wolf that breaks it will die.
"Like the creeper that girdles
the tree trunk...
"the Law runneth over and back.
- "For the strength of the Pack..."
- (THUDS)
(MOANS)
BALOO: This is nice up here.
Now he can climb.
(GIGGLES)
Please don't tell me
you're about to head down.
(BALOO PANTING)
(BALOO SIGHS AND CHUCKLES)
I could get used to this.
(SIGHS)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING)
♪ Now I'm the king of the swingers ♪
♪ Oh, the jungle VIP ♪
♪ I've reached
the top and had to stop ♪
♪ And that's what's botherin' me ♪
♪ I wanna be a man, man-cub ♪
♪ And stroll right into town ♪
♪ And be just like the other men ♪
♪ I'm tired of monkeyin ' around ♪
♪ Oh, ooo-be do ♪
♪ I wanna be like you-oo-oo ♪
♪ I wanna walk like you,
talk like you too-oo-oo ♪
♪ You'll see it's true-oo-oo,
someone like me-ee-ee ♪
♪ Can learn to be
like someone like you-oo-oo ♪
♪ Now, don't try to kid me,
man-cub ♪
♪ I'll make a deal with you ♪
♪ What I desire is man's red fire ♪
♪ To make my dream come true ♪
♪ Now give me the secret, man-cub ♪
♪ Come on!
Clue me what to do ♪
♪ Give me the power
of man's Red Flower ♪
♪ So I can be like you ♪
♪ Oh, ooo-be do ♪
♪ I wanna be like you-oo-oo ♪
♪ I wanna walk like you,
talk like you too-oo-oo ♪
♪ You'll see it's true-oo-oo,
someone like me-ee-ee ♪
♪ Can learn to be
like someone like you-oo-oo ♪
♪ Now you might think
it's ridiculous that me ♪
♪ A Gigantopithecus,
would ever dream ♪
♪ I'd like to team with
the likes of you, man-cub ♪
♪ But together we 'd have powers ♪
♪ All the Jungle's treasures, ours ♪
♪ I got desire ♪
♪ You got the fire ♪
♪ But the dream I dream takes two ♪
- (GRUNTS)
- ♪ So, oo-oo-oo ♪
♪ I wanna be like you-oo-oo ♪
♪ I wanna use that flame ♪
♪ Just the same as you can do ♪
♪ Oh, how magnificus it would be ♪
♪ A Gigantopithecus like me ♪
♪ Could learn to do ♪
♪ Like you humans do-oo-oo ♪
♪ Can learn to be
like someone like you-oo-oo ♪
like someone like me-ee-ee ♪
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Trust in me ♪
♪ Just in me ♪
♪ Shut your eyes ♪
♪ Trust in me ♪
♪ You can sleep ♪
♪ Safe and sound ♪
♪ Knowing I am around ♪
♪ Slip into silent slumber ♪
♪ Sail on a silver mist ♪
♪ Slowly and surely your senses ♪
♪ Will cease to resist ♪
♪ Just relax ♪
♪ Be at rest ♪
♪ Like a bird ♪
♪ In a nest ♪
♪ Trust in me ♪
♪ Just in me ♪
♪ Shut your eyes ♪
♪ And trust in me ♪
♪ Trust in me ♪
♪ Just in me ♪
♪ Shut your eyes ♪
♪ And trust in me ♪
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Yeah, you're right ♪
♪ Look for the bare necessities ♪
♪ The simple bare necessities ♪
♪ Forget about your worries ♪
♪ And your strife ♪
♪ I mean the bare necessities ♪
♪ Old Mother Nature's recipes ♪
♪ That bring the bare
necessities of life ♪
♪ Wherever I wander
Wherever I roam ♪
♪ I couldn't be fonder ♪
♪ Of my big home ♪
♪ The bees are buzzing ♪
♪ In the tree ♪
♪ To make some honey just for me ♪
♪ When you look under
the rocks and plants ♪
♪ And take a glance at them fancy ants ♪
♪ And then maybe try a few ♪
♪ The bare necessities of life ♪
♪ They'll come to you! ♪
♪ Look for the bare necessities ♪
♪ The simple bare necessities ♪
♪ Forget about your worries ♪
♪ And your strife ♪
♪ I mean the bare necessities ♪
♪ That's why a bear can rest at ease ♪
♪ With just the bare necessities of life ♪
♪ So just relax ♪
♪ In my backyard ♪
♪ If you act like that bee acts ♪
♪ You're working too hard ♪
♪ Don't spend your time
just looking around ♪
♪ For something you want
that can't be found ♪
♪ When you find out
you can live without it ♪
♪ And go along not thinking about it ♪
♪ I'll tell you something true ♪
♪ The bare necessities of life ♪
♪ Will come to you ♪
♪ Water, air, love ♪
♪ House with a roof above ♪
♪ Talking 'bout the bare
necessities of life ♪
♪ Wisdom, understanding, sleep ♪
♪ Good health
is something you must keep ♪
♪ Forget about
your worries and your strife ♪
♪ These are the bare necessities of life ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪