Synced and subtitled: Mr. hsp
attention, pirates alongside!
Pirates alongside!
Take cover. All crew below deck!
I repeat pirates alongside!
Initiate emergency procedure!
All crew below deck!
Emergency positions!
Code red! Code red!
Get everybody below deck, now!
Everyone, get down!
Jack, where's that un convoy?
The chopper's on its way, sir.
Eta 30 minutes!
Get everybody below deck
wolf warrior ii
I'm waiting for my son
I need our home for his return!
Wait till police get here! Let's see
how you're going to tear our houses!
If they wanna die, then let 'em.
Mrs. yu, mrs.Fei.
We brought xiao fei home
salute!
Tell these rookies what our motto is
be humble
I became a soldier because
I wanted to be in battles
and now, what about the battles?
Much better to be at home with
wife and kids instead
my daughter,
she's beautiful, huh?
You gang of sumbags!
You think you're tough, huh?
Go get them! Get them!
Officer see! He's got a gun!
A gun!
Comrade, put down your weapon!
You're pretty lethal, huh?
Well you'd better kill me now,
because you're gone,
I'm gonna make them wish they
were dead
hey!
Leng feng!
The reason a soldier is respected
is not because of the uniform he wears,
but is because of the sense of
duty he carries
with or without the uniform,
the duty remains
and he continues to be respected
three years later
shenmutusawa bay, Africa
hey, hurry up!
Hey, leng. There's our hero
thanks for saving the lives of
everyone
let's take a picture together.
No problem!
- Thank you!
- Ok, see you!
Take care, see you!
Hey, boss!
Buy some, it's good stuff.
There was an outbreak in taman recently
because of consuming this herbs,
there were 4 survivors
- please!
- No, thank you!
Please help please consider
boss.
Chinese wine.
This
- hey, hey.
- Come on man
ok, this one is okay
nice one. See you next time.
Get up here!
Welcome back!
Bye
this, good for you
you're not alone
20 dollars. Buy one get one free
- who am I?
- My godfather
if your godfather tells
your mother about this,
what would she think?
Confiscated!
Begin!
Godfather! Godfather! Godfather!
Harry! Harry! Harry!
Leng! Leng! Leng!
Who?
Who else? Who else?
Do it, do it
fuck it!
Who the fuck you think you are?
Come on!
Yeah
Patrick! Patrick! Patrick!
I've been sent to the border
for a mission
when I get back,
this had better be signed
marriage application
why did you join the army?
Join the army, you regret it for two years.
Don't join the army, regret it for life.
- The truth?
- That's the truth.
Drink! Again!
Comrade long xiao yun.
Was attacked while carrying her
mission at the border.
We found this bullet.
Drink again.
What do you want to hear?
Drink!
Again!
You win.
But I lost...
I've lost completely.
It's been more than a year
since you came on board
during that time, from djerba to tolanaro,
I've asked all the chiefs.
More than half of Africa,
and nobody has seen that bullet before.
Peluru itu sebelumnya.
I will find it,
even if I have to scour
the entire continent.
Dear fellow countrymen,
my deepest condolences to the families their
loved ones during batchka village incident
early today, the red scarf rebel army claimed
responsibility for the batchka village
our government condemns
their barbaric behavior.
Our homeland has been attacked on
multiple occasions.
These are great tragedies.
The rebels continue to advance as the
country grapples with the lamanla outbreak.
As your government, we will not back down. The
great people's army will fight to the very end.
Quarantine have been set up
across the country,
in an attempt to contain
the lamanla outbreak.
We have declared a state of emergency.
Hey, brother
you shorted me 300 bucks.
Be careful with that.
Look, we're both Chinese.
You do this to your own people?
Since 3 pm on the 14th of last month,
I am no longer officailly Chinese.
What? Fresh off the boat?
Hear that? In times like this,
that's the price you get.
Seen this before?
Nope
I've been told that it came
from these parts.
Definitely never seen it.
Hey boss.
How are you? Smoking?
Tundu!
Go! Go!
Don't shoot!
- Don't shoot!
- Good people
go, go, go!
Get the fuck down or you die!
Hail the revolution!
You're now talking to rebels!
Don't lie to me.
Your luck is down!
Hail the revolution!
No, no, no guys, look!
Revolution!
What the fuck is this?!
No, no, no
he's a pro-government rat!
- No!
- You lied to me!
No!
Hail the rebels! Hail the rebels!
Shit!
Tundu!
Chinese embassy.
Let's go to the Chinese embassy.
They'll take us in.
We're Chinese.
What about us?
What're we suppose to do?
Will they accept us?
Hard to say.
That's our country.
Everybody follow me.
Go!
Come on!
No!
Here
slow down! No, no! We're Chinese
- go, go!
- Tundu!
Go, go, go!
Die! Scum! Hail the revolution!
Die! Scum!
- Die!
- Lower your guns!
Put down your weapons!
Lower your guns!
Stand down!
We are Chinese!
China and Africa are friends!
Go.
Go, hurry. Go.
Fall back!
Help! Help!
South Indian ociean. Redeployment of China Navy fleet to Africa
for evacuating operations by central military commission
commander, all foreign vessels
are leaving the war zone.
The harbor is unsafe.
Are you certain about docking?
Forward 10 knots.
Set course bearing for 270.
Open the gate!
Well done, you got here just in time
what's the situation?
The entire country's in chaos.
The war has destroyed lives of
many of countrymen.
Can you send our troops
in to help?
Without the un's authorization,
our troops aren't premitted
to enter the war zone.
Ok, slow down up we go! Nice!
Where are from? He can't board.
He's my son.
We have tickets. See, look!
Three tickets. 79, 80, 81.
Fine then. 79, 80, 81.
Thank you.
Where are we going?
Mr. prime minister, please listen to me.
I'm deeply sorry for what's happening
in your country.
But I believe you have not forgotten
about the help,
we provided to your country
and friendship between our countries
I believe you understand how important
our citizen Dr. chen
is to Africa.
Please send somebody to protect
his safety.
I'm sorry,
you're on your own this time.
Prime minister
where's Dr. chen?
I will never
tell you
dyon military resourcing corporation
, roach
let's go!
12 years of hard work.
One war,
and it's all fucking gone
the bullet...
What's the story?
Tundu!
If you get off, you can't get back on.
Tundu! Tundu!
Stop right there!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry
I want my mom!
I want my mom, I don't want to go to China!
Look at me - I want my mom!
I want my mom!
- Ok? I want my mom!
- Hey brother
what are you doing down here?
There's something I have to tell you.
That bullet...
I've seen it before.
That pattern,
is a symbol used by the rebel forces.
An arm dealer friend of mine told me
the rebels have hired the most expensive
mercenaries out of Europe.
Whatever grudge you've got against them,
I urge you,
don't go seeking death.
47 Chinese workers!
Are still stuck at
the hanbond Chinese factory
what's worse, dr, chen is stuck 55 km
behind enemy lines
on a medical relief mission
he's a high value target
for the rebel army.
Everything is in total lockdown
from lochino to St. Francis.
Without un's authorization,
my troops aren't allowed to
enter the war zone.
This operation is highly important!
We have to evacuate those Chinese workers!
And Dr. chen by all means!
Under current circumstances, combat troops
are prohibited from entering the warzone!
In order to complete the evacuation,
someone has to undertake
the mission alone!
- I'll go.
- Stop right there!
What's your purpose?
Former pla, South-east region,
specail ops brigade,
wolf warrior squadron,
leng feng.
This child's mother is
at hanbond Chinese factory.
I know approximately where it is located.
I promise you,
I will bring your mom back.
We took care of business now, didn't we?
Ambassador Thomas, king Angola,
prince drew.
That goddamn communications manager.
They're all gone.
They all disappeared,
real mysterously!
Stop wasting my time with
that crap!
Where's Dr. chen?
Ah, Jesus.
You tell him what you told me.
Dr. chen
is at St. Francis Chinese-invested
hospital.
Good boy.
Did you hear that?
That could be sound of the future.
Sir, why are we helping
these fucking idiots?
Welcome to Africa, son.
Alrights, let's move out boys!
From the latest report,
the fighting is reaching
semshalemu harbour.
The urgency of the evacuating
1536 Chinese nationals wating there
has just been escalated.
Our vessels are heading over
at top speed.
My apologies,
because the conflict is on foreign soil,
you'll have no reinforcements,
no allies and no weapons.
Dr. chen and 47 Chinese workers,
evacuate them all.
Sunkoojia
quanrantine zone, danger
do not enter.
Sunkoojia, st Francis Chinese-invested,
hospital
my boss asked me
to find Dr. chen.
Nobody wants to do something!
Now, I have to try my luck.
Because
I have
a special vision.
Let me guess...
Saint Francis China-hospital
are you Dr. chen?
I'm not! I'm not!
Are you Dr. chen?
- Are you Dr. chen?
- No, no, no.
She's a child, just a child
I am - no
no
I'm Dr. chen.
You are Dr. chen?
Looks like Dr. chen doesn't have balls.
What do you want?
- I am Dr. chen.
- Dr. Rachel, no!
She's not Dr. chen.
She's a very good doctor.
She saved so many lives.
No!
Dr. chen!
Papa!
You just killed.
Dr. chen.
- Papa!
- Dr. chen!
Dr. chen, right?
I was sent by ambassador
fan to rescue you.
This is my daughter, pasha.
Please, I beg you, protect her.
Dr. chen!
Come with me!
Get in the car!
Go fast!
What are you doing?
What do you think I'm doing?
I'm saving your ass!
Let me drive!
Move!
What the hell!
Turn around!
Go, go, go!
Jesus.
Pasha!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Pasha.
Stop!
You want food? We have food.
We have food, okay?
We have food.
Are you okay?
Thank you.
Is that from quarantine zone?
Pasha, can you please hand me the bag?
I said, did you get that in
the quarantine zone?
It's nothing.
I'm not overreacting.
In fact, it's better if I was.
Those people back there were
infected with the lamanla virus.
Symptoms include the sudden onset fever,
hallucinations, lesions,
cold sweats. It's a fatal virus that's
transmitted through direct human contact.
Upon contraction, death strikes between
four hours and five months.
Up until now,
no cure has been found.
Don't worry, I'm insured.
You're killing the Chinese?
This is a big trouble.
Why are you killing the Chinese?
Sir...
I thought you wanted Dr. chen.
Congratulations. You found him.
Fuck!
I wanted him alive!
Alive!
Don't you understand how important
it is to me?
Fuck!
Wait.
That girl.
I like her.
Sir, our facial recognition crew uploaded video
of this man fighting off some of the pirates.
His name's leng.
Ex-member of a secretive special ops
unit pot of China.
Wolf warrior.
Boys!
The doctors without borders
were killed by armed mercenaries.
The lives of Dr. Cheng and other
Chinese medical staff were scarificed.
Comrade leng,
do you stand by what
are you're saying?
Are you certain you witnessed the massacre
or our medical team?
I'm cetain.
Dr. chen give me his daughter
before he died.
An African girl.
Her name is pasha.
Oh, and anurse too.
What's your name?
Rachel Prescott Smith.
You can call me Rachel.
Doctor Rachel, I'm not a nurse.
Report the situation to ambassador
fan immediately.
Yes sir.
Commander, may I speak to
my son please?
Godfather, godfather! Where's my mom?
Where's my mom?
Hey, tundu, tundu!
Trust me, trust your godfather.
We are going to hanbond Chinese factoty
to find your mom right now, okay?
Thank you, godfather.
Leng, I have some bad news for you.
The rebel army is sobotaging
all major roads,
railways and Bridges.
As of 10 minutes ago,
your only route to the port,
the bowerneja bridge,
was bombed. We are formulating an
escape plan now.
But untill then, you're on your own.
Set your watch.
The macimum time we can wait is 18 hours.
After that, we'll be forced to leave.
My deepest apologies.
I have the responsibility
to everyone on board.
I understand.
You're going to the Chinese factory?
We should go to the
ameriacn consulate.
The us marines are stationed there.
That's our safest bet.
You think the us marines are
the best in the world?
That may be true,
but where are they now?
I've informed the
consulate of the situation.
Where are they?
Tell me exactly how you
informed them?
I tweeted at them on Twitter.
Welcome to American consulate.
Unfortunately, we are closed.
Fuck!
All foreign Navy ships have
left when I arrived.
A I watch them sail away from port.
Among the countless departing masts.
I saw one with the stars and stripes.
Stop the car.
Stop the car!
Stop the car, I want to get out!
Stop!
Rachel.
Your gis are here to get you.
Hanbond Chinese factory
I'm Chinese.
I'm here for nessa.
Tundu's mom.
Nessa!
Anyone home?
I've been sent here to rescue you.
By ambassador fan himself.
You?
Rescue us?
I've got 18 ak-47s.
30 m79 grenade launchers,
enough to arm a platoon.
I have a m1911 pointed
at your head right now.
How the fuck are you supposed
to rescue us?
Leng, leng! Are you leng?
Are you leng?
- Nessa?
- Yes, yes, yes!
- What about my son?
- He's safe.
- He's okay?
- He's okay.
Oh, thank God!
He's okay.
Mom, mom, I'm ok, I'm ok!
Oh, thank God! I mom, I'm ok!
Because you're on a Chinese warship.
I told you,
not to sell that porn.
Here we go. You definitely won't
find better dumplings in Africa.
I flew in a chef from China.
Fresh, just for you. Thank you.
What are you looking at?
Seen one before?
Ever shot one of these?
This wolf here,
I killed myself with this gun.
Who drew this map?
I instructed our head of security,
laohe, how to do it.
It still needs some work.
Laohe, come here for a second.
Sector a to sector d.
I've told you so many times.
Why isn't it done yet?
I'll get on it right away.
Laohe,
write it down quickly.
As our head of security. What if
something happens during the operation?
Then what?
This is a real man's toy.
Don't be afraid.
From now on, your safety
will be my responsibilty.
Leng, thank you!
You're welcome.
Thank you so much!
Thank you.
Hey, kiddo. It's super yummy
try this.
Hey! You brat!
I'm fine. What's the big deal?
I think she's kind of cute.
Good news.
Ambassador fan just called.
Tomorrow 07:00 am,
a un rescue helicopter
will be landing at this factory
to evacuate us.
Just one?
Attention please.
Everybody.
Everybody listen to me.
Quiet down everyone.
Listen to me.
All Chinese employees, stand on this side.
We are only taking Chinese people.
Management goes first.
I will lead the evacuation.
Is that clear? All the africans
please stand this side, please.
Clear?
Harry.
- No, boss, no.
- Please.
Come on, come on.
Get moving.
Anyone else?
Come, move. That side. That side.
What are you doing?
She's my wife. She's pregnant
look
any more Chinese?
Any other Chinese?
Lin, listen to me.
Everyone here is my employee.
I'm taking them all with me.
How?
Come on, come on!
Don't stop, get moving.
Get moving. For this side,
fellow African.
Chinese people, this side.
She married me.
So she's is one of us.
Move, move.
You...
Fine, stay there.
There's perfect.
Come on! Come on!
Guys, guys please, please move.
Stand that side, please.
Please, African friends.
Trust me.
Come on, hurry uo, get moving.
You want to be on this side, yeah?
Fuck off, bro!
What's up?
Why?
Give a line down the middle.
I want to see a clear boundary line.
Show me the line, please.
I brought the helicopter.
I call the shots.
Everyone leaves tomorrow.
Children and women leave
with the chopper.
The men will follow me on foot.
Everybody.
We leave together.
Old timer,
the defensive formation out front,
that was you, right?
You're not bad yourself.
Former people's liberation army of China,
14th corps, South-west region,
recon company commander,
he jianguo.
Former people's liberation army,
special ops birgade, South-east region,
wolf warrior squadron, leng feng.
At your service.
Drink in your honor.
An hour ago, these people
didn't know if they'd live
to see tomorrow.
Why are they so happy?
Our African friends,
it doesn't matter if it's war,
disease or poverty,
once they're around the bonfire,
all their cares go away.
Africa. Great food.
Nice scenery.
Hot women.
Hey.
- Cheers.
I don't want to ride my father's
coat tail all my life.
I love this place!
Lions, crocodiles,
ak-47s, sniper rifles,
and the melody of gunfire you
can't get in a peaceful country.
That's the most wonderful
sound in the world.
Do you want to know why pasha
bit you today?
Because her father was killed
ak-47s you so adore.
If this were you,
would you still thinl
it's wonderful??
Oh man, look at this.
That's a big party.
I love these things.
Look at them.
Fuck!
Pasha!
Shit!
Let me go!
Take out the veteran.
Athena, take out the old man.
Stay here!
Let her go!
Pasha!
Like ants when you lift a rock.
Fuck!
Help me!
They got my leg!
You're fine.
Shit!
Go!
Go! Go!
I need a reload!
Go!
What are you doing, man?
Fuck!
Let's split up!
Go! Go!
Damn it.
- Come on!
- Let's go!
Pasha.
Pasha, where are you?
Move out of the way, bitch!
Run!
We know you're not a soldier anymore.
What the fuck are you fighting for?
Once a wolf warrior
always a wolf warrior!
Bear, you're on point.
Athena, cover the exit.
I want this son of a bitch.
Team Charlie, spotted target.
We are in pursuit.
Sir, team bravo has target 12 o'clock.
What the fuck? Those idiots want
us to retreat now?
This is general actu
everyone return to base.
Return to base.
Big daddy, I'm ordering you
to get the fuck back here now!
Hey! What the fuck are you doing?
I told you so many fucking times
that we cannot kill the Chinese!
China is a permanent member of the
un security council.
And I need them on my side if I am
to take political power.
You fucking asshole!
Kill leng, and find pasha,
and you'll be the king of
this fucking country
as you comment, sir!
- Hold it!
- Leng feng!
Who are you?
We just fought a battle together,
what's your deal? Brither fan
we were pretty safe before
he got here.
Ever wonder why the rebels
show up
after he got here?
He's a friend of my son.
He came here for me.
Have you met him before?
My son always talks about him.
So?
I trust him! He rescued pasha
and me earlier today at the hospital
he's been protecting us ever since.
Let me get this straight.
You met him the same time
your doctor friend died?
People are getting killed around him,
while he's unscathed.
Friend, speak for yourself.
Get off me!
- Lamanla (Virus).
- Lamanla?
He has lamanla!
Lin! He's my friend.
He just saved my life.
What about them?
What about them? Last month,
the comms center10 km away,
one person got lamanla.
In the end, the whole place was wiped out.
Everyone's life is at stake here.
Look, it is not just my opinion.
Ask them yourself.
I'll leave.
Wait.
You all know what will happen to
someone infected with lamanla.
I hope you'll always remember
this dying man saved all of you.
Shame on you!
Shame on all of you!
Leng feng!
How confident are you with a gun?
Soso
there's no place in my team
for so-so.
Trying to get me drunk so
I blurt out the truth?
Will you blurt out the truth?
Certainly.
What are you like when you're drunk?
I'll let you buy me drinks
when you come back.
You're the one who didn't
come back.
Come back to bed.
Cut it out.
When I get back
this had better be signed.
It's an easy death when you're
on the attack.
But it's a hard life carrying
a survivor's guilt.
But you didn't come back.
It's you who didn't come back.
You didn't come back.
Against who?
Who were we fighting yesterday?
Didn't your mom tell you that
you shouldn't play with a gun?
Leng!
That was leng, only him alone.
It was me!
I was in the military before I worked here.
Does anyone here
look like they can shoot?
Okay.
You're up.
It's a shame Dr. chen didn't live
to see this.
He discovered the presence of self-healing
properties in humans.
In extreme rare cases, lamanla
antibodies can be found in patients.
Among the thousands of lamanla
patients he treated
he chanced upon one such person
and that person is pasha.
So pasha's not his daughter,
but his patient.
From the analysis of pasha's blood
he created an experimental vaccine.
Last night was a dire situation,
so I experimented on you,
what Dr. chen was planning to do.
The first human trial that
he was hoping for
injecting you with Dr. chen's
newly synthesized vaccine immunogens
honestly speaking,
I didn't know what would happen.
Luckily
God was on your side.
The population has lost faith in the
government to contain the outbreak.
So, whoever takes pasha
takes the country easily.
That explains why the rebel army
is hot on our heels.
My dad said man walked out of
Africa 100.000 years ago.
Africa is the cradle of
modern civilization.
Yet when the "evolved, civilized"
humans returned to this land,
they brought along with them
nothing but suffering,
slavery, disease and war.
Koreans, Icelanders, slavs,
Americans
and over there are Chinese.
People from all over the world,
people like my father.
For Africa
they gave their best years.
In the end,
they got to remain here for eternity.
What's her name?
Huh?
The person you can't seem to forget.
Long xiaoyun.
She's lucky
to have a man that loves her so much.
Why didn't she come back?
Sorry.
I want you to round 'em up like cattle.
Make 'em feel safe. You understand me?
Yes, sir.
We got mountains to the west,
we got forests to the east. The only smart place for them
to come is right here and wait for the rescue helicopter.
I sure hope these Chinese people don't die.
I'm about the only thing that can
save them right now.
Round 'em up.
Everybody, let's go! Let's go!
Move, move, move!
Wait till I get out of here,
I'm going to settle the score with them.
Brother fan,
cut the fucking bullshit.
How are we going to get out?
And besides,
what are you planning to do?
What can you even do?
Brother fan,
in normal times, everyone
gives in to you.
In battle,
no one will be giving in to us.
Shut the fuck up!
Go to hell!
Brother, how are you holding up?
Not as well as back in the day.
Your hands are for saving lives
not taking lives.
How would wolf warriors fight
this battle?
Go!
Didn't your mom tell you not to
play with weap?
Didn't your mom tell you not
to fuck with spoiled brats?
Let's go!
Here's evidence of the rebel
army killing our citizens.
Transmission received.
We will gather up all the information,
and have ambassador fan
submit it to the un.
Copy that.
Oh and one more thing. The local government has
critically requested for our military assistance
the chopper will arrive shortly
we're waiting for you.
Copy that!
United nations
get on the chopper - there're a lot
of people here who still need me.
Lin zhi xiong!
Women and childern must get on the chopper.
Right now I'm not a woman. I'm a doctor
the more professional than
you when it comes to saving lives.
But I'm more professional than
you in protecting lives!
Pasha, are you ready to
get on the helicopter?
Can you pass me some gauze please?
Get on the helicopter.
Don't be difficult, okay?
- Excuse me?
- Excuse you my ass!
Whoa, what was that?
Mayday! Mayday!
Missile strike! Tail rotor lost!
I have control. Going down!
Mayday! Mayday!
Brace! Brace!
- Go! Go!
- Go!
Run!
To the bunker!
Hurry!
Rachel!
Wake up!
Come on! Come on!
Rachel!
Go find laohe!
Get up! Come on!
Fuck!
Get to the bunker!
Go! Quickly! Go!
Go! Quickly!
Get ready!
Fire!
Kill that motherfucker!
Reload!
I can't aim.
This thing's so heavy!
You wanna die!?
Trigger that fuse and
it'll kill us all!
Fire!
Oh, check it.
Three clicks down.
Fire!
They found the bunker!
I got it! I got it! To the left.
- Copy that.
- Reload!
We're out!
Hang on!
Fire!
Son of a bitch!
Fuck! Move this fucking thing.
Come on! Come on!
Good, good, good.
Fuck!
I guess the Chinese military
ain't as lame as I thought.
Cut the crap.
Go!
Hurry!
Don't come out!
Track the signals and verify
targets positions!
Godfather!
Mom!
Sir, we have triangulated on the phone's position!
- Sir, targets locked on!
Sir, we recieved orders from command!
Fire!
Now it's personal.
Long xiaoyun.
Is that your girl?
She's pretty.
Blood... For blood.
Please don't fight!
Look at them.
You're gonna die for this people.
I was born for them.
People like you will always
be inferior to people like me
get used to it.
Get fucking used to it.
That's fucking history.
Welcome back.
The war zone is up ahead.
We can't get through.
Unidentified vehicle convoy
at three o'clock.
Brother,
pass me the flag.
Drive.
It's the Chinese.
Hold your fire.
Hold your fire! It's Chinese.
Leng feng.
Commander!
I see you're enjoying your life.
Not planning on rejoining
the wolf warriors?
Sir, the earliest flight out of here,
departs next Tuesday at 14:15
by Friday 09:00.
I will report for duty sir!
There's something I need to tell you...
Wolf warrior
wolf warrior 3
synced and subtitled: Mr. hsp